{
  "sections": [
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "8.1",
          "definitions": {
            "EVINCE": {
              "word": "EVINCE",
              "phonetic": "(i-vins')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to exhibit, manifest, reveal \nTo EVINCE is to show or demonstrate clearly by some outward sign. The word is applied to emotions, interests, and the like, not to physical characteristics. \n\"He EVINCED no desire to go with us.\" \n\"EVINCING his displeasure with a frown, the manager told Bill to come to his office.\" \n\"The judge said he would have been more lenient if the criminals had EVINCED any regret.\""
            },
            "LUGUBRIOUS": {
              "word": "LUGUBRIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(lu-gU'-brE-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "mournful, dismal, melancholy, doleful \nLUGUBRIOUS means \"expressing, or giving rise to, great sorrow.\" Usually the word is used in a half-humorous sense, about a person or thing that is gloomy in an excessive or exaggerated way. \n\"The LUGUBRIOUS organ music seemed out of place in the modern office building.\" \n\"The LUGUBRIOUS man could talk of nothing but funerals and graveyards.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>merry</em>, which is opposite in meaning to LUGUBRIOUS. Perhaps people are misled by the humorous way.in which LUGUBRIOUS is often used."
            },
            "MITIGATE": {
              "word": "MITIGATE",
              "phonetic": "(mit'-ÔøΩ-gAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to soften, moderate, alleviate, relieve \nTo MITIGATE something is to make it less severe or painful, to moderate its force or intensity. \n\"The judge refused to MITIGATE Stanley's punishment, even though he promised never to steal again.\" \n\"The warm fire and pleasant conversation somewhat MITIGATED the inconvenience of being snowbound.\" \n\"MITIGATING circumstances\" are those that might tend to lessen the severity of an offense. \n\"The man admitted he had stolen the car, but argued that there were MITIGATING circumstances: his wife was about to have a baby, and they had no other way of getting to the hospital.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is \"argue over,\" possibly due to confusion with <em>litigate</em>, which means \"to engage in legal proceedings.\" \nOther forms of the word: MITIGATION, n. MITIGATIVE, adj."
            },
            "PATENTLY": {
              "word": "PATENTLY",
              "phonetic": "(pat'-ÔøΩnt-lE",
              "pos": "adv.",
              "deftext": "obviously, clearly, plainly \nThe adjective PATENT means \"open to view,\" <em>obvious</em>, <em>evident</em>. \n\"Her displeasure with the worker was PATENT: she stormed back and forth, shaking her head and muttering threats.\" \nThe adverbial form of the word, PATENTLY, is perhaps seen more frequently. It means <em>obviously</em>, <em>clearly</em>. \n\"The expert said the painting was PATENTLY a fake, done by a crude amateur.\" \n\"His claim to be the world's greatest writer was PATENTLY ridiculous.\" \nOther forms of the word: PATENT, adj."
            },
            "PERPETRATE": {
              "word": "PERPETRATE",
              "phonetic": "(per'-pÔøΩ-trAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to commit, perform, carry out \nTo PERPETRATE means to <em>commit</em>. The word is usually applied to crimes, but may also refer to actions which, though not criminal, are offensive or deplorable. \n\"The butler was accused of PERPETRATING the murder.\" \n\"The bank robberies were PERPETRATED by a gang of master criminals.\" \n\"The angry teacher said that whoever had PERPETRATED the practical joke would be punished.\" \nOther forms of the word: PERPETRATION, n. PERPETRATOR, n."
            },
            "PLAINTIVE": {
              "word": "PLAINTIVE",
              "phonetic": "(plAn'-tiv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "mournful, melancholy, sorrowful, doleful \nPLAINTIVE is related to the word <em>complaint</em>. Both come originally from a Latin word meaning \"to beat one's breast,\" to <em>lament</em>. PLAINTIVE means <em>sorrowful</em>, <em>melancholy</em>. It is usually used about sounds that are mournful or pitiful. \n\"In a PLAINTIVE voice the child said he couldn't find his mother.\" \n\"The PLAINTIVE melody of the Chopin nocturne made me feel sad and reflective.\" \n\"The hungry man PLAINTIVELY begged for food.\" \n<em>Questioning</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, possibly because to <em>complain</em> about something is in a sense to <em>question</em> it."
            },
            "TRACTABLE": {
              "word": "TRACTABLE",
              "phonetic": "(trak'-tJ-bJI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "obedient, governable, docile \nTRACTABLE means \"able to be easily controlled or handled.\" It is used about persons and animals. \n\"The child became quite TRACTABLE when we told her she couldn't watch TV if she didn't obey us.\" \n\"Beth was afraid of horses, so we let her ride the TRACTABLE old mare before trying any of the more spirited horses.\" \nWhen used about things, TRACTABLE can mean \"easy to work with,\" <em>malleable</em>. \n\"The sculptor found this type of clay to be quite TRACTABLE and used it in many of his works.\" \nThe opposite of TRACTABLE, INTRACTABLE, is frequently used. \n\"The INTRACTABLE child simply refused to eat his spinach.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTRACTABLE, adj. TRACTABILITY, n."
            },
            "ACCEDE": {
              "word": "ACCEDE",
              "phonetic": "(ak-sEd')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to agree, assent, consent \nThe <em>cede</em> part of ACCEDE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>yield</em>, also found in <em>concede</em> and <em>cede</em>. See <em>ad-</em> under Prefixes. To ACCEDE to something is to yield to it, to give one's assent to it, often after persuasion. It is followed by <em>to</em>. \n\"If you do not ACCEDE to our demands we will go on strike.\" \n\"The professor ACCEDED to Jim's request for an extra day to complete his paper.\" \n\"The treasurer was not prepared to ACCEDE to any changes in the budget.\" \n<em>Give</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, perhaps because of the word <em>cede</em>."
            },
            "DIADEM": {
              "word": "DIADEM",
              "phonetic": "(dl1",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a crown, ornamental headband \nA DIADEM was originally a cloth headband worn by Eastern monarchs as a sign of their royal power and dignity. This custom was taken over by Alexander the Great when he conquered their countries. DIADEM then came to be used for any kind of crown used as an emblem of royalty. In an extended sense, DIADEM can be used to refer to the royalty itself. \n\"The emperor wore his DIADEM only on ceremonial occasions.\" \n\"Upon the death of the king, several powerful dukes contended for the DIADEM and scepter of royal power.\""
            },
            "DROLL": {
              "word": "DROLL",
              "phonetic": "(drOI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "comical, laughable, amusing \nDROLL comes from a French noun meaning \"jolly little fellow,\" <em>buffoon</em>, and the word is still used in this way. But it is most frequently used as an adjective and means \"amusing in a sly, odd, or whimsical way.\" The word suggests the soft-spoken humor of a Yankee storyteller rather than the broad slapstick of a clown. \n\"Mr. Peters told us a DROLL story about being mistaken for a famous movie star.\" \n\"The DROLL bartender had a funny story on every subject.\" \n\"We were all amused by the chimpanzee's DROLL actions.\" \nMany people think DROLL means <em>serious</em>, which has virtually the opposite meaning. A DROLL person may have a serious expression while telling a funny story, and this may be a cause of the confusion. \nOther forms of the word: DROLLERY, n."
            },
            "ENNUI": {
              "word": "ENNUI",
              "phonetic": "(ahn-wE')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "boredom, tedium \nNote the pronunciation. ENNUI is from the French, and keeps its French pronunciation. ENNUI is a feeling of dissatisfaction and weariness that stems from a lack of interest in one's surroundings and activities. People who feel ENNUI lack the energy or the desire to do the kinds of things they might previously have enjoyed. \n\"Susan tried to relieve her ENNUI by going skiing in the Rockies, but when she came back she was just as bored as ever.\" \n\"The sameness of his life provoked a strong sense of ENNUI in Mr. Simpson. He just didn't feel like doing the same old job, day in and day out.\" \n\"John had such a strong feeling of ENNUI that all he did was lie around the house all day.\""
            },
            "INDISPOSED": {
              "word": "INDISPOSED",
              "phonetic": "{in-dis-pOzd')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "mildly ill; unwilling \nOne meaning of the verb <em>dispose</em> is \"to be willing or receptive.\" \n\"I am DISPOSED to believe you.\" \nTo be INDISPOSED is to be unwilling or disinclined. See <em>in-2</em> under Prefixes. \n\"Bill was tired and grumpy and generally INDISPOSED to listen to Ralph's excuses.\" \nINDISPOSED is usually seen with a very different meaning: <em>mildly ill</em>. The image is of a person who is not feeling well and is therefore not disposed to do something. \n\"When Ted called, Marge's roommate said she was INDISPOSED and couldn't come to the phone.\" \n\"The performance had to be canceled because the star was INDISPOSED.\" \nOther forms of the word: INDISPOSITION, n."
            },
            "INJUNCTION": {
              "word": "INJUNCTION",
              "phonetic": "(in-juh",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an order, command, directive \nAn INJUNCTION is a command to do or not do something. \n\"With a last INJUNCTION to eat well and wear clean socks, the anxious mother sent her son off to summer camp.\" \n\"He conscientiously obeyed his doctor's INJUNCTION not to eat tomatoes.\" \nINJUNCTION is a frequently used term in law, where it refers to a court order that must be obeyed on penalty of being held in contempt of court. \n\"The court issued an INJUNCTION against the illegal strike.\" \n\"The reporter disobeyed the court's INJUNCTION to hand over his notes.\""
            },
            "REGALE": {
              "word": "REGALE",
              "phonetic": "(ri-gAI')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to delight, entertain, gratify \nREGALE is related to the word <em>regal</em>. It means \"to entertain or give pleasure to.\" The word suggests the kind of lavish or sumptuous entertainment a king would provide. \n\"Mary REGALED her guests with fine wines and delicious cheeses.\" \n\"The speaker REGALED the audience with his tales of life on the high seas.\" \n\"Jim liked to REGALE himself with memories of the athletic triumphs of his college days.\""
            },
            "VAGARY": {
              "word": "VAGARY",
              "phonetic": "(vA'-g:-rE",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a whim, caprice, flight of fancy \nA VAGARY is a fanciful, extravagant idea or notion. \n\"No one was quite sure if the learned man's occasional strange ideas were harmless VAGARIES or brilliant insights.\" \nIn a slightly different sense, a VAGARY is an unpredictable or erratic action. \n\"The VAGARIES of New England weather make it a chancy thing to plan outdoor activities.\" \n\"Experts tried in vain to explain the VAGARIES of the stock market.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "to EVINCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "exhibit",
                    "arouse",
                    "overcome",
                    "need",
                    "eject"
                  ],
                  "word": "EVINCE",
                  "correct": "exhibit"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LUGUBRIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "merry",
                    "angry",
                    "mournful",
                    "proud",
                    "dangerous"
                  ],
                  "word": "LUGUBRIOUS",
                  "correct": "mournful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to MITIGATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "worsen",
                    "soften",
                    "prevent",
                    "argue over",
                    "perfect"
                  ],
                  "word": "MITIGATE",
                  "correct": "soften"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PATENTLY",
                  "answers": [
                    "rarely",
                    "usually",
                    "continually",
                    "cleverly",
                    "obviously"
                  ],
                  "word": "PATENTLY",
                  "correct": "obviously"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to PERPETRATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "solve",
                    "plan",
                    "commit",
                    "recall",
                    "explore"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERPETRATE",
                  "correct": "commit"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PLAINTIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "soothing",
                    "questioning",
                    "common",
                    "mournful",
                    "unfortunate"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLAINTIVE",
                  "correct": "mournful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRACTABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "obedient",
                    "stubborn",
                    "noticeable",
                    "lovely",
                    "friendly"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRACTABLE",
                  "correct": "obedient"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ACCEDE",
                  "answers": [
                    "refuse",
                    "confess",
                    "interrupt",
                    "give",
                    "agree"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACCEDE",
                  "correct": "agree"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DIADEM",
                  "answers": [
                    "ring",
                    "star",
                    "crown",
                    "robe",
                    "necklace"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIADEM",
                  "correct": "crown"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DROLL",
                  "answers": [
                    "comical",
                    "serious",
                    "cruel",
                    "uneducated",
                    "tuneful"
                  ],
                  "word": "DROLL",
                  "correct": "comical"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENNUI",
                  "answers": [
                    "boredom",
                    "envy",
                    "weakness",
                    "calmness",
                    "courtesy"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENNUI",
                  "correct": "boredom"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INDISPOSED",
                  "answers": [
                    "too busy",
                    "dying",
                    "ignorant",
                    "mildly ill",
                    "unhelpful"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDISPOSED",
                  "correct": "mildly ill"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INJUNCTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "plea",
                    "arrest",
                    "command",
                    "connection",
                    "penalty"
                  ],
                  "word": "INJUNCTION",
                  "correct": "command"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to REGALE",
                  "answers": [
                    "offend",
                    "delight",
                    "rejoin",
                    "ridicule",
                    "admire"
                  ],
                  "word": "REGALE",
                  "correct": "delight"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VAGARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "lie",
                    "whim",
                    "trick",
                    "symptom",
                    "hope"
                  ],
                  "word": "VAGARY",
                  "correct": "whim"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a sneer EVINCE scorn?",
                  "word": "EVINCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are LUGUBRIOUS people fun to have around?",
                  "word": "LUGUBRIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would winning a million dollars MITIGATE one's financial problems?",
                  "word": "MITIGATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a PATENT mistake easy to spot?",
                  "word": "PATENTLY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you PERPETRATE a masterpiece?",
                  "word": "PERPETRATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a mother enjoy hearing her child make PLAINTIVE sounds?",
                  "word": "PLAINTIVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do teachers prefer TRACTABLE students?",
                  "word": "TRACTABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a generous person readily ACCEDE to a request?",
                  "word": "ACCEDE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a DIADEM valuable?",
                  "word": "DIADEM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a stodgy person be DROLL?",
                  "word": "DROLL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a yawn be evidence of ENNUI?",
                  "word": "ENNUI",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a headache make one INDISPOSED?",
                  "word": "INDISPOSED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a conviction the same as an INJUNCTION?",
                  "word": "INJUNCTION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could amusing stories REGALE a person?",
                  "word": "REGALE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a letter contain VAGARIES?",
                  "word": "VAGARY",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Sally EVINCED her anger by slamming the door behind her.",
                  "word": "EVINCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The LUGUBRIOUS man laughed heartily at the story of our adventures.",
                  "word": "LUGUBRIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The judge said that, since there were no MITIGATING circumstances, he would have to impose the full penalty prescribed by law.",
                  "word": "MITIGATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The track coach said it was PATENTLY impossible for anyone to run so fast.",
                  "word": "PATENTLY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The critic said that the actors who had PERPETRATED these dismal performances should be banned from the theater.",
                  "word": "PERPETRATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The student PLAINTIVELY requested just one more day in which to finish the report.",
                  "word": "PLAINTIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The unruly prisoners became TRACTABLE when they were threatened with further punishment.",
                  "word": "TRACTABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He ACCEDED to us all we could ask for.",
                  "word": "ACCEDE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The king placed the DIADEM on the young prince's head as a symbol of the transfer of power",
                  "word": "DIADEM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The DROLL tolling of the bell told us the funeral was over.",
                  "word": "DROLL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jack's ENNUI deepened as they continued to talk about things he wasn't interested in.",
                  "word": "ENNUI",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jane was INDISPOSED to help someone who had been rude to her.",
                  "word": "INDISPOSED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She ignored the dentist's INJUNCTION to brush her teeth after every meal.",
                  "word": "INJUNCTION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Their mother REGALED them to clean up their rooms fast.",
                  "word": "REGALE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Students enjoyed the professor's occasional VAGARIES more than his formal presentation of the material.",
                  "word": "VAGARY",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "EVINCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "manifest",
                    "display",
                    "create"
                  ],
                  "word": "EVINCE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LUGUBRIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "sullen",
                    "diseased",
                    "gloomy"
                  ],
                  "word": "LUGUBRIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MITIGATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "augment",
                    "assuage",
                    "extenuate"
                  ],
                  "word": "MITIGATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PATENTLY",
                  "answers": [
                    "evidently",
                    "typically",
                    "plainly"
                  ],
                  "word": "PATENTLY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERPETRATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "commit",
                    "perform",
                    "argue"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERPETRATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PLAINTIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "pitiful",
                    "sinful",
                    "melancholy"
                  ],
                  "word": "PLAINTIVE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRACTABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "submissive",
                    "amenable",
                    "friendly"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRACTABLE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ACCEDE",
                  "answers": [
                    "incline",
                    "assent",
                    "acquiesce"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACCEDE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DIADEM",
                  "answers": [
                    "crown",
                    "headband",
                    "sword"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIADEM",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DROLL",
                  "answers": [
                    "dull",
                    "whimsical",
                    "witty"
                  ],
                  "word": "DROLL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENNUI",
                  "answers": [
                    "listlessness",
                    "depression",
                    "fright"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENNUI",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INDISPOSED",
                  "answers": [
                    "averse",
                    "unwell",
                    "unhappy"
                  ],
                  "word": "INDISPOSED",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INJUNCTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "directive",
                    "appraisal",
                    "admonishment"
                  ],
                  "word": "INJUNCTION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REGALE",
                  "answers": [
                    "instruct",
                    "entertain",
                    "please"
                  ],
                  "word": "REGALE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VAGARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "whim",
                    "fracas",
                    "fancy"
                  ],
                  "word": "VAGARY",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "8.2",
          "definitions": {
            "ACETOUS": {
              "word": "ACETOUS",
              "phonetic": "(as'-g-tgs",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "vinegary, sour tasting \nACETOUS comes from the Latin word for <em>vinegar</em>. It means \"pertaining to or producing vinegar.\" It is sometimes used in an extended sense to mean generally <em>sour</em> or <em>sour tasting</em>. \n\"The chemical formula produces an ACETOUS solution that is very sour to the taste.\" \n\"The sarcastic man made some ACETOUS comments about the way the government was being run.\""
            },
            "ALACRITY": {
              "word": "ALACRITY",
              "phonetic": "(g-lak'-rg-tE)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "eagerness, readiness, willingness \nALACRITY is promptness, eagerness, lively readiness. The word is used with regard to a person who is eager or quite willing to do something, and who will respond quickly and cheerfully when asked. \n\"When Charles asked her to the party, she accepted with ALACRITY.\" \n\"The ALACRITY with which George went on overtime surprised his boss; he hadn't thought George needed the money.\" \n\"When the call came, the firemen responded with ALACRITY: they were dressed and in their engines in thirty seconds.\""
            },
            "COMPORT": {
              "word": "COMPORT",
              "phonetic": "(kgm-port')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to behave, conduct; to agree, correspond \nCOMPORT means to <em>behave</em>. It is used reflexively--that is, with a word such as <em>himself</em>, <em>herself</em>, or <em>themselves</em>. \n\"James COMPORTED himself with great dignity at his father's funeral.\" \n\"At the opera Ann COMPORTED herself in such a way that we knew she went there all the time.\" \nIn a different sense, COMPORT can mean to <em>agree</em> or <em>correspond</em>. In this sense the word is followed by <em>with</em>. \n\"The statements in this book do not COMPORT with our current understanding of the facts.\" \nOther forms of the word: COMPORTMENT, n."
            },
            "CURSORY": {
              "word": "CURSORY",
              "phonetic": "(ker'-sg-rE)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "superficial, hasty \nCURSORY comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>run</em>, also the source of <em>current</em> and <em>course</em>. CURSORY means \"done hastily and without thoroughness,\" <em>superficial</em>. The word usually suggests casualness and lack of attention to detail. \n\"With a single CURSORY glance at the painting the expert said it was obviously a fake.\" \n\"Jim had time for only a CURSORY reading of the report before the meeting.\" \n\"The president made a CURSORY reference to the problem, but didn't go into any detail about how he would solve it.\" \nMany people pick <em>swift</em> as the word closest in meaning to CURSORY on the Pretest. CURSORY certainly suggests swiftness, but the emphasis in the word is on the lack of care and thoroughness brought about by one's speed of doing something."
            },
            "DENIZEN": {
              "word": "DENIZEN",
              "phonetic": "(den'-g-zgn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an inhabitant, resident \nA DENIZEN is an inhabitant of a region or a country, particularly one who belongs there by birth or naturalization. \n\"The stranger's wild appearance shocked the staid DENIZENS of the small town.\" \"At the aquarium we saw sharks, squid, and other DENIZENS of the ocean.\" \"The woodsman was familiar with all the DENIZENS of the forest.\""
            },
            "DESICCATE": {
              "word": "DESICCATE",
              "phonetic": "(des'-i-kAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to dry up, dry thoroughly \nTo DESICCATE is to dry thoroughly, to remove all the moisture from. \n\"The intense dry heat DESICCATED all the logs we had cut.\" \nIt can also mean to <em>become dry</em>. \n\"All the plants DESICCATED during the drought.\" \nIn a specific sense, DESICCATE can mean \"to preserve (a food) by removing the moisture.\" In an extension of its basic meaning, DESICCATE also means \"to make dry or dull, to drain of interest and vitality.\" \n\"The critic called the play stale and DESICCATED, devoid of intellectual or human interest.\" \n\"The professor claimed that censorship DESICCATED art by removing all that was fresh and vital in it.\" \nOther forms of the word: DESICCATION, n. DESICCATIVE, adj."
            },
            "EGRESS": {
              "word": "EGRESS",
              "phonetic": "(E'-gres)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "exit, departure \nEGRESS comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>go out</em>. See <em>e-</em> under Prefixes. The <em>gress</em> root, meaning <em>go</em>, is also found in such words as <em>progress</em> and <em>regress</em>. An EGRESS is the act of leaving a place. \n\"The students' EGRESS from the classroom at the end of the day was rapid and noisy.\" \nAn EGRESS is also the place by means of which one departs, an exit. \n\"The only EGRESS from the room was a skylight far above his head.\""
            },
            "IMPECUNIOUS": {
              "word": "IMPECUNIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(im-pi-kyU'-nE-gs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "penniless, indigent, needy \n<em>Pecunia</em> is the Latin word for <em>money</em>. It is found in the English words <em>pecuniary</em>, \"having to do with money,\" and IMPECUNIOUS. See <em>in-2</em> under Prefixes and <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. The basic meaning of IMPECUNIOUS is \"not having money.\" IMPECUNIOUS generally implies that this is a more or less continuous state, and sometimes suggests that it is the person's own fault, because of overspending. \n\"The IMPECUNIOUS young man was constantly borrowing money from his friends.\" \n\"Her IMPECUNIOUS father was forever having difficulty making the mortgage payments on the house.\""
            },
            "MALADROIT": {
              "word": "MALADROIT",
              "phonetic": "(mal-g-droyt')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "awkward, clumsy; tactless, inept \nThe French and Latin prefix <em>mal-</em> means <em>bad</em> or <em>badly</em>. Someone who is MALADROIT is \"badly adroit,\" is not at all skillful or dexterous. The word can be used about physical clumsiness, but it is more frequently applied to a lack of tact or good judgment in social situations. \n\"The president's MALADROIT remarks managed to offend just about everyone at the meeting.\" \n\"Her MALADROIT attempt to make excuses for herself only got her into deeper trouble.\" \n\"Betty detested family gatherings; try as she would, she always seemed to say something MALADROIT and offend someone.\""
            },
            "MALEDICTION": {
              "word": "MALEDICTION",
              "phonetic": "(mal-g-dik'-shgn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a curse, slander \nThe <em>dic</em> part of MALEDICTION comes from a Latin word meaning <em>speak</em>; it is also found in words like <em>diction</em>, <em>dictation</em>, <em>predict</em>, and <em>contradict</em>. The <em>mal</em> part of the word means <em>bad</em>; see <em>maladroit</em> in this chapter. A MALEDICTION is bad speech directed at someone, a curse or slander. It is the opposite of <em>benediction</em>, which is a <em>blessing</em>. \n\"The witch uttered a grim MALEDICTION against her torturers.\" \n\"Despite the MALEDICTIONS of his opponents the governor was reelected.\""
            },
            "MENDICANT": {
              "word": "MENDICANT",
              "phonetic": "(men'-di-kgnt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a beggar \nA MENDICANT is a person who lives by begging. \n\"The MENDICANT went from house to house, begging for alms.\" \nMENDICANT is also an adjective meaning \"practicing begging.\" \n\"The MENDICANT friars depended on the charity of the townspeople for food and shelter.\" \nMENDICANT orders are religious orders whose members are not allowed to own property, and who originally had to live by receiving alms."
            },
            "SALUTARY": {
              "word": "SALUTARY",
              "phonetic": "(sal'-yÔøΩ-ter-E)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "wholesome, healthful, salubrious, remedial \nSALUTARY comes from the Latin word for <em>health</em>. Its basic meaning is \"promoting health.\" \n\"This ointment's effect is SALUTARY; it will be quite an effective medicine.\" \nIn an extended sense, SALUTARY means \"producing a beneficial effect.\" In this sense, it is often used about things that may be temporarily unpleasant, but ultimately will be helpful. \n\"The doctor said that a salt-free diet would prove to be SALUTARY in the long run.\" \n\"This SALUTARY criticism helped the pianist overcome many of her problems.\" \n\"The SALUTARY debate forced both sides to think more deeply about the issue.\""
            },
            "UMBRAGE": {
              "word": "UMBRAGE",
              "phonetic": "(uhm'-brij)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "offense, resentment, annoyance \nUMBRAGE is usually used in the phrases \"to give UMBRAGE\" or \"to take UMBRAGE.\" To take UMBRAGE is to take offense, often because one's pride is hurt. \n\"John took UMBRAGE at the coach's suggestion that he wasn't trying hard.\" \n\"I'm afraid I gave UMBRAGE to Mr. Donnelly with my remarks about his children.\" \n\"Jones said he didn't feel any UMBRAGE about being passed over for the promotion, because he didn't think he was qualified.\""
            },
            "ABSCOND": {
              "word": "ABSCOND",
              "phonetic": "(ab-skond')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to depart hurriedly and secretly, flee, escape \nTo ABSCOND is to leave in a sudden and secret manner, generally to avoid the consequences of a crime. \n\"The embezzler ABSCONDED with millions of dollars of the bank's money.\" \n\"When the Internal Revenue Service began investigating his tax returns, Bill decided to ABSCOND from the country.\" \n\"The mobster chose to ABSCOND rather than stand trial for murder.\" \n<em>Rob</em> is the most common wrong answer, chosen by people who know that ABSCOND has something to do with crime. Robbers might ABSCOND after committing their crime, but ABSCOND means to <em>flee</em>, not to <em>rob</em>."
            },
            "LACHRYMOSE": {
              "word": "LACHRYMOSE",
              "phonetic": "(lak'-rÔøΩ-mOs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "tearful, weepy; melancholy, mournful \nLACHRYMOSE comes from the Latin word for <em>tear</em> and means \"given to tears or weeping.\" The word usually has a somewhat negative sense, suggesting that the weepiness is excessive. \n\"When he was drunk he became quite LACHRYMOSE, weeping over the sins of his past and the state of the world.\" \nLACHRYMOSE also means \"causing tears,\" <em>melancholy</em>. \n\"After his defeat the politician made a LACHRYMOSE speech, full of self-pity and resentment.\" \n\"Their farewell at the airport was long and LACHRYMOSE. They didn't know if they'd ever see each other again.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ACETOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "vinegary",
                    "smooth",
                    "brittle",
                    "putrid",
                    "sweet"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACETOUS",
                  "correct": "vinegary"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ALACRITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "uncertainty",
                    "despair",
                    "sarcasm",
                    "cleverness",
                    "eagerness"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALACRITY",
                  "correct": "eagerness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to COMPORT",
                  "answers": [
                    "instruct",
                    "transmit",
                    "join",
                    "believe",
                    "behave"
                  ],
                  "word": "COMPORT",
                  "correct": "behave"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CURSORY",
                  "answers": [
                    "careful",
                    "swift",
                    "superficial",
                    "deceptive",
                    "unnecessary"
                  ],
                  "word": "CURSORY",
                  "correct": "superficial"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DENIZEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "stranger",
                    "inhabitant",
                    "supporter",
                    "veteran",
                    "victim"
                  ],
                  "word": "DENIZEN",
                  "correct": "inhabitant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DESICCATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "massacre",
                    "flood",
                    "dry up",
                    "crush",
                    "burn"
                  ],
                  "word": "DESICCATE",
                  "correct": "dry up"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EGRESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "entrance",
                    "exit",
                    "corridor",
                    "descent",
                    "pathway"
                  ],
                  "word": "EGRESS",
                  "correct": "exit"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPECUNIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "extravagant",
                    "homeless",
                    "penniless",
                    "strange",
                    "humorless"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPECUNIOUS",
                  "correct": "penniless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MALADROIT",
                  "answers": [
                    "ill",
                    "vicious",
                    "unhappy",
                    "awkward",
                    "skillful"
                  ],
                  "word": "MALADROIT",
                  "correct": "awkward"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MALEDICTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "admiration",
                    "illness",
                    "mistake",
                    "criticism",
                    "curse"
                  ],
                  "word": "MALEDICTION",
                  "correct": "curse"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MENDICANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "beggar",
                    "tailor",
                    "cripple",
                    "miser",
                    "priest"
                  ],
                  "word": "MENDICANT",
                  "correct": "beggar"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SALUTARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "lonely",
                    "wholesome",
                    "perfect",
                    "bad",
                    "wet"
                  ],
                  "word": "SALUTARY",
                  "correct": "wholesome"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UMBRAGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "pleasure",
                    "concern",
                    "offense",
                    "danger",
                    "pressure"
                  ],
                  "word": "UMBRAGE",
                  "correct": "offense"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ABSCOND",
                  "answers": [
                    "lie",
                    "wander",
                    "flee",
                    "rob",
                    "hide"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABSCOND",
                  "correct": "flee"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LACHRYMOSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "tearful",
                    "sleepy",
                    "thirsty",
                    "grim",
                    "lazy"
                  ],
                  "word": "LACHRYMOSE",
                  "correct": "tearful"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Is sugar ACETOUS?",
                  "word": "ACETOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are lazy people known for their ALACRITY?",
                  "word": "ALACRITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a rowdy COMPORT himself with dignity?",
                  "word": "COMPORT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a painstaking examination CURSORY?",
                  "word": "CURSORY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are you a DENIZEN of the universe?",
                  "word": "DENIZEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can heat cause things to DESICCATE?",
                  "word": "DESICCATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a trap door be an EGRESS?",
                  "word": "EGRESS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are IMPECUNIOUS people likely to spend a great deal of money?",
                  "word": "IMPECUNIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should diplomats be MALADROIT?",
                  "word": "MALADROIT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person generally be pleased by MALEDICTIONS?",
                  "word": "MALEDICTION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are MENDICANTS usually needy?",
                  "word": "MENDICANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can self-denial be SALUTARY?",
                  "word": "SALUTARY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person take UMBRAGE at being cursed at?",
                  "word": "UMBRAGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person who is ABSCONDING be in a hurry?",
                  "word": "ABSCOND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a love story be LACHRYMOSE?",
                  "word": "LACHRYMOSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "The cider had an unpleasant ACETOUS taste that told us it had gone bad.",
                  "word": "ACETOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her ALACRITY in accepting the job startled the interviewer.",
                  "word": "ALACRITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Mary COMPORTED herself better than anyone else in the contest.",
                  "word": "COMPORT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His CURSORY attempts to keep us informed showed that he really didn't care what we knew.",
                  "word": "CURSORY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The exterminator said he would get rid of the termites, carpenter ants, and any other unwanted DENIZENS of the house.",
                  "word": "DENIZEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The piece of fruit was old and DESICCATED and did not look very appetizing.",
                  "word": "DESICCATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The fire blocked their only means of EGRESS from the building.",
                  "word": "EGRESS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The IMPECUNIOUS man finally went bankrupt.",
                  "word": "IMPECUNIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The speaker's MALADROIT witticisms did little to put the audience at ease.",
                  "word": "MALADROIT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The priest uttered a brief MALEDICTION for us before we set off on the dangerous journey.",
                  "word": "MALEDICTION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We offered the MENDICANT what food and money we could spare.",
                  "word": "MENDICANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The SALUTARY woman said she had never felt better in her life.",
                  "word": "SALUTARY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Mrs. Fields took UMBRAGE at the teacher's comment that her son watched too much television.",
                  "word": "UMBRAGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Three teenagers ABSCONDED the liquor store of a thousand dollars.",
                  "word": "ABSCOND",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The LACHRYMOSE girl found a dozen things to weep about in the newspaper every morning.",
                  "word": "LACHRYMOSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ACETOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "tart",
                    "hot",
                    "sour"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACETOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ALACRITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "harshness",
                    "swiftness",
                    "eagerness"
                  ],
                  "word": "ALACRITY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COMPORT",
                  "answers": [
                    "express",
                    "agree",
                    "behave"
                  ],
                  "word": "COMPORT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CURSORY",
                  "answers": [
                    "haphazard",
                    "rapid",
                    "hasty"
                  ],
                  "word": "CURSORY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DENIZEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "resident",
                    "traveler",
                    "inhabitant"
                  ],
                  "word": "DENIZEN",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DESICCATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "starve",
                    "bake",
                    "parch"
                  ],
                  "word": "DESICCATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EGRESS",
                  "answers": [
                    "movement",
                    "departure",
                    "exit"
                  ],
                  "word": "EGRESS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPECUNIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "needy",
                    "devious",
                    "destitute"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPECUNIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MALADROIT",
                  "answers": [
                    "tactless",
                    "sarcastic",
                    "gauche"
                  ],
                  "word": "MALADROIT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MALEDICTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "curse",
                    "denunciation",
                    "fright"
                  ],
                  "word": "MALEDICTION",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MENDICANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "solicitor",
                    "physician",
                    "beggar"
                  ],
                  "word": "MENDICANT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SALUTARY",
                  "answers": [
                    "sanitary",
                    "truthful",
                    "beneficial"
                  ],
                  "word": "SALUTARY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UMBRAGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "resentment",
                    "indignation",
                    "incredulity"
                  ],
                  "word": "UMBRAGE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABSCOND",
                  "answers": [
                    "escape",
                    "flee",
                    "retreat"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABSCOND",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LACHRYMOSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "ashamed",
                    "tearful",
                    "sorrowful"
                  ],
                  "word": "LACHRYMOSE",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "8.3",
          "definitions": {
            "PUERILE": {
              "word": "PUERILE",
              "phonetic": "(pyU'-ÔøΩr-il",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "childish, juvenile, foolish \nPUERILE comes from the Latin word for boy, <em>puer</em>. Someone who is PUERILE is boyish, childish. It is an uncomplimentary term that suggests immaturity, even foolishness. \n\"'Stop being so PUERILE--it's time to grow up', she would say whenever her husband threw a tantrum.\" \n\"You may be twenty-one-years old, but your PUERILE behavior makes you seem about ten.\" \nOther forms of the word: PUERILITY, n."
            },
            "TRENCHANT": {
              "word": "TRENCHANT",
              "phonetic": "(tren'-ch:mt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "incisive, keen, effective \nTRENCHANT was originally applied to objects and meant <em>sharp</em>, <em>keen</em>, as a \"TRENCHANT blade.\" That meaning is now obsolete and the word is only used figuratively to describe speech, thought, or manner that penetrates or cuts to the heart of an issue. \n\"The speaker's comments on civil rights were TRENCHANT: we saw the issue more clearly than ever before.\" \n\"The judge's TRENCHANT analysis of the case aided the jury in its debate.\" \n\"The politician's grave manner made his utterances seem TRENCHANT even when they were nonsensical.\" \nOther forms of the word: TRENCHANCY, n."
            },
            "BUFFET": {
              "word": "BUFFET",
              "phonetic": "(buht'-it)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to strike, hit, batter, beat, thrash \nTo BUFFET is to hit repeatedly as if with an open hand. The word can be used about actual physical beating, or it can be used figuratively. \n\"High waves BUFFETED the sides of the ship.\" \n\"He had been constantly BUFFETED by the misfortunes of life.\" \nBUFFET is also a noun. \n\"The house withstood the BUFFETS of the tree branches during the hurricane.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>protect</em>, probably due to a confusion of BUFFET and <em>buffer</em>, which is something that protects by reducing the shock of impact or by shielding from undesirable pressures."
            },
            "CRAVEN": {
              "word": "CRAVEN",
              "phonetic": "(krA'-vÔøΩn)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "cowardly, pusillanimous \nCRAVEN is both a noun and an adjective. A CRAVEN is an abject coward, someone who is contemptibly fearful in the face of danger. \n\"The CRAVEN turned and ran as soon as he saw the enemy soldiers in the distance.\" \nAs an adjective CRAVEN is used about people and activities that demonstrate this cowardice. \n\"The CRAVEN scoundrel challenged me to a duel, then fled the city when I accepted his challenge.\" \n\"Your CRAVEN refusal to stand up for your principles sickens me.\""
            },
            "DETRITUS": {
              "word": "DETRITUS",
              "phonetic": "(di-trl'-tÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "debris \nDETRITUS is the loose material that forms from the abrasion or erosion of rocks. In an extended sense, DETRITUS is used about fragmented material of any sort, <em>debris</em>. \n\"After the avalanche, all that remained of the cliff was DETRITUS.\" \n\"The flood victims searched among the DETRITUS of their homes for prized possessions.\" \nDETRITUS can also be used figuratively. \n\"The woman tried in vain to dredge the visitor's name from the DETRITUS of her memory.\""
            },
            "DIDACTIC": {
              "word": "DIDACTIC",
              "phonetic": "(dl-dak'-tik",
              "pos": " adj.",
              "deftext": "instructive, pedantic \nDIDACTIC means \"intended to teach,\" often some moral lesson. It is frequently used in a derogatory sense about someone or something that tries to teach too much or too often. \n\"DIDACTIC Aunt Betty never missed a chance to instruct: even a social call was turned into a lecture.\" \n\"The professor was so DIDACTIC that he would quiz a student if he met him in the hall.\" \n\"The history text is accurate, but so dry and DIDACTIC that it's impossible to read.\""
            },
            "PREVARICATE": {
              "word": "PREVARICATE",
              "phonetic": "(pri-var'-::!-kAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to lie, equivocate \nPREVARICATE comes from a Latin word meaning \"to walk crookedly.\" In English, to PREVARICATE is to stray from the path of the truth. It is a formal and high-sounding synonym of <em>lie</em>. It is also used to suggest a weaker kind of \"avoiding the truth.\" \n\"The student attempted to PREVARICATE, and said he hadn't really meant to cheat, but the book just happened to be open on his lap.\" \n\"Ed's boss accused him of PREVARICATING when he said that the report must have been lost in the mail.\" \nOther forms of the word: PREVARICATION, n. PREVARICATOR, n."
            },
            "INCIPIENT": {
              "word": "INCIPIENT",
              "phonetic": "(in-sip'-E-:;,nt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "beginning, commencing, initial \nINCIPIENT means \"at an early stage,\" <em>beginning</em>. It comes from a Latin verb meaning \"to take in hand,\" and thus to <em>start</em>. The <em>cip</em> root, meaning to <em>take</em>, is also found in the word <em>recipient</em>. \n\"The INCIPIENT revolt was crushed before it had a chance to spread.\" \n\"The INCIPIENT stage of the illness is characterized by nausea and a low fever.\" \n\"The president thought it was an INCIPIENT problem and should be taken care of before it became serious.\" \nOther forms of the word: INCIPIENCE, n. INCIPIENCY, n."
            },
            "PITHY": {
              "word": "PITHY",
              "phonetic": "(pith'-E)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "terse, concise, cogent \nA PITHY statement is one that is both brief and full of substance, so that it is particularly effective. \n\"His argument was intelligent and PITHY; the opposition had no time to think of a rebuttal.\" \n\"The father and daughter corresponded with notes that were short but PITHY; all the important information was transmitted.\" \n\"Angela preferred the PITHY news reports on television to the wordiness of the newspaper.\" \n<em>Sarcastic</em> is chosen more often than the correct answer, <em>concise</em>. PITHY remarks are short and forceful and often witty; they may be sarcastic, but they do not have to be."
            },
            "RAREFIED": {
              "word": "RAREFIED",
              "phonetic": "(rÔøΩ_ir'-:;,-fld)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "exalted, elevated, esoteric \nThe basic meaning of the verb to RAREFY is to <em>make rare</em>. From this it came to mean \"to make more spiritual.\" RAREFIED is the adjective from RAREFY. It can mean \"of interest to a small select group,\" <em>esoteric</em>. \n\"The art of glass-blowing has become so RAREFIED that only a few craftsmen now practice it.\" \nOr it can mean <em>exalted</em>, <em>lofty</em>, usually in a figurative sense. \n\"The young ballplayer aspired to the RAREFIED heights of the Hall of Fame.\" \n\"We were completely lost in this RAREFIED realm of pure mathematics.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>unknown</em>, probably a guess based on the <em>rare</em> in RAREFIED. Other forms of the word: RAREFY, v."
            },
            "SANGFROID": {
              "word": "SANGFROID",
              "phonetic": "(sahn-frwah')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "composure, equanimity, self-possession, imperturbability \nNote the pronunciation. SANGFROID is from the French, and keeps its French pronunciation. SANGFROID literally means \"cold blood\" in French. In English SANGFROID is used for the quality of great coolness and self-possession, especially under trying circumstances. \n\"With incredible SANGFROID he walked right up to the criminal and took the gun away from him.\" \n\"You have to admire her SANGFROID. Millions of people were watching her performance, and it didn't seem to bother her at all.\" \n\"Bill is somewhat lacking in SANGFROID. He gets very nervous when there is any pressure put on him.\" \n<em>Arrogance</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer. Arrogance is a characteristic that one might associate with SANGFROID, but the two words are not synonymous."
            },
            "SUCCOR": {
              "word": "SUCCOR",
              "phonetic": "(suhk'-ÔøΩr)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "aid, assistance, relief \nSUCCOR means <em>help</em>, especially help given to someone in distress. \n\"The Coast Guard is always there to give SUCCOR to ships in distress.\" \n\"In times of trouble, the family found SUCCOR in their faith.\" \nSUCCOR is also the person or thing that gives help. \n\"The Aid to Families with Dependent Children program is a great SUCCOR to poor people.\" \nSUCCOR is also used as a verb. \n\"All attempts to SUCCOR the poor man and his family proved fruitless.\""
            },
            "ACERBITY": {
              "word": "ACERBITY",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩ-ser'-bÔøΩtE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "sourness, acidity of taste or manner \nACERBITY comes from the Latin word for <em>sharp</em>. Its basic meaning in English is \"sour or acid to the taste\": \"The cranberry's ACERBITY is such that you can't eat it without sugar.\" It is used more often in its extended sense of sourness of disposition, sharpness of manner. \n\"The woman's ACERBITY made her a harsh mistress; nothing was ever done right, or quickly enough.\" \n\"Barbara's quick mind and ACERBITY of manner made her a formidable debating opponent.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>quickness</em>, perhaps due to a confusion with the word <em>alacrity</em>. See <em>alacrity</em> in Chapter 2. \nOther forms of the word: ACERB, adj. ACERBIC, adj."
            },
            "BUCOLIC": {
              "word": "BUCOLIC",
              "phonetic": "(byU-kol'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "pastoral, rustic \nBUCOLIC means \"pertaining to shepherds,\" <em>pastoral</em>. In a broader sense, it can refer to the life of the countryside generally. The word usually emphasizes the peacefulness and simplicity of rustic life. \n\"Victoria felt sure she would be happy in this BUCOLIC setting of meadows and farms.\" \n\"The BUCOLIC atmosphere was destroyed when the bulldozers appeared and started tearing up the fields.\" \nThe wrong answer <em>poisonous</em> attracts many people, probably due to confusion with the adjective <em>bubonic</em>. The <em>bubonic</em> plague is a contagious, usually fatal disease transmitted by infected rats."
            },
            "CALUMNY": {
              "word": "CALUMNY",
              "phonetic": "(kal'-ÔøΩm-nE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "slander, detraction, defamation \nCALUMNY is the malicious telling of an untruth in order to hurt someone. \n\"The candidate said that the rumors about her past were CALUMNY; she had never been to prison.\" \n\"Famous people cannot escape CALUMNY; someone is always out to destroy their reputations.\" \nCALUMNY is also used about the false statement itself. \n\"The movie star said she would sue the reporter over his outrageous CALUMNIES.\" \n\"Paul said it was a CALUMNY even to suggest he might have cheated on the test.\" \nOther forms of the word: CALUMNIATE, v. CALUMNIOUS, adj."
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "PUERILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "difficult",
                    "easy",
                    "childish",
                    "unimportant",
                    "indecent"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUERILE",
                  "correct": "childish"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRENCHANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "disgusting",
                    "incisive",
                    "ambiguous",
                    "painful",
                    "unnecessary"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRENCHANT",
                  "correct": "incisive"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to BUFFET",
                  "answers": [
                    "protect",
                    "trip",
                    "hurt",
                    "strike",
                    "threaten"
                  ],
                  "word": "BUFFET",
                  "correct": "strike"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CRAVEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "cowardly",
                    "tricky",
                    "sarcastic",
                    "helpless",
                    "shy"
                  ],
                  "word": "CRAVEN",
                  "correct": "cowardly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DETRITUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "debris",
                    "equipment",
                    "rain",
                    "food",
                    "clothing"
                  ],
                  "word": "DETRITUS",
                  "correct": "debris"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DIDACTIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "impersonal",
                    "boring",
                    "complicated",
                    "imitative",
                    "instructive"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIDACTIC",
                  "correct": "instructive"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to PREVARICATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "postpone",
                    "lie",
                    "gossip",
                    "hide out",
                    "prepare"
                  ],
                  "word": "PREVARICATE",
                  "correct": "lie"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCIPIENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "final",
                    "difficult",
                    "beginning",
                    "worst",
                    "next"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCIPIENT",
                  "correct": "beginning"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PITHY",
                  "answers": [
                    "true",
                    "ugly",
                    "sarcastic",
                    "terse",
                    "humorous"
                  ],
                  "word": "PITHY",
                  "correct": "terse"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RAREFIED",
                  "answers": [
                    "exalted",
                    "aged",
                    "microscopic",
                    "fake",
                    "unknown"
                  ],
                  "word": "RAREFIED",
                  "correct": "exalted"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SANGFROID",
                  "answers": [
                    "agitation",
                    "spirit",
                    "charm",
                    "composure",
                    "arrogance"
                  ],
                  "word": "SANGFROID",
                  "correct": "composure"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUCCOR",
                  "answers": [
                    "trickery",
                    "food",
                    "affection",
                    "praise",
                    "aid"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUCCOR",
                  "correct": "aid"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ACERBITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "quickness",
                    "sourness",
                    "courtesy",
                    "silliness",
                    "unhappiness"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACERBITY",
                  "correct": "sourness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BUCOLIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "urban",
                    "poisonous",
                    "pastoral",
                    "joyous",
                    "heavenly"
                  ],
                  "word": "BUCOLIC",
                  "correct": "pastoral"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CALUMNY",
                  "answers": [
                    "praise",
                    "disgrace",
                    "slander",
                    "celebration",
                    "rumor"
                  ],
                  "word": "CALUMNY",
                  "correct": "slander"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a PUERILE plan excite admiration?",
                  "word": "PUERILE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a brief examination likely to lead to a TRENCHANT analysis?",
                  "word": "TRENCHANT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person dislike being BUFFETED?",
                  "word": "BUFFET",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a CRAVEN be brave during a battle?",
                  "word": "CRAVEN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is DETRITUS generally valuable?",
                  "word": "DETRITUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a DIDACTIC person usually ignorant?",
                  "word": "DIDACTIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are witnesses at a trial supposed to PREVARICATE?",
                  "word": "PREVARICATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a person getting better during the INCIPIENT stages of a disease?",
                  "word": "INCIPIENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are mottoes usually PITHY?",
                  "word": "PITHY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is general a RAREFIED rank in the army?",
                  "word": "RAREFIED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a frightened person possess SANGFROID?",
                  "word": "SANGFROID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a beggar be in need of SUCCOR?",
                  "word": "SUCCOR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a movie critic possess ACERBITY?",
                  "word": "ACERBITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would shepherds live in a BUCOLIC area?",
                  "word": "BUCOLIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a CALUMNY be true?",
                  "word": "CALUMNY",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Her PUERILE chatter convinced us she didn't have the maturity required for the job.",
                  "word": "PUERILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "All the actors felt the sting of the critic's TRENCHANT comments.",
                  "word": "TRENCHANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She had received so many BUFFETS at the hands of Fate that finally she just gave up.",
                  "word": "BUFFET",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The CRAVEN general saved his own skin while endangering all his troops.",
                  "word": "CRAVEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "There is so much DETRITUS in the basement that we'll never get it all cleaned out.",
                  "word": "DETRITUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her DIDACTIC speech told us more than we wanted to know about the benefits of virtuous living.",
                  "word": "DIDACTIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The fireman PREVARICATED us from entering the burning building.",
                  "word": "PREVARICATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Grandma's INCIPIENT deafness caused her to occasionally miss snatches of the conversation.",
                  "word": "INCIPIENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The announcer's PITHY comments heightened our enjoyment of the football game.",
                  "word": "PITHY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Buffalo are almost completely RAREFIED in that part of the country.",
                  "word": "RAREFIED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Phipps could tell the most outrageous lies with complete SANGFROID, even when speaking to very important people.",
                  "word": "SANGFROID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The relief agencies could provide little SUCCOR for the thousands of unemployed.",
                  "word": "SUCCOR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ACERBITY of the teacher's comments showed she didn't think much of Steve's paper.",
                  "word": "ACERBITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Albert feared any BUCOLIC intrusion into his already busy life.",
                  "word": "BUCOLIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "These CALUMNIES cannot be allowed to go unchallenged, or people will start believing them.",
                  "word": "CALUMNY",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "PUERILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "adolescent",
                    "infantile",
                    "novel"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUERILE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRENCHANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "comical",
                    "caustic",
                    "penetrating"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRENCHANT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BUFFET",
                  "answers": [
                    "smite",
                    "pummel",
                    "cleave"
                  ],
                  "word": "BUFFET",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CRAVEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "timorous",
                    "sly",
                    "frightened"
                  ],
                  "word": "CRAVEN",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DETRITUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "boulders",
                    "fragments",
                    "rubbish"
                  ],
                  "word": "DETRITUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DIDACTIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "erudite",
                    "moralistic",
                    "mournful"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIDACTIC",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PREVARICATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "deceive",
                    "disagree",
                    "lie"
                  ],
                  "word": "PREVARICATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCIPIENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "initial",
                    "derivative",
                    "introductory"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCIPIENT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PITHY",
                  "answers": [
                    "succinct",
                    "cogent",
                    "cursory"
                  ],
                  "word": "PITHY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RAREFIED",
                  "answers": [
                    "abstruse",
                    "lofty",
                    "banal"
                  ],
                  "word": "RAREFIED",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SANGFROID",
                  "answers": [
                    "composure",
                    "zeal",
                    "aplomb"
                  ],
                  "word": "SANGFROID",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUCCOR",
                  "answers": [
                    "assist",
                    "relieve",
                    "flee"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUCCOR",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ACERBITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "bitterness",
                    "acrimony",
                    "anguish"
                  ],
                  "word": "ACERBITY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BUCOLIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "diseased",
                    "serene",
                    "rural"
                  ],
                  "word": "BUCOLIC",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CALUMNY",
                  "answers": [
                    "abuse",
                    "vilification",
                    "rebuke"
                  ],
                  "word": "CALUMNY",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ACCEDE",
            "answer": "accede"
          },
          {
            "word": "DIDACTIC",
            "answer": "didactic"
          },
          {
            "word": "INJUNCTION",
            "answer": "injunction"
          },
          {
            "word": "PATENTLY",
            "answer": "patently"
          },
          {
            "word": "SALUTARY",
            "answer": "salutary"
          },
          {
            "word": "ALACRITY",
            "answer": "alacrity"
          },
          {
            "word": "EGRESS",
            "answer": "egress"
          },
          {
            "word": "LACHRYMOSE",
            "answer": "lachrymose or lugubrious"
          },
          {
            "word": "PLAINTIVE",
            "answer": "plaintive or lugubrious"
          },
          {
            "word": "SANGFROID",
            "answer": "sangfroid"
          },
          {
            "word": "CRAVEN",
            "answer": "craven"
          },
          {
            "word": "ENNUI",
            "answer": "ennui"
          },
          {
            "word": "LUGUBRIOUS",
            "answer": "lugubrious"
          },
          {
            "word": "PUERILE",
            "answer": "puerile"
          },
          {
            "word": "SUCCOR",
            "answer": "succor"
          },
          {
            "word": "CURSORY",
            "answer": "cursory"
          },
          {
            "word": "IMPECUNIOUS",
            "answer": "impecunious"
          },
          {
            "word": "MENDICANT",
            "answer": "mendicant"
          },
          {
            "word": "REGALE",
            "answer": "regaled"
          },
          {
            "word": "UMBRAGE",
            "answer": "umbrage"
          },
          {
            "word": "DENIZEN",
            "answer": "denizen"
          },
          {
            "word": "INDISPOSED",
            "answer": "indisposed"
          },
          {
            "word": "ABSCOND",
            "answer": "absconded"
          },
          {
            "word": "CALUMNY",
            "answer": "calumny"
          },
          {
            "word": "DROLL",
            "answer": "droll"
          },
          {
            "word": "MITIGATE",
            "answer": "mitigate"
          },
          {
            "word": "RAREFIED",
            "answer": "rarefied"
          },
          {
            "word": "ACERBITY",
            "answer": "acerbity"
          },
          {
            "word": "COMPORT",
            "answer": "comported"
          },
          {
            "word": "EVINCE",
            "answer": "evinced"
          },
          {
            "word": "PERPETRATE",
            "answer": "perpetrated"
          },
          {
            "word": "TRACTABLE",
            "answer": "tractable"
          },
          {
            "word": "ACETOUS",
            "answer": "acetous"
          },
          {
            "word": "DESICCATE",
            "answer": "desiccated"
          },
          {
            "word": "INCIPIENT",
            "answer": "incipient"
          },
          {
            "word": "PITHY",
            "answer": "pithy"
          },
          {
            "word": "TRENCHANT",
            "answer": "trenchant"
          },
          {
            "word": "BUCOLIC",
            "answer": "bucolic"
          },
          {
            "word": "DETRITUS",
            "answer": "detritus"
          },
          {
            "word": "MALADROIT",
            "answer": "maladroit"
          },
          {
            "word": "PREVARICATE",
            "answer": "prevaricate"
          },
          {
            "word": "VAGARY",
            "answer": "vagaries"
          },
          {
            "word": "BUFFET",
            "answer": "buffet"
          },
          {
            "word": "DIADEM",
            "answer": "diadem"
          },
          {
            "word": "MALEDICTION",
            "answer": "malediction"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "The minister tried to give",
            "part2": "to the distressed families who had lost their homes.",
            "correct": "succor",
            "word": "SUCCOR"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim accepted the ticket with",
            "part2": "; he was dying to go to the game.",
            "correct": "alacrity",
            "word": "ALACRITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "movie had everyone in the audience in tears.",
            "correct": "lachrymose or lugubrious",
            "word": "LACHRYMOSE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Julie couldn't overcome her feeling of",
            "part2": "as the days went by and nothing changed.",
            "correct": "ennui",
            "word": "ENNUI"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mr. Jones would not",
            "part2": "to Ralph's request for a raise.",
            "correct": "accede",
            "word": "ACCEDE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We rushed outside when we heard the",
            "part2": "whimpering of the injured puppy.",
            "correct": "plaintive or lugubrious",
            "word": "PLAINTIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The unexpected defeat proved to be",
            "part2": "for the team, since it then worked harder and eventually won the championship.",
            "correct": "salutary",
            "word": "SALUTARY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "All this",
            "part2": "talk of death and unhappiness is beginning to bother me.",
            "correct": "lugubrious",
            "word": "LUGUBRIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It is",
            "part2": "absurd to expect to learn physics in two weeks.",
            "correct": "patently",
            "word": "PATENTLY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The pitiful",
            "part2": "came to our door, begging for food.",
            "correct": "mendicant",
            "word": "MENDICANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The stranger",
            "part2": "us late into the night with hilarious stories and songs.",
            "correct": "regaled",
            "word": "REGALE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "With amazing",
            "part2": "she calmly told her boss that she would do things her way and he would just have to accept it.",
            "correct": "sangfroid",
            "word": "SANGFROID"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He is so",
            "part2": "that he has no money for food, and has to keep borrowing from his friends.",
            "correct": "impecunious",
            "word": "IMPECUNIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Alice took",
            "part2": "whenever anyone suggested that she should lose weight.",
            "correct": "umbrage",
            "word": "UMBRAGE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The comedian's",
            "part2": "jokes wouldn't appeal to anyone over the age of twelve.",
            "correct": "puerile",
            "word": "PUERILE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The bully liked to pretend he was brave, but he was really",
            "part2": "and would run at the first hint of fighting.",
            "correct": "craven",
            "word": "CRAVEN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Although it was nothing serious, Mrs. Johnson felt",
            "part2": "and cancelled her appointment at the beauty parlor.",
            "correct": "indisposed",
            "word": "INDISPOSED"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Everyone obeyed the teacher's",
            "part2": "not to use any books or notes during the exam.",
            "correct": "injunction",
            "word": "INJUNCTION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The play was too",
            "part2": "to hold our interest; we came to be entertained, not instructed.",
            "correct": "didactic",
            "word": "DIDACTIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Every",
            "part2": "of the city had to be counted in the census.",
            "correct": "denizen",
            "word": "DENIZEN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Janet was upset by the doctor's",
            "part2": "examination of her injury; she felt he should have spent more time studying it.",
            "correct": "cursory",
            "word": "CURSORY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "",
            "part2": "from the theater was made difficult by the large number of people standing in front of the doors.",
            "correct": "egress",
            "word": "EGRESS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The peasants were terrified by the dire",
            "part2": "the evil sorcerer uttered against them.",
            "correct": "malediction",
            "word": "MALEDICTION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "of Mr. Johnson's temper make it impossible to predict what his mood will be.",
            "correct": "vagaries",
            "word": "VAGARY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The new chairman",
            "part2": "himself with quiet dignity during the meeting.",
            "correct": "comported",
            "word": "COMPORT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Peter longed for the",
            "part2": "life of the shepherd.",
            "correct": "bucolic",
            "word": "BUCOLIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The murderer",
            "part2": "his crime on a moonless night.",
            "correct": "perpetrated",
            "word": "PERPETRATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His",
            "part2": "essays cut to the heart of the issues.",
            "correct": "trenchant",
            "word": "TRENCHANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim was",
            "part2": "when speaking to people at parties; he always managed to insult someone unwittingly.",
            "correct": "maladroit",
            "word": "MALADROIT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Workers had to clear away all the",
            "part2": "at the mouth of the tunnel before they could reach the trapped miners.",
            "correct": "detritus",
            "word": "DETRITUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "storyteller kept us laughing at his tall tales.",
            "correct": "droll",
            "word": "DROLL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Tell the absolute truth. Don't",
            "part2": "or try to get out of answering anything.",
            "correct": "prevaricate",
            "word": "PREVARICATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The dry heat of the desert made us feel",
            "part2": ", as if all our bodily fluids had evaporated.",
            "correct": "desiccated",
            "word": "DESICCATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Raising the tax rate enabled the mayor to",
            "part2": "somewhat the city's fiscal difficulties.",
            "correct": "mitigate",
            "word": "MITIGATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We common people were astonished at the",
            "part2": "heights of their philosophical discussions.",
            "correct": "rarefied",
            "word": "RAREFIED"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He thought the first few snowflakes were a(n)",
            "part2": "blizzard, so he returned home as fast as he could.",
            "correct": "incipient",
            "word": "INCIPIENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "of the reporter's questions indicated the bitterness of his feeling toward the mayor.",
            "correct": "acerbity",
            "word": "ACERBITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "taste of the wine made people think they were drinking vinegar.",
            "correct": "acetous",
            "word": "ACETOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The mayor said it was",
            "part2": "to suggest he had taken a bribe.",
            "correct": "calumny",
            "word": "CALUMNY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Everyone thought the mild-mannered clerk was harmless until she",
            "part2": "with the company payroll.",
            "correct": "absconded",
            "word": "ABSCOND"
          },
          {
            "part1": "High winds and torrential rain are expected to",
            "part2": "the region all through the night.",
            "correct": "buffet",
            "word": "BUFFET"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The young woman wore her",
            "part2": "proudly when she was crowned queen.",
            "correct": "diadem",
            "word": "DIADEM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Her brief,",
            "part2": "remarks summed things up perfectly.",
            "correct": "pithy",
            "word": "PITHY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I wish the horse were more",
            "part2": "; it just won't obey any of my commands.",
            "correct": "tractable",
            "word": "TRACTABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The children",
            "part2": "their pleasure by shouting happily and jumping up and down.",
            "correct": "evinced",
            "word": "EVINCE"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "8.4",
          "definitions": {
            "CAVIL": {
              "word": "CAVIL",
              "phonetic": "(kav'-gl)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to quibble, carp \nTo CAVIL is to raise petty or trivial objections to something. It is usually used with <em>at</em>, <em>about</em>, or <em>with</em>. \n\"A small group delayed the passage of the treaty for some time by CAVILING about its language.\" \n\"I wish you wouldn't CAVIL at my grammar; you understand what I mean.\" \n\"Critics' reviews often skim over the whole performance to CAVIL with minor details.\" \nCAVIL is also a noun, meaning a <em>trivial objection</em>. \n\"Despite the CAVILS of petty critics, audiences seem to love the play.\""
            },
            "COGENT": {
              "word": "COGENT",
              "phonetic": "(kO'-jgnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "convincing, forceful, compelling \nCOGENT comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>force together</em>. See <em>co-</em> under Prefixes. COGENT is usually applied to arguments, reasons, or the like, and means <em>forceful</em>, <em>convincing</em>. \n\"Pete advanced several COGENT arguments about why he deserved a raise.\" \n\"The principal made some COGENT remarks about the need for greater discipline in the school.\" \n\"The mayor COGENTLY pointed out that taxes would have to be raised in order to pay for a new high school.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is <em>obvious</em>, probably due to a confusion of COGENT with <em>blatant</em>. \nOther forms of the word: COGENCY, n."
            },
            "FIRMAMENT": {
              "word": "FIRMAMENT",
              "phonetic": "(fer'-mg-mgnt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "the heavens, sky, celestial sphere \nThe word FIRMAMENT is difficult because the <em>firm</em> part of the word makes people think it means <em>earth</em>, an opposite of its correct meaning, <em>sky</em> or <em>heavens</em>. FIRMAMENT in fact is related to the word <em>firm</em>; it means <em>sky</em> because of the ancient belief that the outermost portion of the heavens was actually solid, an arch or vault into which the stars were fixed. FIRMAMENT in modern usage is a poetic or literary word. \n\"Every star in the FIRMAMENT seemed to blaze with an unnatural light.\" \n\"Kate gazed up at the FIRMAMENT and wondered if one day she would travel to the stars.\""
            },
            "HALCYON": {
              "word": "HALCYON",
              "phonetic": "(hal'-sE-gn)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "tranquil, calm, peaceful \nThe HALCYON was a mythical bird that nested on the sea at the time of the winter solstice, and was supposed to have the power to calm the wind and the waves during that time. As an adjective, HALCYON refers to this magical calmness and tranquility. \"HALCYON days\" are literally the days of fine weather around the winter solstice; in extended use the phrase is applied to any tranquil time. \n\"The man reflected that life was simpler and people were happier in the HALCYON days of his youth.\" \n\"Summer vacations were a HALCYON time when we spent endless days relaxing on the beach.\" \n\"The commencement speaker said that these HALCYON college days would stay in our memories all our lives.\""
            },
            "NONPLUSSED": {
              "word": "NONPLUSSED",
              "phonetic": "(non-pluhsd')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "perplexed, puzzled, baffled \nNONPLUSSED is also spelled NONPLUSED. \nThe verb to NONPLUS comes from the Latin words <em>non plus</em>, meaning \"no more.\" It suggests a state in which no more can be said or done because of profound puzzlement or perplexity. \n\"The mayor's decision not to seek reelection NONPLUSSED his supporters. They couldn't understand why he wanted to leave the job.\" \nThe word is usually seen in its adjective form, NONPLUSSED. \n\"I was NONPLUSSED at the man's insults. Why would he say such things?\" \n\"The NONPLUSSED audience stared in disbelief as the conductor threw down his baton and walked offstage.\" \nThe word is also occasionally used as a noun, in the expression <em>at</em> or <em>to a</em> NONPLUS. \n\"We were reduced to a NONPLUS when the lamp suddenly started moving across the room.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>certain</em>, an opposite of NONPLUSSED. \nOther forms of the word: NONPLUS, n., v."
            },
            "PREPOSSESSING": {
              "word": "PREPOSSESSING",
              "phonetic": "(prE-pÔøΩzes'-ing)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "attractive, pleasing \nTo be PREPOSSESSING is to create a favorable impression. The word often suggests an obvious attractiveness that has an immediate, pleasant effect. See <em>pre-</em> under Prefixes. \n\"The friendly, PREPOSSESSING young man always did well in job interviews.\" \n\"Her PREPOSSESSING appearance disposed people to think well of her as soon as they met her.\" \n\"The album's PREPOSSESSING cover certainly helped its sales.\" \n<em>Kindly</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer. It is probably chosen by people who know that PREPOSSESSING is a positive word, hut don't have a clear idea of its meaning. \nOther forms of the word: PREPOSSESS, v."
            },
            "RAPACIOUS": {
              "word": "RAPACIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(rÔøΩ-pA'-shÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "greedy, grasping, plundering \nRAPACIOUS and <em>rape</em> both come from a Latin word meaning to <em>seize</em>. RAPACIOUS means \"seizing or grasping like a bird of prey\" and usually suggests extreme greed. \n\"The RAPACIOUS pirates seized everything on the defenseless ship.\" \n\"The RAPACIOUS loanshark was unrelenting in the collection of his debts; he brought many people to financial ruin.\" \nThe noun form of RAPACIOUS is RAPACITY. \n\"The consumer advocate condemned the RAPACITY of businesses that cared only about making high profits without considering the cost to society.\" \nOther forms of the word: RAPACITY, n."
            },
            "REVILE": {
              "word": "REVILE",
              "phonetic": "(ri-vll')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to abuse, rail against, denounce, malign \nTo REVILE is to denounce or abuse, often at length. The <em>vile</em> part of the word is from the same Latin word as the English words <em>vile</em> and <em>vilify</em>. \n\"The prisoner REVILED his captors as evil, soulless persecutors.\" \n\"In his hook the author REVILES an economic system that can produce such human misery.\" \n\"You shouldn't REVILE us for criticizing you; you should praise us for having the courage to say what we think.\" \n<em>Hate</em> is by far the most commonly chosen wrong answer. This is an understandable confusion, since one will usually hate what one REVILES. But to REVILE something is to express one's hatred for it in abusive language."
            },
            "RISIBLE": {
              "word": "RISIBLE",
              "phonetic": "(riz'-ÔøΩ-bÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "funny, laughable, ludicrous \nRISIBLE comes from the Latin word meaning to <em>laugh</em>, also the source of <em>derision</em> and <em>ridiculous</em>. See <em>-able</em> under Suffixes. RISIBLE means \"able to excite laughter,\" <em>laughable</em>. \n\"The comedian's RISIBLE stories kept the audience laughing all night.\" \n\"The sight of all those clowns trying to fit into the little car was quite RISIBLE.\" \n\"The boy thought his insults were RISIBLE, hut no one else even smiled at them.\" \nOther forms of the word: RISIBILITY, n."
            },
            "SUPERCILIOUS": {
              "word": "SUPERCILIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(sU-pÔøΩr-sil'-E-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "haughty, disdainful, arrogant \nSUPERCILIOUS means \"having a haughty, superior manner.\" It comes from the Latin word for <em>eyebrow</em>; the image is of a person raising an eyebrow in disdain. \n\"Her SUPERCILIOUS attitude infuriates us; why does she think she is so much better than the rest of us?\" \n\"With a SUPERCILIOUS sneer he said the miners' lives were too unimportant for him to worry about.\" \n\"The SUPERCILIOUS boss does nothing but make cutting remarks about how stupid his workers are.\" \n<em>Ridiculous</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, probably because SUPERCILIOUS sounds like <em>super silly</em>."
            },
            "TORPOR": {
              "word": "TORPOR",
              "phonetic": "(tor'-p:r)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "sluggishness, lethargy, lassitude \nTORPOR is mental or physical inactivity, like that of an animal in hibernation. In a slightly extended sense, the word can also be used as a synonym of <em>apathy</em> or <em>lethargy</em>. \n\"The drug caused a strange TORPOR to fall over the crew; they didn't have enough energy to lift their oars.\" \n\"Nothing could rouse him from his TORPOR; he just wanted to lie in bed all day and sleep.\" \nTORPID is the adjective related to TORPOR. It means <em>lethargic</em>, <em>sluggish</em>. \n\"Used to the hectic big city life, he can't adjust to the TORPID pace of village life.\" \n<em>Heat</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, probably because hot weather can be a cause of TORPOR. \nOther forms of the word: TORPID, adj."
            },
            "TUMID": {
              "word": "TUMID",
              "phonetic": "(tU'-mid",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "swollen, distended, bloated \nTUMID is related to the word <em>tumor</em>; both come from a Latin word meaning to <em>swell</em>. TUMID means <em>swollen</em>, usually in an unhealthy way; it is usually used about parts of the body. \n\"His foot became TUMID because of the infection.\" \nIn an extended sense TUMID is often applied to language and means <em>overblown</em>, <em>bombastic</em>. \n\"The old-fashioned politician's TUMID style made his speeches very dull to listen to.\" \n<em>Diseased</em>, the most commonly chosen wrong answer, is probably selected by people who make the connection of TUMID with <em>tumor</em>, but aren't sure of the exact meaning of TUMID."
            },
            "UNCTUOUS": {
              "word": "UNCTUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(uh",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "oily, slippery, greasy \nUNCTUOUS comes from the Latin word for <em>ointment</em>; it is related to the word <em>unguent</em>, which is an ointment or salve. The basic meaning of UNCTUOUS is <em>oily</em> or <em>greasy</em>, like an ointment. It is most often used in an extended sense about people with an oily manner, particularly when they are hypocritically ingratiating. \n\"The woman was completely taken in by the salesman's UNCTUOUS flattery.\" \n\"The new minister's UNCTUOUS air of spirituality strikes many members of the congregation as completely phony.\" \n<em>Proud</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, perhaps due to confusion with the equally unpleasant word <em>pompous</em>."
            },
            "ABJURE": {
              "word": "ABJURE",
              "phonetic": "(ab-jur')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to renounce, recant, forswear, retract \nThe <em>jure</em> part of ABJURE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>swear</em>. This word is also the source of the word <em>jury</em>, which is a group of people sworn to give a verdict in a legal case. See <em>ab-</em> under Prefixes. To ABJURE something is to \"swear away\" from it, to renounce it solemnly or publicly. \n\"The knight solemnly ABJURED his oath of allegiance to the former king and swore to follow King Henry instead.\" \n\"The new members have to ABJURE violence as a means of changing society.\" \n\"In a public ceremony the convert to the religion ABJURED his former beliefs.\""
            },
            "CANARD": {
              "word": "CANARD",
              "phonetic": "(k:-nahrd'):",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a false story, groundless report \nCANARD is the French word for <em>duck</em>. It comes into English by way of a French phrase that means \"to half-sell a duck,\" to cheat or deceive someone; it has come to mean in English a <em>false story</em>, an <em>unfounded rumor</em>. \n\"Bob just told me there was an earthquake in California today, but I think it's a CANARD: it would have been on the news if it had actually happened.\" \n\"Joel keeps us endlessly entertained with his tales of adventure: they're probably all CANARDS, but it doesn't matter.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "to CAVIL",
                  "answers": [
                    "wonder",
                    "quibble",
                    "rejoice",
                    "mumble",
                    "sigh"
                  ],
                  "word": "CAVIL",
                  "correct": "quibble"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COGENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "fanciful",
                    "misleading",
                    "convincing",
                    "complex",
                    "obvious"
                  ],
                  "word": "COGENT",
                  "correct": "convincing"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FIRMAMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "earth",
                    "heavens",
                    "solar system",
                    "mountains",
                    "horizon"
                  ],
                  "word": "FIRMAMENT",
                  "correct": "heavens"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HALCYON",
                  "answers": [
                    "tranquil",
                    "frantic",
                    "remote",
                    "cloudy",
                    "holy"
                  ],
                  "word": "HALCYON",
                  "correct": "tranquil"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NONPLUSSED",
                  "answers": [
                    "certain",
                    "puzzled",
                    "excited",
                    "afraid",
                    "worried"
                  ],
                  "word": "NONPLUSSED",
                  "correct": "puzzled"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PREPOSSESSING",
                  "answers": [
                    "weird",
                    "rich",
                    "attractive",
                    "sloppy",
                    "kindly"
                  ],
                  "word": "PREPOSSESSING",
                  "correct": "attractive"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RAPACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "kindly",
                    "fierce",
                    "polite",
                    "greedy",
                    "impatient"
                  ],
                  "word": "RAPACIOUS",
                  "correct": "greedy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to REVILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "praise",
                    "annoy",
                    "disturb",
                    "abuse",
                    "hate"
                  ],
                  "word": "REVILE",
                  "correct": "abuse"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RISIBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "mournful",
                    "obvious",
                    "petty",
                    "uplifting",
                    "funny"
                  ],
                  "word": "RISIBLE",
                  "correct": "funny"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUPERCILIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "precise",
                    "outstanding",
                    "ridiculous",
                    "hostile",
                    "haughty"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUPERCILIOUS",
                  "correct": "haughty"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TORPOR",
                  "answers": [
                    "heat",
                    "sweetness",
                    "sluggishness",
                    "anger",
                    "fever"
                  ],
                  "word": "TORPOR",
                  "correct": "sluggishness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TUMID",
                  "answers": [
                    "swollen",
                    "shrunken",
                    "moist",
                    "heavy",
                    "diseased"
                  ],
                  "word": "TUMID",
                  "correct": "swollen"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UNCTUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "crusty",
                    "careful",
                    "gorgeous",
                    "oily",
                    "proud"
                  ],
                  "word": "UNCTUOUS",
                  "correct": "oily"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ABJURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "uphold",
                    "renounce",
                    "despair",
                    "resist",
                    "curse"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABJURE",
                  "correct": "renounce"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CANARD",
                  "answers": [
                    "adage",
                    "card trick",
                    "opinion",
                    "legend",
                    "false story"
                  ],
                  "word": "CANARD",
                  "correct": "false story"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an argumentative person likely to CAVIL?",
                  "word": "CAVIL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would people be persuaded by a COGENT argument?",
                  "word": "COGENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you walk on the FIRMAMENT?",
                  "word": "FIRMAMENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are HALCYON days unpleasant?",
                  "word": "HALCYON",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a confident person be likely to act NONPLUSSED?",
                  "word": "NONPLUSSED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a lackluster person likely to be PREPOSSESSING?",
                  "word": "PREPOSSESSING",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is RAPACITY a good trait to have?",
                  "word": "RAPACIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could one use curses in REVILING someone?",
                  "word": "REVILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are sordid events RISIBLE?",
                  "word": "RISIBLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a SUPERCILIOUS person be likely to think of others as childish?",
                  "word": "SUPERCILIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is TORPOR a characteristic of lazy people?",
                  "word": "TORPOR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is TUMID flesh pleasant to look at?",
                  "word": "TUMID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would nastiness be a characteristic of an UNCTUOUS person?",
                  "word": "UNCTUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you ABJURE a vow?",
                  "word": "ABJURE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should one be gullible when it comes to CANARDS?",
                  "word": "CANARD",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Their mother CAVILED them for not doing their homework.",
                  "word": "CAVIL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It is COGENT that we will have to do something about our old car pretty soon.",
                  "word": "COGENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The explosion seemed to make the FIRMAMENT glow from one end to the other.",
                  "word": "FIRMAMENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Those early years were fondly recalled as a HALCYON period in the organization's history.",
                  "word": "HALCYON",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jim is NONPLUSSED at hockey; he is by far the best player on the team.",
                  "word": "NONPLUSSED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "You didn't have to be so PREPOSSESSING, but we appreciated the thought.",
                  "word": "PREPOSSESSING",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Your arguments are RAPACIOUS; they make no sense at all.",
                  "word": "RAPACIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The speaker REVILED the people who are unwilling to get involved in community affairs.",
                  "word": "REVILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The playwright thought that this scene would be quite dramatic, but the audience found it RISIBLE.",
                  "word": "RISIBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Tom looked SUPERCILIOUS wearing that lampshade at the party.",
                  "word": "SUPERCILIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The young radicals decried the intellectual TORPOR of the university.",
                  "word": "TORPOR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was difficult to breathe the hot, TUMID air.",
                  "word": "TUMID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The butler's UNCTUOUS manner completely hid his true feelings and opinions.",
                  "word": "UNCTUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She ABJURED us to hurry, because time was running out.",
                  "word": "ABJURE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "No one believed the CANARD about the con man selling the Brooklyn Bridge to a rich tourist.",
                  "word": "CANARD",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "CAVIL",
                  "answers": [
                    "criticize",
                    "quibble",
                    "instruct"
                  ],
                  "word": "CAVIL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COGENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "weighty",
                    "childish",
                    "convincing"
                  ],
                  "word": "COGENT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FIRMAMENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "heavens",
                    "sky",
                    "planets"
                  ],
                  "word": "FIRMAMENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HALCYON",
                  "answers": [
                    "serene",
                    "placid",
                    "dull"
                  ],
                  "word": "HALCYON",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NONPLUSSED",
                  "answers": [
                    "conquered",
                    "bewildered",
                    "disconcerted"
                  ],
                  "word": "NONPLUSSED",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PREPOSSESSING",
                  "answers": [
                    "charming",
                    "beautiful",
                    "knowledgeable"
                  ],
                  "word": "PREPOSSESSING",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RAPACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "presumptuous",
                    "avaricious",
                    "voracious"
                  ],
                  "word": "RAPACIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REVILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "vilify",
                    "loathe",
                    "upbraid"
                  ],
                  "word": "REVILE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RISIBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "amusing",
                    "entertaining",
                    "edifying"
                  ],
                  "word": "RISIBLE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SUPERCILIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "prideful",
                    "contemptuous",
                    "envious"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUPERCILIOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TORPOR",
                  "answers": [
                    "loneliness",
                    "lethargy",
                    "listlessness"
                  ],
                  "word": "TORPOR",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TUMID",
                  "answers": [
                    "distended",
                    "rotten",
                    "overblown"
                  ],
                  "word": "TUMID",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UNCTUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "extravagant",
                    "doleful",
                    "cloying"
                  ],
                  "word": "UNCTUOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABJURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "despise",
                    "reject",
                    "eschew"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABJURE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CANARD",
                  "answers": [
                    "fabrication",
                    "falsehood",
                    "facade"
                  ],
                  "word": "CANARD",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "8.5",
          "definitions": {
            "CAPACIOUS": {
              "word": "CAPACIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(kg-pA'-shgs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "roomy, spacious \nCAPACIOUS comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>contain</em>; it is also the source of the English word <em>capacity</em>. CAPACIOUS means <em>roomy</em>, \"able to contain a lot.\" \n\"The flower-filled hall was so CAPACIOUS that I felt as if I were in a meadow.\" \n\"The CAPACIOUS pockets in the man's coat contained everything from candy to an old Boy Scout manual.\" \nCAPACIOUS can also be used in an extended sense. \n\"Her CAPACIOUS mind absorbs everything she reads and sees; where she stores all that information is a mystery.\" \nMany people wrongly choose <em>greedy</em> as the answer on the Pretest, perhaps confusing CAPACIOUS with <em>rapacious</em>. See <em>rapacious</em> in Chapter 4."
            },
            "DIAPHANOUS": {
              "word": "DIAPHANOUS",
              "phonetic": "(dl-af'-g-ngs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "translucent, transparent \nSomething that is DIAPHANOUS allows light to shine through it, usually because of its delicate, sheer texture. \n\"I could make out her beautiful features beneath the DIAPHANOUS veil.\" \n\"In the painting you could see the sunlight through the DIAPHANOUS wings of the angel.\" \nOften the word is used in a somewhat general sense, with the emphasis on the delicacy of form and texture. \n\"The movie made you feel as if you were in an ethereal, DIAPHANOUS fairyland, floating through gossamer clouds.\""
            },
            "PROSAIC": {
              "word": "PROSAIC",
              "phonetic": "(prO-zA'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "like prose; commonplace, matter-of-fact, ordinary, dull \n<em>Prose</em> is ordinary speech or writing, as distinguished from poetry. PROSAIC is the adjective from <em>prose</em>. See <em>-ic</em> under Suffixes. PROSAIC emphasizes the dull, commonplace character of prose, and can be used about anything that has this quality. \n\"The book is a very PROSAIC summary of his life, merely listing names and dates and places without trying to explain the man's greatness.\" \n\"Luciano Pavarotti left his PROSAIC job as an insurance salesman to become a famous opera singer.\" \nTwice as many people who take the Pretest think PROSAIC means <em>poetic</em> as think it means <em>commonplace</em>. These people are probably familiar with the phrase \"prose and poetry,\" but have not learned the distinction between the two."
            },
            "QUERULOUS": {
              "word": "QUERULOUS",
              "phonetic": "(kwer'-g-lgs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "complaining, irritable, peevish \nQUERULOUS comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>complain</em>. A QUERULOUS person is full of complaints, particularly petty ones. \n\"The head of the complaint department soon tired of dealing with QUERULOUS customers.\" \n\"He is so QUERULOUS, always finding fault with trivial shortcomings. He certainly isn't fun to be with.\" \nQUERULOUS is also used about one's tone and manner and means \"expressing complaints.\" \n\"Even when she was being polite her tone was QUERULOUS, as if she were irritated by something.\""
            },
            "RESTIVE": {
              "word": "RESTIVE",
              "phonetic": "(res'-tiv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "restless, unruly, uneasy, refractory \nThe original meaning of RESTIVE is \"resisting control,\" <em>balky</em>, and it is still used in this sense. More commonly, however, it is now used as a synonym of <em>restless</em>, especially when the restlessness is a result of an attempt to restrict or control. \n\"The horse became RESTIVE whenever anyone tried to put a bridle on it.\" \n\"The audience became RESTIVE as the intermission lengthened and the play did not resume.\" \n\"By three o'clock the children were so RESTIVE that the teacher could no longer keep them in their seats.\" \n<em>Quiet</em> is a very common answer on the Pretest. It is probably chosen by people who think RESTIVE has something to do with <em>resting</em>. The two words are not related, however, and <em>quiet</em> is virtually an opposite of RESTIVE."
            },
            "SYCOPHANCY": {
              "word": "SYCOPHANCY",
              "phonetic": "(sik'-;-fan-sE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "servility, toadying, base flattery \nA SYCOPHANT is a person who attempts to gain favor by lavishing flattery and attention on a person who has wealth or power. \n\"Wherever he went the king was surrounded by SYCOPHANTS who catered to his every whim in the hope that he would reward them.\" \nSYCOPHANCY is the quality or practice of a SYCOPHANT. \n\"Bill's SYCOPHANCY toward the coach won't get him anywhere. It's what he does during the game that counts.\" \n\"The SYCOPHANCY of the courtiers disgusted the knight, and he soon left the court to serve another nobleman.\" \nOther forms of the word: SYCOPHANT, n. SYCOPHANTIC, adj."
            },
            "VIRULENT": {
              "word": "VIRULENT",
              "phonetic": "(vEr'-y;-l;nt",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "poisonous, venomous \nVIRULENT comes from the Latin word <em>virus</em>, the source also of the English word <em>virus</em>. See <em>-ent</em> under Suffixes. In English today VIRULENT refers to the destructive and malignant qualities of a disease or poison. \n\"This VIRULENT form of the flu caused thousands of deaths last winter.\" \nIn its extended use, VIRULENT refers to anything that is particularly bitter, hostile, or hateful. \n\"The mudslinging between the opponents became increasingly VIRULENT: terrible things were said on both sides.\" \n\"Mr. Jones has a VIRULENT hatred of cats; he has been known to poison them.\" \n<em>Persistent</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer. It is perhaps chosen by people who know that VIRULENT diseases are serious and long-term. The meaning of VIRULENT, however, is <em>poisonous</em>. \nOther forms of the word: VIRULENCE, n."
            },
            "CONFITURE": {
              "word": "CONFITURE",
              "phonetic": "(kon'-fi-chur)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a jam, preserve, confection \nA CONFITURE is preserved fruit; it is a rather literary synonym for <em>jam</em>. \n\"Pierre always had a dish of raspberry CONFITURE with his croissant.\" \n\"Martha spends hours in the kitchen every fall, canning vegetables and preparing CONFITURES.\""
            },
            "DEMUR": {
              "word": "DEMUR",
              "phonetic": "(de-mer')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to object, take exception \nTo DEMUR to something is to object to it, to be reluctant to agree to it. It is usually used with <em>to</em> or <em>at</em>. \n\"Bill wanted to DEMUR to the proposition, but everybody else seemed to agree with it.\" \n\"Many of the councilmen DEMURRED at the suggestion that gambling casinos be built in their town.\" \n\"Sarah wanted to have lunch at Rick's, but Joe DEMURRED, remembering how bad the food had been there.\" \n<em>Retreat</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, perhaps because of a vague association with the unrelated adjective <em>demure</em>. \nOther forms of the word: DEMURRAL, n."
            },
            "EQUANIMITY": {
              "word": "EQUANIMITY",
              "phonetic": "(E-kw;-nim'-;-tE",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "composure, calmness, sangfroid \nEQUANIMITY comes from a Latin word meaning <em>even-tempered</em>. The <em>equ</em> root, meaning <em>equal</em> or <em>even</em>, is also found in words like <em>equation</em> and <em>equality</em>. EQUANAMITY is the characteristic of being even-tempered, of possessing mental and emotional balance. Someone with EQUANIMITY is not easily upset or excited. \n\"Even the children's fighting could not disturb Harold's EQUANIMITY. He merely inquired what the matter was.\" \n\"The pressures of her job caused Susan to lose her usual EQUANIMITY.\" \n\"The teacher doesn't possess enough EQUANIMITY to face the rowdy students day after day without losing her temper.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>fairness</em>, perhaps because the <em>equ</em> root suggests the words <em>equality</em> or <em>equitability</em>."
            },
            "MENDACIOUS": {
              "word": "MENDACIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(men-dA'-sh:)s)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "lying, untruthful, dishonest \nMENDACIOUS means lying. It is used particularly about people who are habitually untruthful. \n\"The MENDACIOUS boy told everyone a different story about how the house had caught fire.\" \nIt is also used about what such a person says. \n\"The politician called the newspaper report completely MENDACIOUS. He said he had never taken a bribe in his life.\" \nThe noun form of MENDACIOUS is MENDACITY, which means \"habitual lying.\" \n\"Her reputation for MENDACITY makes it difficult for me to believe her accusations.\" \nOther forms of the word: MENDACITY, n."
            },
            "PENURIOUS": {
              "word": "PENURIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(p:)-nUr'-E-:)s",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "needy, poor; stingy, miserly \nPENURIOUS means needy, very poor. Someone who is PENURIOUS is oppressed by a lack of money. \n\"The man is so PENURIOUS that he has to sleep outside in a box.\" \n\"The PENURIOUS conditions of life among migrant workers often mean one meal a day and ragged clothes.\" \nPENURIOUS can also mean <em>stingy</em>. The implication is that someone is so miserly that he or she appears poor. \n\"The lady is so PENURIOUS that even though she has a small fortune, she wears the same old coat winter and summer and eats out of garbage cans.\" \nOther forms of the word: PENURY, n."
            },
            "SEDITIOUS": {
              "word": "SEDITIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(si-dish'-:)s)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "rebellious, insubordinate, mutinous \nSEDITION is conduct that incites rebellion against the government. The difference between SEDITION and <em>treason</em> is that treason is the actual act of trying to overthrow the government or aiding the enemy; a speech or book that promotes this kind of act would be an example of SEDITION. SEDITIOUS is the adjective from SEDITION; see <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. \n\"The government accused him of SEDITION because of his fiery speeches attacking its leaders.\" \n\"Her SEDITIOUS pamphlets were secretly circulated among the opponents of the government.\" \n\"The dictator decreed that any newspaper article critical of him would be considered SEDITIOUS.\" \nOther forms of the word: SEDITION, n."
            },
            "EFFACE": {
              "word": "EFFACE",
              "phonetic": "(i-fAs')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to wipe out, obliterate, erase \nTo EFFACE something is to remove all visible evidence of its existence. \n\"Over the centuries the weather gradually EFFACED the inscription on the tomb.\" \nThe word is often used figuratively. \n\"Bob's new wife completely redecorated his house in an effort to EFFACE the memory of his unfortunate first marriage.\" \nTo EFFACE oneself is to act inconspicuously, to avoid drawing attention to oneself. This meaning of the word is also found in the adjective SELF-EFFACING. \n\"In public the prince always EFFACED himself so that attention would be centered on the queen.\" \nOther forms of the word: EFFACEMENT, n."
            },
            "INIMICAL": {
              "word": "INIMICAL",
              "phonetic": "in-im'-i-k:)I)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "hostile, antagonistic; harmful, adverse \nINIMICAL is related to the word <em>enemy</em>. Its basic meaning in English is <em>unfriendly</em>, <em>hostile</em>. \n\"The man's INIMICAL stare told us he certainly wasn't going to do us any favors.\" \nUsually, however, INIMICAL is used about things or activities and means \"harmful in its effects.\" In this sense INIMICAL is usually followed by <em>to</em>. \n\"Eating huge amounts of candy is INIMICAL to good health.\" \n\"The president claims that raising taxes is INIMICAL to the interests of the average citizen.\" \n<em>Fake</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, perhaps because people make a vague connection with <em>inimitable</em>, which means \"not able to be imitated.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "CAPACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "cramped",
                    "nearby",
                    "impressive",
                    "greedy",
                    "roomy"
                  ],
                  "word": "CAPACIOUS",
                  "correct": "roomy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DIAPHANOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "thin",
                    "clouded",
                    "translucent",
                    "two-sided",
                    "short-lived"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIAPHANOUS",
                  "correct": "translucent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROSAIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "commonplace",
                    "thoughtful",
                    "old-fashioned",
                    "purposeful",
                    "poetic"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROSAIC",
                  "correct": "commonplace"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "QUERULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "grateful",
                    "complaining",
                    "puzzling",
                    "trusting",
                    "unfriendly"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUERULOUS",
                  "correct": "complaining"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RESTIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "alert",
                    "quiet",
                    "swift",
                    "restless",
                    "stupid"
                  ],
                  "word": "RESTIVE",
                  "correct": "restless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SYCOPHANCY",
                  "answers": [
                    "vanity",
                    "servility",
                    "brutality",
                    "lunacy",
                    "slyness"
                  ],
                  "word": "SYCOPHANCY",
                  "correct": "servility"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VIRULENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "sly",
                    "forgiving",
                    "persistent",
                    "poisonous",
                    "crazy"
                  ],
                  "word": "VIRULENT",
                  "correct": "poisonous"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONFITURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "jam",
                    "bacon",
                    "blanket",
                    "chocolate",
                    "cake"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONFITURE",
                  "correct": "jam"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DEMUR",
                  "answers": [
                    "insist",
                    "wonder",
                    "object",
                    "retreat",
                    "cry"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEMUR",
                  "correct": "object"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EQUANIMITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "fairness",
                    "excitability",
                    "joy",
                    "secrecy",
                    "composure"
                  ],
                  "word": "EQUANIMITY",
                  "correct": "composure"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MENDACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "crude",
                    "tricky",
                    "lying",
                    "bold",
                    "graceful"
                  ],
                  "word": "MENDACIOUS",
                  "correct": "lying"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PENURIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "needy",
                    "sorrowful",
                    "boring",
                    "sickly",
                    "generous"
                  ],
                  "word": "PENURIOUS",
                  "correct": "needy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SEDITIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "criminal",
                    "rebellious",
                    "brutal",
                    "questionable",
                    "helpful"
                  ],
                  "word": "SEDITIOUS",
                  "correct": "rebellious"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to EFFACE",
                  "answers": [
                    "illuminate",
                    "harm",
                    "promote",
                    "wipe out",
                    "cleanse"
                  ],
                  "word": "EFFACE",
                  "correct": "wipe out"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INIMICAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "perfect",
                    "fake",
                    "hostile",
                    "impossible",
                    "advantageous"
                  ],
                  "word": "INIMICAL",
                  "correct": "hostile"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Are most professional sports stadiums CAPACIOUS?",
                  "word": "CAPACIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a gown be DIAPHANOUS?",
                  "word": "DIAPHANOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would most people consider being an astronaut a PROSAIC occupation?",
                  "word": "PROSAIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a QUERULOUS person likely to be considered easy-going?",
                  "word": "QUERULOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is laziness a characteristic of a RESTIVE person?",
                  "word": "RESTIVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are SYCOPHANTS aggressive?",
                  "word": "SYCOPHANCY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is something that is VIRULENT fun to have?",
                  "word": "VIRULENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a CONFITURE generally contain sugar?",
                  "word": "CONFITURE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an argumentative person be likely to DEMUR frequently?",
                  "word": "DEMUR",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do unruly people possess EQUANIMITY?",
                  "word": "EQUANIMITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a MENDACIOUS person tell lies?",
                  "word": "MENDACIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a beggar be PENURIOUS?",
                  "word": "PENURIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could antigovernment speeches that urge the people to riot be considered SEDITIOUS?",
                  "word": "SEDITIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a belligerent man be likely to EFFACE himself?",
                  "word": "EFFACE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a pastoral setting INIMICAL to tranquility?",
                  "word": "INIMICAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Their demands are CAPACIOUS; we will never agree to them.",
                  "word": "CAPACIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A thick layer of soot had made the window practically DIAPHANOUS.",
                  "word": "DIAPHANOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Keats's \"Ode on a Grecian Urn\" is one of the most PROSAIC lyrics in the language.",
                  "word": "PROSAIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The couple's QUERULOUS remarks about the food and the service infuriated the waiter.",
                  "word": "QUERULOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The RESTIVE medicine is supposed to help him sleep.",
                  "word": "RESTIVE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The SYCOPHANT told the Duke he was the wisest nobleman in the land.",
                  "word": "SYCOPHANCY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The author was upset by the VIRULENT criticism of his novel.",
                  "word": "VIRULENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They had roast duck for a main course and specially prepared CONFITURES for dessert.",
                  "word": "CONFITURE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They DEMURRED us for wanting to do things our own way.",
                  "word": "DEMUR",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her habitual EQUANIMITY was shattered by the news of her husband's death.",
                  "word": "EQUANIMITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jim's MENDACITY belied his pleasing appearance.",
                  "word": "MENDACIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The PENURIOUS man served his guests nothing but thin soup and stale bread.",
                  "word": "PENURIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They were sentenced to ten years in prison for their SEDITIOUS utterances.",
                  "word": "SEDITIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The threat of a common enemy forced the inhabitants of the valley to EFFACE their internal differences.",
                  "word": "EFFACE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We may never again see the equal of this INIMICAL young pianist.",
                  "word": "INIMICAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "CAPACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "stupendous",
                    "spacious",
                    "commodious"
                  ],
                  "word": "CAPACIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DIAPHANOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "transparent",
                    "bright",
                    "delicate"
                  ],
                  "word": "DIAPHANOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROSAIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "boring",
                    "ordinary",
                    "dreadful"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROSAIC",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "QUERULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "petulant",
                    "bestial",
                    "irascible"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUERULOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RESTIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "happy",
                    "uneasy",
                    "frisky"
                  ],
                  "word": "RESTIVE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SYCOPHANCY",
                  "answers": [
                    "courtesy",
                    "servility",
                    "fawning"
                  ],
                  "word": "SYCOPHANCY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VIRULENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "noxious",
                    "lethal",
                    "ardent"
                  ],
                  "word": "VIRULENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONFITURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "confection",
                    "casserole",
                    "preserve"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONFITURE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DEMUR",
                  "answers": [
                    "defile",
                    "object",
                    "dispute"
                  ],
                  "word": "DEMUR",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EQUANIMITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "nonchalance",
                    "quality",
                    "composure"
                  ],
                  "word": "EQUANIMITY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MENDACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "untruthful",
                    "argumentative",
                    "misleading"
                  ],
                  "word": "MENDACIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PENURIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "parsimonious",
                    "superficial",
                    "miserly"
                  ],
                  "word": "PENURIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SEDITIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "libelous",
                    "treasonous",
                    "rebellious"
                  ],
                  "word": "SEDITIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EFFACE",
                  "answers": [
                    "obliterate",
                    "expunge",
                    "disturb"
                  ],
                  "word": "EFFACE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INIMICAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "antagonistic",
                    "pernicious",
                    "banal"
                  ],
                  "word": "INIMICAL",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "8.6",
          "definitions": {
            "NASCENT": {
              "word": "NASCENT",
              "phonetic": "(nas'-::mt",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "beginning to exist, incipient \nNASCENT comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>be born</em>, and is related to such words as <em>natal</em> and <em>native</em>. Something that is NASCENT is just beginning to be born, is coming into existence. \n\"Jane's parents try to encourage her NASCENT interest in classical music.\" \n\"The NASCENT solar energy industry was greatly aided by the oil shortage.\" \n\"The country's NASCENT war fever died down after the destruction of its fleet.\" \n<em>Changing</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest. Something that is NASCENT is changing, but in a particular way: it is beginning to exist. \nOther forms of the word: NASCENCE, n. NASCENCY, n."
            },
            "PHLEGMATIC": {
              "word": "PHLEGMATIC",
              "phonetic": "(fleg-mat'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "unemotional, impassive, undemonstrative \nPHLEGMATIC is the adjective from PHLEGM (flem), which today means specifically <em>mucus</em>, but in medieval theory was considered one of the four \"humors\" or fluids of the body that were supposed to determine a person's disposition. PHLEGM was thought to cause sluggishness and lack of emotion. PHLEGMATIC therefore means \"difficult to arouse,\" <em>impassive</em>, <em>sluggish</em>. \n\"Bob's aloofness makes him seem PHLEGMATIC but really he is only shy.\" \n\"The lofty spires of the cathedral thrilled Peggy, but left her more PHLEGMATIC husband totally unmoved.\" \n\"The speaker hoped to arouse his audience's passions, and was disappointed by its PHLEGMATIC response.\" \n<em>Sickly</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, probably because people are misled by the PHLEGM part of PHLEGMATIC. \nOther forms of the word: PHLEGM, n."
            },
            "PRECIPITOUS": {
              "word": "PRECIPITOUS",
              "phonetic": "(pri-sip'-ÔøΩ-tÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "extremely steep \nPRECIPITOUS is the adjective from PRECIPICE, a cliff with a vertical face. It means <em>steep</em>, nearly vertical. \n\"The mountain presented a PRECIPITOUS wall of rock on its eastern face.\" \n\"We realized that we had come to the edge of the cliff and had nearly had a PRECIPITOUS fall.\" \n<em>Dangerous</em> and <em>threatening</em> are two very common wrong answers. Something that is PRECIPITOUS is probably both dangerous and threatening, but PRECIPITOUS means only <em>steep</em>. \nOther forms of the word: PRECIPICE, n."
            },
            "BADINAGE": {
              "word": "BADINAGE",
              "phonetic": "(bad-ÔøΩ-nah",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "banter, light repartee \nBADINAGE is lighthearted, playful banter, playful kidding. \n\"Their BADINAGE was very entertaining: witty puns and playful insults bounced back and forth like tennis balls.\" \n\"Even if they don't look alike, the BADINAGE in their conversation marks them as brother and sister: only siblings are so affectionately disrespectful.\""
            },
            "COLLOQUY": {
              "word": "COLLOQUY",
              "phonetic": "(kol'-ÔøΩ-kwE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a conference, formal conversation \nCOLLOQUY comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>speak together</em>. See <em>col-</em> under Prefixes. The <em>loqu</em> root is also found in such words as <em>colloquial</em> and <em>loquacity</em>. A COLLOQUY is a conversation or a dialogue, especially one that is serious or at a high level. \n\"The COLLOQUY between the heads of state went on for several hours.\" \n\"The labor-management COLLOQUY was amicable, but failed to resolve their differences.\" \n<em>Expression</em> and <em>lecture <em>are both commonly chosen wrong answers. Both deal with speaking, but neither involve speaking <em>together</em>."
            },
            "HEGEMONY": {
              "word": "HEGEMONY",
              "phonetic": "(hi-jem'-3-nE",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "dominance, predominance, leadership \nHEGEMONY is dominance or preponderant influence. The word is used especially about the dominance of one country over others in a particular area. \n\"China sought to establish its HEGEMONY in Southeast Asia.\" \n\"Athens and Sparta vied for HEGEMONY in ancient Greece.\" \n\"The tribe's HEGEMONY in the area crumbled with the arrival of the European colonists.\""
            },
            "OSTENSIBLE": {
              "word": "OSTENSIBLE",
              "phonetic": "(o-sten'-s3-b31)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "pretended, seeming, apparent \nOSTENSIBLE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>show</em>; it is related to the word <em>ostentation</em>, which is boastful showiness. OSTENSIBLE originally meant \"open to view; able to be seen,\" but in modern use it suggests that what is apparent on the surface is not true underneath, that there is a hidden purpose or character to something. \n\"Ralph's OSTENSIBLE business was television repair, but he was really a smuggler.\" \n\"The OSTENSIBLE purpose of her visit was to welcome them to the neighborhood, but she really just wanted to see how rich they were.\" \n\"He is OSTENSIBLY an accountant, but in fact he is a daring secret agent.\" \n<em>Reasonable</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, perhaps because it sounds somewhat like OSTENSIBLE, perhaps because something that is OSTENSIBLE appears reasonable, even if it is not true."
            },
            "PERIPATETIC": {
              "word": "PERIPATETIC",
              "phonetic": "(per-3-p3-tet'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "walking about, itinerant \nThe Greek philosopher Aristotle taught his followers while walking about the Lyceum, a school of ancient Athens. These followers came to be called PERIPATETICS, after a Greek word meaning \"to walk around,\" and the word was also applied to Aristotle's philosophy. The word then came to be used about anyone who wanders about, especially in connection with his or her calling. \n\"The PERIPATETIC actors wandered through the countryside, performing in every town they entered.\" \nThe word can also be used about something that is carried on while one moves about. \n\"The two travelers had a PERIPATETIC debate about the merits of walking versus riding a bicycle.\""
            },
            "PROFLIGATE": {
              "word": "PROFLIGATE",
              "phonetic": "(prof'-li-git)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "extravagant, wasteful; dissolute, immoral, abandoned \nSomeone who is PROFLIGATE is shamelessly immoral, totally given over to dissipation. \n\"The PROFLIGATE young noblemen wasted their lives gambling and drinking.\" \nVery often the word refers only to a person's spending and wastefulness, and means \"recklessly extravagant.\" \n\"The heiress was so PROFLIGATE that she soon spent her inheritance.\" \n\"The mayor's PROFLIGATE spending ultimately meant that taxes had to be increased.\" \nPROFLIGATE is also a noun, meaning \"an extravagant or immoral person.\" \n\"These young PROFLIGATES will never come to anything unless they mend their ways.\" \nOther forms of the word: PROFLIGACY, n."
            },
            "PUTATIVE": {
              "word": "PUTATIVE",
              "phonetic": "(pyU'-t3-tiv)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "supposed, reputed \nPUTATIVE comes from a Latin word meaning \"to consider,\" the source also of the English words <em>dispute</em>, <em>impute</em>, <em>repute</em>, and <em>compute</em>. PUTATIVE refers to something that is commonly believed but is not proven, so that the speaker has some doubts about its truth: something that is <em>supposed</em> to be true, but not assured to be. \n\"This secretary has good references, but her PUTATIVE skills are nonexistent: she can't type or do shorthand.\" \n\"Many people were executed even though their PUTATIVE treasons had been only half-baked dreams of revolution.\" \n\"Shakespeare is the PUTATIVE author of the play, but the evidence in his favor is somewhat contradictory.\""
            },
            "RAILLERY": {
              "word": "RAILLERY",
              "phonetic": "(rA'-lgr-E)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "banter, good-natured teasing \nRAILLERY is related to the verb to <em>rail</em>, which means to <em>speak bitterly</em>, to <em>abuse verbally</em>. RAILLERY is softer; it is good-natured teasing, pleasant banter with a touch of sarcasm. \n\"The throwing of the bride's bouquet was accompanied by some RAILLERY about old maids.\" \n\"The RAILLERY of his buddies on his sixtieth birthday bothered the man not at all.\" \n\"The two young men got into a fight when what had started as good-natured RAILLERY took on a sharper edge.\""
            },
            "DISSEMBLE": {
              "word": "DISSEMBLE",
              "phonetic": "(di-sem'-bgl)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to disguise, pretend, feign \nTo DISSEMBLE is to conceal one's true identity or purpose, usually in order to deceive someone. \n\"When asked why he was in the off-limits area, the spy was forced to DISSEMBLE and said that he had gotten lost.\" \nWhen used as a transitive verb, DISSEMBLE means \"to cloak the true appearance of,\" to <em>disguise</em>. \n\"She DISSEMBLED her anxiety by laughing gaily and trying to appear unconcerned.\" \n\"It was impossible to DISSEMBLE his exultation at the defeat of his enemy.\" \n<em>Destroy</em> is a commonly chosen wrong answer, possibly because of confusion with the word <em>disassemble</em>."
            },
            "EXPATIATE": {
              "word": "EXPATIATE",
              "phonetic": "(ek-spA'-shE-At)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to elaborate, dilate, discourse \nEXPATIATE is related to the words <em>space</em> and <em>spatial</em>. To EXPATIATE was originally used about physical movement and meant \"to move about freely.\" The word is now used only in a figurative sense about wide-ranging and lengthy speech. \n\"The orator EXPATIATED on the virtues of ancient Athens.\" \n\"The teacher EXPATIATED upon the difference between participles and gerunds.\" \n\"Realizing he had an hour to fill, the speaker had to EXPATIATE at great length upon the topic.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXPATIATION, n."
            },
            "MACERATE": {
              "word": "MACERATE",
              "phonetic": "(mas'-g-rAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to soften, to emaciate \nTo MACERATE something is to soften it or to separate it into its parts by steeping it in a liquid. \n\"The process involves MACERATING the tree bark in water for several hours.\" \n\"The tough grass MACERATED in the cow's stomach.\" \nThe word is also occasionally used about the wasting away of a person's flesh due to fasting, worry, or illness. \n\"His long suffering has MACERATED his flesh, and now he is nothing but skin and bones.\""
            },
            "MAELSTROM": {
              "word": "MAELSTROM",
              "phonetic": "(mAl'-strgm)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a whirlpool \nMAELSTROM was originally the name of a very powerful whirlpool off the coast of Norway; now it is applied to any especially violent or dangerous whirlpool. \n\"The ship's captain awoke from a nightmare in which his ship was being relentlessly sucked into a MAELSTROM.\" \nIn an extended sense, MAELSTROM is used about any turbulent situation that is like a whirlpool, drawing people into it. \n\"Even the peaceful Quakers were caught up in the MAELSTROM of the war, as marauding soldiers burned their barns and pillaged their farms.\" \n\"The exciting final inning of the game drew even the quietest spectators into the MAELSTROM of excitement.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "NASCENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "dying",
                    "normal",
                    "changing",
                    "flowing",
                    "incipient"
                  ],
                  "word": "NASCENT",
                  "correct": "incipient"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PHLEGMATIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "unemotional",
                    "excitable",
                    "practical",
                    "serene",
                    "sickly"
                  ],
                  "word": "PHLEGMATIC",
                  "correct": "unemotional"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRECIPITOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "narrow",
                    "steep",
                    "dangerous",
                    "level",
                    "threatening"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRECIPITOUS",
                  "correct": "steep"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BADINAGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "debris",
                    "injury",
                    "banter",
                    "confusion",
                    "debate"
                  ],
                  "word": "BADINAGE",
                  "correct": "banter"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COLLOQUY",
                  "answers": [
                    "expression",
                    "memory",
                    "collection",
                    "conference",
                    "lecture"
                  ],
                  "word": "COLLOQUY",
                  "correct": "conference"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HEGEMONY",
                  "answers": [
                    "slavery",
                    "ritual",
                    "dominance",
                    "property",
                    "expansion"
                  ],
                  "word": "HEGEMONY",
                  "correct": "dominance"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OSTENSIBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "important",
                    "reasonable",
                    "pretended",
                    "incorrect",
                    "possible"
                  ],
                  "word": "OSTENSIBLE",
                  "correct": "pretended"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERIPATETIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "itinerant",
                    "constant",
                    "pitiful",
                    "academic",
                    "curious"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERIPATETIC",
                  "correct": "itinerant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROFLIGATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "illegal",
                    "extravagant",
                    "religious",
                    "rude",
                    "generous"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROFLIGATE",
                  "correct": "extravagant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PUTATIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "unexpected",
                    "former",
                    "uncertain",
                    "supposed",
                    "possible"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUTATIVE",
                  "correct": "supposed"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RAILLERY",
                  "answers": [
                    "fantasy",
                    "anger",
                    "comedy",
                    "complaining",
                    "banter"
                  ],
                  "word": "RAILLERY",
                  "correct": "banter"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DISSEMBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "confuse",
                    "enlighten",
                    "disguise",
                    "destroy",
                    "embezzle"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISSEMBLE",
                  "correct": "disguise"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to EXPATIATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "refuse",
                    "elaborate",
                    "insist",
                    "curse",
                    "fantasize"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXPATIATE",
                  "correct": "elaborate"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to MACERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "soften",
                    "toughen",
                    "torment",
                    "destroy",
                    "stretch"
                  ],
                  "word": "MACERATE",
                  "correct": "soften"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MAELSTROM",
                  "answers": [
                    "icy wind",
                    "tornado",
                    "flood",
                    "iceberg",
                    "whirlpool"
                  ],
                  "word": "MAELSTROM",
                  "correct": "whirlpool"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a NASCENT actor have a lot of experience?",
                  "word": "NASCENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a PHLEGMATIC person be demonstrative?",
                  "word": "PHLEGMATIC",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a hillock PRECIPITOUS?",
                  "word": "PRECIPITOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is BADINAGE harmful?",
                  "word": "BADINAGE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a monologue a COLLOQUY?",
                  "word": "COLLOQUY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Did Napoleon seek French HEGEMONY in Europe?",
                  "word": "HEGEMONY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would having OSTENSIBLE purposes appeal to a secret agent?",
                  "word": "OSTENSIBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a traveling salesman be called PERIPATETIC?",
                  "word": "PERIPATETIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a PROFLIGATE person become penniless?",
                  "word": "PROFLIGATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a PUTATIVE solution be incorrect?",
                  "word": "PUTATIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can RAILLERY be fun?",
                  "word": "RAILLERY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do people who lie DISSEMBLE?",
                  "word": "DISSEMBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is brevity a characteristic of people who like to EXPATIATE?",
                  "word": "EXPATIATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can food MACERATE?",
                  "word": "MACERATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a ship in a MAELSTROM be in danger?",
                  "word": "MAELSTROM",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Her NASCENT interest in bullfighting finally led to a trip to Spain.",
                  "word": "NASCENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Even the most exciting game doesn't seem to arouse the PHLEGMATIC coach.",
                  "word": "PHLEGMATIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We refused to climb the PRECIPITOUS slope of the mountain.",
                  "word": "PRECIPITOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The BADINAGE between the old classmates at the high school was fast and furious.",
                  "word": "BADINAGE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Neither side had much to say to the other, so the COLLOQUY had to be considered a failure.",
                  "word": "COLLOQUY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Few Americans would like to see Communist HEGEMONY in Western Europe.",
                  "word": "HEGEMONY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It is perfectly OSTENSIBLE of you not to want to come with us.",
                  "word": "OSTENSIBLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "They held their PERIPATETIC debate during their long walks in the woods.",
                  "word": "PERIPATETIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The nation's PROFLIGATE use of its oil supplies caused a severe shortage.",
                  "word": "PROFLIGATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The PUTATIVE scientific breakthrough turned out to be nothing more than a hoax.",
                  "word": "PUTATIVE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Mary doesn't mind her brother's RAILLERY because she knows he loves her.",
                  "word": "RAILLERY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The interviewer was used to people DISSEMBLING, and quickly spotted the man as a phony.",
                  "word": "DISSEMBLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Mrs. Porter EXPATIATED us to try her brownies.",
                  "word": "EXPATIATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The sharp blade of the sword MACERATED his arm.",
                  "word": "MACERATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Everyone became involved in the MAELSTROM of controversy surrounding the building of the new power plant.",
                  "word": "MAELSTROM",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "NASCENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "beginning",
                    "growing",
                    "dying"
                  ],
                  "word": "NASCENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PHLEGMATIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "lethargic",
                    "dull",
                    "upset"
                  ],
                  "word": "PHLEGMATIC",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRECIPITOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "sheer",
                    "perpendicular",
                    "wet"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRECIPITOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BADINAGE",
                  "answers": [
                    "ridicule",
                    "sarcasm",
                    "hate"
                  ],
                  "word": "BADINAGE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COLLOQUY",
                  "answers": [
                    "discussion",
                    "speech",
                    "symposium"
                  ],
                  "word": "COLLOQUY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HEGEMONY",
                  "answers": [
                    "power",
                    "leadership",
                    "wisdom"
                  ],
                  "word": "HEGEMONY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OSTENSIBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "illusory",
                    "reproducible",
                    "specious"
                  ],
                  "word": "OSTENSIBLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERIPATETIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "walking",
                    "wandering",
                    "wondering"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERIPATETIC",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROFLIGATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "wanton",
                    "degenerate",
                    "farcical"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROFLIGATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PUTATIVE",
                  "answers": [
                    "hypothetical",
                    "dubious",
                    "actual"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUTATIVE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RAILLERY",
                  "answers": [
                    "slander",
                    "mockery",
                    "teasing"
                  ],
                  "word": "RAILLERY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DISSEMBLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "revile",
                    "lie",
                    "feign"
                  ],
                  "word": "DISSEMBLE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXPATIATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "expound",
                    "expunge",
                    "explain"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXPATIATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MACERATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "wear away",
                    "emaciate",
                    "cut"
                  ],
                  "word": "MACERATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MAELSTROM",
                  "answers": [
                    "turbulence",
                    "cloudiness",
                    "whirlpool"
                  ],
                  "word": "MAELSTROM",
                  "correct": 1
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ABJURE",
            "answer": "abjure"
          },
          {
            "word": "EFFACE",
            "answer": "effaced"
          },
          {
            "word": "PRECIPITOUS",
            "answer": "precipitous"
          },
          {
            "word": "PUTATIVE",
            "answer": "putative"
          },
          {
            "word": "SUPERCILIOUS",
            "answer": "supercilious"
          },
          {
            "word": "CAVIL",
            "answer": "caviled"
          },
          {
            "word": "EQUANIMITY",
            "answer": "equanimity"
          },
          {
            "word": "PREPOSSESSING",
            "answer": "prepossessing"
          },
          {
            "word": "RAILLERY",
            "answer": "raillery"
          },
          {
            "word": "TORPOR",
            "answer": "torpor"
          },
          {
            "word": "COGENT",
            "answer": "cogent"
          },
          {
            "word": "NASCENT",
            "answer": "nascent"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROFLIGATE",
            "answer": "profligate"
          },
          {
            "word": "RAPACIOUS",
            "answer": "rapacious"
          },
          {
            "word": "TUMID",
            "answer": "tumid"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONFITURE",
            "answer": "confiture"
          },
          {
            "word": "NONPLUSSED",
            "answer": "nonplussed"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROSAIC",
            "answer": "prosaic"
          },
          {
            "word": "REVILE",
            "answer": "reviled"
          },
          {
            "word": "UNCTUOUS",
            "answer": "unctuous"
          },
          {
            "word": "DEMUR",
            "answer": "demurred"
          },
          {
            "word": "PERIPATETIC",
            "answer": "peripatetic"
          },
          {
            "word": "BADINAGE",
            "answer": "badinage"
          },
          {
            "word": "DISSEMBLE",
            "answer": "dissembled"
          },
          {
            "word": "INIMICAL",
            "answer": "inimical"
          },
          {
            "word": "PENURIOUS",
            "answer": "penurious"
          },
          {
            "word": "RISIBLE",
            "answer": "risible"
          },
          {
            "word": "CANARD",
            "answer": "canard"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXPATIATE",
            "answer": "expatiated"
          },
          {
            "word": "MACERATE",
            "answer": "macerated"
          },
          {
            "word": "PHLEGMATIC",
            "answer": "phlegmatic"
          },
          {
            "word": "SEDITIOUS",
            "answer": "seditious"
          },
          {
            "word": "CAPACIOUS",
            "answer": "capacious"
          },
          {
            "word": "FIRMAMENT",
            "answer": "firmament"
          },
          {
            "word": "MAELSTROM",
            "answer": "maelstrom"
          },
          {
            "word": "QUERULOUS",
            "answer": "querulous"
          },
          {
            "word": "SYCOPHANCY",
            "answer": "sycophancy"
          },
          {
            "word": "COLLOQUY",
            "answer": "colloquy"
          },
          {
            "word": "HALCYON",
            "answer": "halcyon"
          },
          {
            "word": "MENDACIOUS",
            "answer": "mendacious"
          },
          {
            "word": "RESTIVE",
            "answer": "restive"
          },
          {
            "word": "VIRULENT",
            "answer": "virulent"
          },
          {
            "word": "DIAPHANOUS",
            "answer": "diaphanous"
          },
          {
            "word": "HEGEMONY",
            "answer": "hegemony"
          },
          {
            "word": "OSTENSIBLE",
            "answer": "ostensible"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "The good-natured",
            "part2": "between the two friends was witty but affectionate.",
            "correct": "raillery",
            "word": "RAILLERY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The cook prepared a delightful cherry",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "confiture",
            "word": "CONFITURE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His",
            "part2": "attitude showed everyone he thought he was too important to be working with the likes of them.",
            "correct": "supercilious",
            "word": "SUPERCILIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "lecturer was always on the road, traveling here and there to give his talks.",
            "correct": "peripatetic",
            "word": "PERIPATETIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Everything seemed to move more slowly in the",
            "part2": "of the long hot summer days.",
            "correct": "torpor",
            "word": "TORPOR"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The president's",
            "part2": "spending soon caused the company to go bankrupt.",
            "correct": "profligate",
            "word": "PROFLIGATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The author of the pamphlet",
            "part2": "the dictator and urged the people to rise up in revolt.",
            "correct": "reviled",
            "word": "REVILE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Their",
            "part2": "arguments finally convinced us they were right.",
            "correct": "cogent",
            "word": "COGENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "This article is too",
            "part2": "; it presents all the facts, but in a very dull, ordinary way.",
            "correct": "prosaic",
            "word": "PROSAIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "It takes considerable",
            "part2": "to remain unruffled when everyone is insulting you.",
            "correct": "equanimity",
            "word": "EQUANIMITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The disease caused his flesh to swell and become",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "tumid",
            "word": "TUMID"
          },
          {
            "part1": "In a solemn oath Harris agreed to",
            "part2": "drinking and never touch alcohol again.",
            "correct": "abjure",
            "word": "ABJURE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We would like to study this",
            "part2": "masterpiece, to see if it is as good as people claim.",
            "correct": "putative",
            "word": "PUTATIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After descending gradually for a while the road has a sudden",
            "part2": "drop.",
            "correct": "precipitous",
            "word": "PRECIPITOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mrs. Benson",
            "part2": "constantly about the hotel. She had a trivial criticism to make about everything from the sheets to the elevators.",
            "correct": "caviled",
            "word": "CAVIL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Peter's parents are",
            "part2": "by his behavior; they just can't understand why he is acting so strangely.",
            "correct": "nonplussed",
            "word": "NONPLUSSED"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Constant handling over many years had completely",
            "part2": "the date on the coin.",
            "correct": "effaced",
            "word": "EFFACE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "young man vowed to stop at nothing until he was rich.",
            "correct": "rapacious",
            "word": "RAPACIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The slick salesman gave us a(n)",
            "part2": "smile and smoothly began to talk about the virtues of his product.",
            "correct": "unctuous",
            "word": "UNCTUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Sharon has such a(n)",
            "part2": "manner that people just naturally like her.",
            "correct": "prepossessing",
            "word": "PREPOSSESSING"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The college’s",
            "part2": "psychology department is only a couple of years old, but it is fast becoming one of the best in the country.",
            "correct": "nascent",
            "word": "NASCENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "When asked if he wanted to play football, Joe",
            "part2": ", saying it was a game for younger men.",
            "correct": "demurred",
            "word": "DEMUR"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Light shone through the",
            "part2": "curtains into the room.",
            "correct": "diaphanous",
            "word": "DIAPHANOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "To raise prices would be helpful now, but it would be",
            "part2": "to the company's long-term growth.",
            "correct": "inimical",
            "word": "INIMICAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "disease wiped out entire cities before a cure was found.",
            "correct": "virulent",
            "word": "VIRULENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She wished she could return to the",
            "part2": "days of her youth, when she was happy and without a care.",
            "correct": "halcyon",
            "word": "HALCYON"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The government said that the radical's speech was",
            "part2": "and would give aid and comfort to the enemy.",
            "correct": "seditious",
            "word": "SEDITIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The ship was sucked into the",
            "part2": "and quickly disappeared from sight.",
            "correct": "maelstrom",
            "word": "MAELSTROM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The playful",
            "part2": "between the good friends couldn't disguise their true liking for each other.",
            "correct": "badinage",
            "word": "BADINAGE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "There is no truth to that story about the rock singer losing his voice; it is simply a(n)",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "canard",
            "word": "CANARD"
          },
          {
            "part1": "While his",
            "part2": "reason for being here was to help us, we knew he really wanted just to see what we were up to.",
            "correct": "ostensible",
            "word": "OSTENSIBLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "John became quite",
            "part2": "as the meeting went on with no agreement in sight.",
            "correct": "restive",
            "word": "RESTIVE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The man habitually",
            "part2": "about his age, saying that he was five years younger than he really was.",
            "correct": "dissembled",
            "word": "DISSEMBLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The coach",
            "part2": "at considerable length about what makes a good football player.",
            "correct": "expatiated",
            "word": "EXPATIATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He is so",
            "part2": "that a herd of charging elephants would only stir his interest slightly.",
            "correct": "phlegmatic",
            "word": "PHLEGMATIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The report called the manufacturer's claims",
            "part2": ", stating that the product would never do all the things it was supposed to do.",
            "correct": "mendacious",
            "word": "MENDACIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Julie picked out the brightest star in the",
            "part2": "and made a wish on it.",
            "correct": "firmament",
            "word": "FIRMAMENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I thought his jokes were faintly",
            "part2": ", but not real sidesplitters.",
            "correct": "risible",
            "word": "RISIBLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The star's",
            "part2": "dressing room is large enough to fit a house in it.",
            "correct": "capacious",
            "word": "CAPACIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We",
            "part2": "the fibers by soaking them in water for several days.",
            "correct": "macerated",
            "word": "MACERATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The Soviet Union established its",
            "part2": "in Eastern Europe after World War II.",
            "correct": "hegemony",
            "word": "HEGEMONY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The two senators had a stimulating",
            "part2": "in which both points of view were well represented.",
            "correct": "colloquy",
            "word": "COLLOQUY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The president quickly tired of the",
            "part2": "of his advisers and demanded they give their real opinions instead of just flattering him.",
            "correct": "sycophancy",
            "word": "SYCOPHANCY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "family lives without heat, electricity, or running water.",
            "correct": "penurious",
            "word": "PENURIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "patient complained about everything from the nurses to the food.",
            "correct": "querulous",
            "word": "QUERULOUS"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "8.7",
          "definitions": {
            "RATIOCINATION": {
              "word": "RATIOCINATION",
              "phonetic": "(rash-E-os-g-nA'-shgn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "reasoning \nRATIOCINATION is the process of logical thinking. The word comes from the same Latin root as <em>rational</em>. It usually suggests an extended process, not simply a deduction reached from a set of facts. \n\"Carla didn't reach the correct solution by guesswork, but by pure RATIOCINATION.\" \n\"The philosopher's RATIOCINATIONS were interrupted by the arrival of a visitor.\" \n\"Sidney was not capable of prolonged RATIOCINATION. He said hard thinking gave him a headache.\" \n<em>Dividing</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, probably because people are attracted to the <em>ratio</em> part of the word. \nOther forms of the word: RATIOCINATE, v. RATIOCINATIVE, adj."
            },
            "TRUCULENT": {
              "word": "TRUCULENT",
              "phonetic": "(truhk'-yg-lgnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "fierce, belligerent, pugnacious \nTRUCULENT means \"having a fierce appearance or dis- position.\" It is used about people who are always ready to fight or bully others. \n\"The TRUCULENT drunk bellowed that he could beat up anybody in the bar.\" \n\"The TRUCULENT hockey team likes nothing more than to get in a brawl with its opponent.\" \n\"Despite its small size, the country is quite TRUCULENT, and is always threatening to invade its neighbors.\" \nOther forms of the word: TRUCULENCE, n."
            },
            "NACREOUS": {
              "word": "NACREOUS",
              "phonetic": "(nA'-krE-gs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "pearly, lustrous \nNACRE is mother-of-pearl, the hard, luminous, colorful substance that forms the inside layer of the pearl oyster shell and other sea-animal shells. Something that is NACREOUS is pearl-like, lustrous. \n\"The shell that he found on the beach was rough and encrusted on the outside, but smooth and NACREOUS within.\" \n\"The blue veins just visible under the skin of her white throat lent it a beautiful NACREOUS quality.\""
            },
            "TEMERITY": {
              "word": "TEMERITY",
              "phonetic": "(t;-mer'-;-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "rashness, effrontery, audacity \nTEMERITY is rash boldness, a reckless disregard of danger or opposition. The word often suggests presumptuousness. \n\"The student had the TEMERITY to suggest that the professor didn't know what she was talking about.\" \n\"It took a certain amount of TEMERITY for Bill to ignore his doctor's advice and run in the marathon.\" \n\"Janet's TEMERITY in arguing with the president about company policy cost her her job.\" \nA related adjective is TEMERARIOUS, which means \"presumptuously rash.\" \nTEMERITY appears to be difficult mostly because of confusion with <em>timidity</em>. <em>Cowardice</em>, an opposite, is a more popular choice on the Pretest than the correct answer, <em>rashness</em>. \nOther forms of the word: TEMERARIOUS, adj."
            },
            "ADJURE": {
              "word": "ADJURE",
              "phonetic": "(ad-jUr')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "command, enjoin, entreat \nTo ADJURE is to command solemnly or earnestly. When the emphasis is placed on the earnestness of the com-mand, ADJURE comes close to meaning <em>entreat</em> or <em>beg</em>. \n\"The missionary ADJURED his disciples to think less about the world and more about their work.\" \n\"All of the new altarboys were ADJURED to pay strict attention during the service.\" \n\"The guard ADJURED us not to touch the sculptures.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>criticize</em>, due perhaps to a confusion of ADJURE with <em>admonish</em>. \nOther forms of the word: ADJURATION, n."
            },
            "ASPERITY": {
              "word": "ASPERITY",
              "phonetic": "(as-per'-ÔøΩ-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "harshness, acerbity, severity, irritability \nASPERITY comes from a Latin word meaning <em>rough</em>. This root is also found in the word <em>exasperate</em>, which literally means to <em>make rough</em>, but is usually used about people's states of mind and means to <em>make irritable</em>, to <em>provoke</em>. ASPERITY can be used about the literal roughness of a surface, or of harsh sounds, but like <em>exasperate</em> it is usually applied to people, and refers to harshness of temper or manner. \n\"The company's spokesman said with some ASPERITY that it had never done anything illegal.\" \n\"He regretted now the ASPERITY with which he had rejected their advice.\" \n\"The ASPERITY of his manner made people nervous and a little frightened.\""
            },
            "GAINSAY": {
              "word": "GAINSAY",
              "phonetic": "(gAn'-sA)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to deny, contradict \nTo GAINSAY something is to dispute its truth, to deny it. It is a rather literary term, and is generally used in a negative construction. The past tense is GAINSAID. \n\"Much as we dislike her, we cannot GAINSAY her right to inherit the house.\" \n\"No one is attempting to GAINSAY the accuracy of your data; we merely question your interpretation of it.\" \n\"Despite his shortcomings, he is a great man; that cannot be GAINSAID.\" \n<em>Suggest</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, probably influenced by the <em>say</em> part of GAINSAY."
            },
            "EXTIRPATE": {
              "word": "EXTIRPATE",
              "phonetic": "(ek'-stÔøΩr-pAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to annihilate, exterminate, root out \nThe <em>tirp</em> part of EXTIRPATE comes from a Latin word meaning <em>root</em>. The literal meaning of EXTIRPATE is to <em>root out</em>. See <em>ex-</em> under Prefixes and <em>-ate1</em> under Suffixes. The word usually suggests total destruction. \n\"We must not only defeat the enemy, we must EXTIRPATE them.\" \n\"Sharon was determined to EXTIRPATE the weeds from her garden, once and for all.\" \n\"The missionaries were not successful in EXTIRPATING the devil worship among the natives.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXTIRPATION, n."
            },
            "INGENUOUS": {
              "word": "INGENUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(in-jen'-yU-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "naive, natural, artless \nINGENUOUS means <em>candid</em>, <em>open</em>, <em>simple</em>, <em>without pretense</em>. It implies a childlike inability to deceive, rather than a conscious choice not to deceive. It is applied both to people and their actions. \n\"Even when he misbehaved, Billy's voluntary, INGENUOUS confession would endear him to his parents.\" \n\"Diane is so INGENUOUS that it seems cruel to trick her like this.\" \n\"When questioned about her whereabouts on the night of the murder, her INGENUOUS answer convinced the detectives of her innocence.\" \nMore people choose <em>cunning</em>, a wrong answer, than <em>naive</em>, the right one, due no doubt to a confusion with the easier word <em>ingenious</em>."
            },
            "INSOUCIANT": {
              "word": "INSOUCIANT",
              "phonetic": "(in-sU'-sE-ÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "carefree, unconcerned \nINSOUCIANT means \"free from care or anxiety.\" The word is used with regard to people who don't care what kind of impression they make or how others respond to them. \n\"Debbie's INSOUCIANT behavior at the party showed that she didn't mind shocking her hosts.\" \n\"Jim INSOUCIANTLY asked the principal to hold his books for him while he tied his shoelace.\" \n\"The INSOUCIANT young fellow wore whatever he liked and said whatever popped into his mind.\" \n<em>Disrespectful</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer. Often INSOUCIANT people may appear disrespectful, since they don't care what other people think of them, but the emphasis in the word is on this lack of concern, not the lack of respect. \nOther forms of the word: INSOUCIANCE, n."
            },
            "SANGUINE": {
              "word": "SANGUINE",
              "phonetic": "(sang'-gwin)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "hopeful, optimistic, confident \nSANGUINE comes from the Latin word for <em>blood</em>, and is still used in English to mean <em>bloody</em> or <em>blood-covered</em>. Its most common use, however, derives from the medieval theory that a person's general disposition was determined by the quantities of four fluids in his or her body. If blood predominated, the person was supposed to be spirited and passionate. From this has come SANGUINE's current meaning of \"cheerfully optimistic,\" <em>hopeful</em>. Sometimes the word suggests over-optimism or confidence that is misplaced. \n\"Despite all his misfortunes, Mr. Micawber remained SANGUINE about his prospects for the future.\" \n\"I am not SANGUINE about my chances of getting into a good college.\" \n\"Gail's SANGUINE disposition led her to think that losing her job was just a temporary setback.\" \n<em>Cruel</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, probably due to the connection of SANGUINE with blood."
            },
            "SEDULOUS": {
              "word": "SEDULOUS",
              "phonetic": "(sej'-u-lÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "diligent, industrious \nSEDULOUS means <em>industrious</em>, and implies that a person is working hard and persistently at accomplishing something. \n\"He is not a genius, but his SEDULOUS efforts earn him very good grades.\" \n\"SEDULOUS attention to detail marks Joe as a clerk who takes his job seriously.\" \n\"The nurse is SEDULOUS in carrying out her duties; nothing remains undone at the end of her shift.\""
            },
            "SENTIENT": {
              "word": "SENTIENT",
              "phonetic": "(sen'-chÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "conscious, aware, capable of feeling \nSENTIENT is from a Latin word meaning to <em>feel</em>; it is related to words like <em>sensitive</em> and <em>sensuous</em> that also have to do with feeling and the senses. SENTIENT means \"capable of perceiving through the senses.\" It is applied to living beings, like animals or humans, who have some form of consciousness. \n\"He could not believe there was a SENTIENT creature that didn't know who had won the World Series.\" \n\"She thought rocks were SENTIENT and wouldn't kick any for fear of hurting them.\" \n<em>Wise</em> is a commonly chosen wrong answer, perhaps due to confusion with <em>sententious</em>, which means <em>pithy</em>, \"full of aphorisms.\" \nOther forms of the word: SENTIENCE, n."
            },
            "SOBRIQUET": {
              "word": "SOBRIQUET",
              "phonetic": "(sO-bri-kA'",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a nickname \nSOBRIQUET is sometimes spelled SOUBRIQUET. \nA SOBRIQUET is a nickname, especially one that is humorous, affectionate, or picturesque. \n\"Babe Ruth's tremendous batting prowess earned him the SOBRIQUET 'The Sultan of Swat.'\" \n\"Lincoln's SOBRIQUET 'Honest Abe' is known by every American schoolchild.\" \n\"After losing his hat in a gust of wind, Bill decided that 'The Windy City' was an appropriate SOBRIQUET for Chicago.\""
            },
            "SPATE": {
              "word": "SPATE",
              "phonetic": "(spAt)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a flood, outpouring, deluge \nA SPATE is literally a stream or river that has become full and turbulent due to melting snow or heavy rains. In this sense, the word is often used in the phrase \"in SPATE\" or \"in full SPATE.\" Usually the word is used in a figurative sense about any kind of sudden rush or outpouring. \n\"The news that the prince was to be married produced a SPATE of books and articles on the royal family.\" \n\"There was a SPATE of phone calls at the TV station protesting the decision not to televise the basketball game.\" \nThis word is difficult because many people think a SPATE is a lot slower than it really is. <em>Trickle</em> is almost as common an answer on the Pretest as the correct answer, <em>flood</em>."
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "RATIOCINATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "remembering",
                    "dividing",
                    "reasoning",
                    "persuading",
                    "deciding"
                  ],
                  "word": "RATIOCINATION",
                  "correct": "reasoning"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRUCULENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "gentle",
                    "fierce",
                    "heavy",
                    "cunning",
                    "excited"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRUCULENT",
                  "correct": "fierce"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NACREOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "ebony",
                    "shining",
                    "smooth",
                    "pearly",
                    "turquoise"
                  ],
                  "word": "NACREOUS",
                  "correct": "pearly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TEMERITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "rashness",
                    "cowardice",
                    "impatience",
                    "pride",
                    "strength"
                  ],
                  "word": "TEMERITY",
                  "correct": "rashness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ADJURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "admire",
                    "command",
                    "fear",
                    "join",
                    "criticize"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADJURE",
                  "correct": "command"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASPERITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "harshness",
                    "poverty",
                    "cheerfulness",
                    "pride",
                    "dissatisfaction"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASPERITY",
                  "correct": "harshness"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to GAINSAY",
                  "answers": [
                    "approve",
                    "repeat",
                    "suggest",
                    "recall",
                    "deny"
                  ],
                  "word": "GAINSAY",
                  "correct": "deny"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to EXTIRPATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "establish",
                    "insert",
                    "annihilate",
                    "disfigure",
                    "transform"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXTIRPATE",
                  "correct": "annihilate"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INGENUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "stupid",
                    "naive",
                    "cunning",
                    "phony",
                    "sophisticated"
                  ],
                  "word": "INGENUOUS",
                  "correct": "naive"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INSOUCIANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "carefree",
                    "earnest",
                    "disrespectful",
                    "warm-hearted",
                    "naive"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSOUCIANT",
                  "correct": "carefree"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SANGUINE",
                  "answers": [
                    "discouraged",
                    "cruel",
                    "sluggish",
                    "hopeful",
                    "loving"
                  ],
                  "word": "SANGUINE",
                  "correct": "hopeful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SEDULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "naive",
                    "talkative",
                    "lazy",
                    "cunning",
                    "diligent"
                  ],
                  "word": "SEDULOUS",
                  "correct": "diligent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SENTIENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "unthinking",
                    "motionless",
                    "active",
                    "wise",
                    "conscious"
                  ],
                  "word": "SENTIENT",
                  "correct": "conscious"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SOBRIQUET",
                  "answers": [
                    "insult",
                    "eulogy",
                    "nickname",
                    "salutation",
                    "title"
                  ],
                  "word": "SOBRIQUET",
                  "correct": "nickname"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SPATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "flood",
                    "trickle",
                    "noise",
                    "rain",
                    "battle"
                  ],
                  "word": "SPATE",
                  "correct": "flood"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Can infants perform RATIOCINATION?",
                  "word": "RATIOCINATION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do timid people tend to be TRUCULENT?",
                  "word": "TRUCULENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are ashes NACREOUS?",
                  "word": "NACREOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a bold person likely to possess TEMERITY?",
                  "word": "TEMERITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a minister ADJURE people not to lie?",
                  "word": "ADJURE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do most people find ASPERITY pleasant?",
                  "word": "ASPERITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person who lies GAINSAY something that is true?",
                  "word": "GAINSAY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an implacable foe want to EXTIRPATE his enemy?",
                  "word": "EXTIRPATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an INGENUOUS person try to deceive people?",
                  "word": "INGENUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would INSOUCIANT people usually possess self-confidence?",
                  "word": "INSOUCIANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a SANGUINE person likely to be anguished?",
                  "word": "SANGUINE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is laziness a characteristic of a SEDULOUS person?",
                  "word": "SEDULOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would someone who is capable of deep thought be SENTIENT?",
                  "word": "SENTIENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is \"Reginald\" a SOBRIQUET?",
                  "word": "SOBRIQUET",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a river in SPATE likely to be dangerous?",
                  "word": "SPATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "These plans are the result of deep RATIOCINATION by some of our finest minds.",
                  "word": "RATIOCINATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The student's TRUCULENT behavior quickly exasperated the teacher.",
                  "word": "TRUCULENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The NACREOUS wolves advanced across the clearing toward him.",
                  "word": "NACREOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Phil lacked the TEMERITY to object to his boss's outrageous demands.",
                  "word": "TEMERITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Sal ADJURED her for putting catsup on her fried egg.",
                  "word": "ADJURE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The ASPERITY with which she gazed at our work suggested that we were in for a tongue-lashing.",
                  "word": "ASPERITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The professor GAINSAID to us that we would have to try harder on the final.",
                  "word": "GAINSAY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The military government vowed to EXTIRPATE all of its opponents.",
                  "word": "EXTIRPATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "This INGENUOUS new invention will revolutionize photography.",
                  "word": "INGENUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The INSOUCIANT secretary didn't seem to care what her boss thought of her.",
                  "word": "INSOUCIANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The judge sent the mother to jail for her SANGUINE abuse of her children.",
                  "word": "SANGUINE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It was SEDULOUS of her to refuse to see us.",
                  "word": "SEDULOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Benjamin Franklin's SENTIENT maxims are still widely quoted.",
                  "word": "SENTIENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The baseball player received the SOBRIQUET \"Stick\" because he was so thin.",
                  "word": "SOBRIQUET",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The movie was really popular at first, but attendance declined to a SPATE after a few weeks.",
                  "word": "SPATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "RATIOCINATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "deduction",
                    "intuition",
                    "inference"
                  ],
                  "word": "RATIOCINATION",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRUCULENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "malevolent",
                    "bellicose",
                    "pugnacious"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRUCULENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NACREOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "lustrous",
                    "glittering",
                    "pearly"
                  ],
                  "word": "NACREOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TEMERITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "wariness",
                    "brashness",
                    "audacity"
                  ],
                  "word": "TEMERITY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ADJURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "beg",
                    "forbid",
                    "enjoin"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADJURE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ASPERITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "rancor",
                    "hope",
                    "acrimony"
                  ],
                  "word": "ASPERITY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GAINSAY",
                  "answers": [
                    "dispute",
                    "reduce",
                    "refute"
                  ],
                  "word": "GAINSAY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXTIRPATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "eradicate",
                    "mitigate",
                    "obliterate"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXTIRPATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INGENUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "candid",
                    "artless",
                    "wise"
                  ],
                  "word": "INGENUOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INSOUCIANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "disobedient",
                    "unconcerned",
                    "happy-go-lucky"
                  ],
                  "word": "INSOUCIANT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SANGUINE",
                  "answers": [
                    "tasteful",
                    "hopeful",
                    "optimistic"
                  ],
                  "word": "SANGUINE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SEDULOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "hasty",
                    "persevering",
                    "energetic"
                  ],
                  "word": "SEDULOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SENTIENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "conscious",
                    "aware",
                    "viable"
                  ],
                  "word": "SENTIENT",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SOBRIQUET",
                  "answers": [
                    "appellation",
                    "nickname",
                    "insult"
                  ],
                  "word": "SOBRIQUET",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SPATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "cataract",
                    "inundation",
                    "drizzle"
                  ],
                  "word": "SPATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "8.8",
          "definitions": {
            "APPOSITE": {
              "word": "APPOSITE",
              "phonetic": "(ap'-ÔøΩzit)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "fitting, suitable, appropriate \nAPPOSITE means <em>fitting</em>, <em>apt</em>, <em>pertinent</em>. The word is usually applied to something, like a quotation, that is strikingly appropriate for a particular situation. \n\"I thought the dean's remarks about belt-tightening were extremely APPOSITE, given the recent release of this year's budget figures.\" \n\"The text was reasonably clear, but the photographs were not particularly APPOSITE.\" \n\"We thought it was an APPOSITE decision to dedicate the new gym on the twenty-fifth anniversary of the dedication of the old gym.\""
            },
            "CALLOW": {
              "word": "CALLOW",
              "phonetic": "(kal'-0)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "immature, inexperienced, unsophisticated \nCALLOW comes from an Anglo-Saxon word meaning <em>bald</em>, which would seem to be almost an opposite of its current meaning, <em>immature</em>. Originally, however, the word was applied to birds, and referred to the lack of feathers of a young bird. CALLOW people, then, are like birds who haven't learned to fly; they are naive and inexperienced in the ways of the world. \n\"The upperclassmen at the school often take advantage of the CALLOW freshmen.\" \n\"The CALLOW recruits were hopelessly inept at being soldiers.\" \n<em>Insincere</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest, perhaps because CALLOW sounds like such negative words as <em>callous</em> and <em>shallow</em>."
            },
            "CONTUMACIOUS": {
              "word": "CONTUMACIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(kon-tU-mA'-shÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "rebellious, insubordinate \nA CONTUMACIOUS person is stubbornly, and often contemptuously, resistant to authority. The word is especially used about resistance to legal authority, for example by ignoring a summons. \n\"The CONTUMACIOUS rebels scoffed at the indictments, saying they were nothing but worthless pieces of paper.\" \n\"When asked if he would abide by the committee's decision, his CONTUMACIOUS reply was 'Nuts!'.\" \nThe noun form of CONTUMACIOUS is CONTUMACY. \n\"His CONTUMACY in refusing to turn over the documents to the court is reprehensible and illegal.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONTUMACY, n."
            },
            "COUNTERPANE": {
              "word": "COUNTERPANE",
              "phonetic": "(kown'-tÔøΩr-pAn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a bedspread, coverlet \nCOUNTERPANE is an old-fashioned word for bedspread. \n\"When you make the bed, turn the COUNTERPANE down neatly under the pillow.\" \n\"The bed was covered with a beautiful needlepoint COUNTERPANE.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>window</em>, probably a guess based on the <em>pane</em> part of COUNTERPANE."
            },
            "CUPIDITY": {
              "word": "CUPIDITY",
              "phonetic": "(kyU-pid'-ÔøΩ-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "greed, avarice, rapacity \nCupid was the Roman god of love. Both <em>Cupid</em> and CUPIDITY come from a Latin word meaning <em>desire</em>. See <em>-ity</em> under Suffixes. CUPIDITY, however, is only used about desire for wealth or possessions, <em>greed</em>. \n\"His CUPIDITY is only exceeded by his stupidity. He is not smart enough to know how to obtain the wealth he longs for.\" \n\"Her greatest fault is her CUPIDITY; she wants to own everything she sees in the jewelry store.\" \nThe wrong answer <em>love</em> attracts people who are familiar with Cupid, but don't know the meaning of CUPIDITY."
            },
            "OFFICIOUS": {
              "word": "OFFICIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ÔøΩ-fish'-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "meddlesome, impertinent, intrusive \nOne of the many meanings of the word OFFICE is \"an act performed for another,\" a <em>service</em> or <em>favor</em>. \n\"Through the kind OFFICES of a friend she was able to find transportation to the meeting.\" \nOFFICIOUS is an adjective from this sense of OFFICE. See <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. OFFICIOUS originally meant simply \"eager to offer one's services.\" Now, however, it always contains the sense that this offer is unwanted and intrusive. \n\"The president's OFFICIOUS meddling made a mess out of the company volleyball tournament.\" \n\"The OFFICIOUS nurse wants to have a hand in every decision made on the ward.\" \n<em>Pompous</em> is a more common answer than the correct synonym, <em>meddlesome</em>. An OFFICIOUS person may seem pompous, but pomposity is not involved in the meaning of the word."
            },
            "PROLIX": {
              "word": "PROLIX",
              "phonetic": "(prO'-liks)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "wordy, verbose, long-winded \nA PROLIX person speaks or writes at such great length as to be tedious. A PROLIX work is one that is too wordy. \n\"It seemed as if the PROLIX after-dinner speaker would go on forever.\" \n\"My teacher hasn't assigned many books, but each one is so PROLIX I'm afraid I won't get through any of them.\" \n\"Your essay is too PROLIX; you go on for ten pages to state what you could have said in one.\" \nOther forms of the word: PROLIXITY, n."
            },
            "UKASE": {
              "word": "UKASE",
              "phonetic": "(yU'-kAs",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an edict, decree \nUKASE is one of the few words in English that come from the Russian. A UKASE was a proclamation or order of the czar that had the force of law. In English, a UKASE is any edict or decree that is backed by strong authority and a presumption that it will be obeyed. \n\"When Mr. Phipps issued a UKASE, no one dared disobey; he was the absolute authority in the company.\" \n\"The citizens rebelled against the dictator's government by UKASE, and insisted that they be able to elect representatives who could vote on laws.\""
            },
            "ANIMUS": {
              "word": "ANIMUS",
              "phonetic": "(an'-ÔøΩ-mÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "hostility, animosity, enmity \nANIMUS is the Latin word for <em>soul</em>. In English it can be used in a similar way to mean <em>spirit</em> or <em>imagination</em>, but it is generally used in a narrower sense to mean \"a spirit of ill will,\" <em>hostility</em>. It is similar to <em>animosity</em>, which comes from the same Latin source, except that an ANIMUS is more deep-seated and personal. \n\"The defendant's ANIMUS toward the lawyer was evident in the short, surly answers he gave.\" \n\"It is difficult to overcome the children's ANIMUS toward classical music.\" \n\"Her ANIMUS toward her ex-husband was so strong that no one mentioned his name in her presence.\""
            },
            "ATELIER": {
              "word": "ATELIER",
              "phonetic": "(at-ÔøΩ1-yA')",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a workshop, artist's studio \nNote the pronunciation: ATELIER is from the French, and keeps its French pronunciation. An ATELIER is an artist's studio or a workroom where students or apprentices of an artist work. \n\"The painter's ATELIER has a skylight so that he gets natural light.\" \n\"The huge mural covered one wall of the ATELIER; dozens of students worked on little pieces of it.\" \nMore people choose <em>garret</em>, a wrong answer, than <em>workshop</em>, the right one. This could be due to a confusion with <em>attic</em>, or <em>garret</em> may be chosen by people who know that an ATELIER is usually at the top of a building, without knowing precisely what it is."
            },
            "EVANESCENT": {
              "word": "EVANESCENT",
              "phonetic": "(ev-ÔøΩ-nes'-ÔøΩnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "vanishing, fleeting, impermanent \nSomething that is EVANESCENT exists only for a short time and then vanishes. The word usually implies that this brief existence is due to the object's delicacy and fragility. EVANESCENT is used about both physical objects and nonphysical states like fame. \n\"Her dreams were so EVANESCENT that she couldn't remember them, and was left only with uncertain memories of loveliness.\" \n\"The EVANESCENT morning mist drifted up from the river and vanished in the sunlight.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>sparkling</em>. This is probably due to a confusion with <em>effervescent</em>. \nOther forms of the word: EVANESCE, v. EVANESCENCE, n."
            },
            "PERTINACIOUS": {
              "word": "PERTINACIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(per-tÔøΩ-nA'-shÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "obstinate, stubborn, persistent \nPERTINACIOUS is related to the word <em>tenacious</em>. Both come from a Latin word meaning to <em>hold</em> and are used about people who hold fast to a purpose or belief. But while <em>tenacious</em> is usually used in a positive sense, PERTINACIOUS has a negative connotation; it is used about people who are stubbornly persistent, who annoy others with their doggedness. \n\"The PERTINACIOUS derelict followed me down the street, asking again and again for money.\" \n\"The guide PERTINACIOUSLY insisted we were heading east, even when the sun began to set in front of us.\" \n\"The boy's PERTINACIOUS curiosity exhausted us and then started to irritate us.\" \n<em>Rude</em> is a commonly chosen wrong answer, probably due to confusion with <em>impertinent</em>. \nOther forms of the word: PERTINACITY, n."
            },
            "PILEOUS": {
              "word": "PILEOUS",
              "phonetic": "(pll'-E-ÔøΩs",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "hairy, furry \nPILEOUS and the similar adjective <em>pilose</em> both come from a Latin word for <em>hair</em>, and mean <em>hairy</em>. The words particularly refer to hair with a soft texture. Another word from this source is <em>pile</em>, the soft compact surface texture of certain kinds of carpets. \n\"He was startled awake when he reached over and embraced something very PILEOUS, but it was only his daughter's huge teddy bear.\" \n\"Tarantulas have PILEOUS bodies that, along with their large size, make them quite gruesome.\""
            },
            "PUNCTILIOUS": {
              "word": "PUNCTILIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(puh",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "attentive to fine points, careful, precise, scrupulous \nPUNCTILIOUS and its related noun PUNCTILIO come from Italian and Spanish words meaning \"a small point.\" A PUNCTILIO is a fine point of behavior or etiquette. \n\"He had no use for the PUNCTILIOS of these stuffy people, so he said and did whatever he pleased.\" \nPUNCTILIOUS means \"attentive to fine points\" and would be used about a person who is careful to observe the niceties of formal behavior. Often the word suggests excessive attention to these fine points. \n\"Mrs. Andrews is PUNCTILIOUS about following the etiquette books in every detail when she gives a party.\" \n\"The PUNCTILIOUS expert is always correcting everyone's grammar.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>pompous</em>, possibly because PUNCTILIOUS people seem pompous and arrogant, possibly because of confusion with the word <em>supercilious</em>, which means <em>haughty</em>, <em>disdainful</em>. See <em>supercilious</em> in Chapter 4. \nOther forms of the word: PUNCTILIO, n."
            },
            "COMITY": {
              "word": "COMITY",
              "phonetic": "(kom'-ÔøΩ-tE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "civility, mutual courtesy \nCOMITY is a rather formal word for <em>civility</em>. It is often used to refer to courteous relations between countries or heads of state, as in \"COMITY of nations.\" \n\"We must strive for COMITY; if nothing else, we should treat each other with respect.\" \n\"The COMITY of the two leaders was based on a sincere desire for world peace; to this end, they started by treating one another civilly.\" \n\"As it became clear that the little principality was not going to repay its debts soon, the COMITY it shared with larger states began to wear thin.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "APPOSITE",
                  "answers": [
                    "unsuitable",
                    "correct",
                    "famous",
                    "different",
                    "fitting"
                  ],
                  "word": "APPOSITE",
                  "correct": "fitting"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CALLOW",
                  "answers": [
                    "insincere",
                    "serene",
                    "pompous",
                    "good-looking",
                    "immature"
                  ],
                  "word": "CALLOW",
                  "correct": "immature"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTUMACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "diplomatic",
                    "afflicted",
                    "enormous",
                    "rebellious",
                    "dangerous"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTUMACIOUS",
                  "correct": "rebellious"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COUNTERPANE",
                  "answers": [
                    "window",
                    "bedspread",
                    "tablecloth",
                    "pillow",
                    "rug"
                  ],
                  "word": "COUNTERPANE",
                  "correct": "bedspread"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CUPIDITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "generosity",
                    "love",
                    "greed",
                    "fear",
                    "deceit"
                  ],
                  "word": "CUPIDITY",
                  "correct": "greed"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OFFICIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "useful",
                    "pompous",
                    "arrogant",
                    "hardworking",
                    "meddlesome"
                  ],
                  "word": "OFFICIOUS",
                  "correct": "meddlesome"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROLIX",
                  "answers": [
                    "wordy",
                    "short",
                    "political",
                    "complicated",
                    "unnecessary"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROLIX",
                  "correct": "wordy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UKASE",
                  "answers": [
                    "edict",
                    "debate",
                    "greeting",
                    "tyrant",
                    "ordinance"
                  ],
                  "word": "UKASE",
                  "correct": "edict"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANIMUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "attraction",
                    "perplexity",
                    "fear",
                    "power",
                    "hostility"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANIMUS",
                  "correct": "hostility"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ATELIER",
                  "answers": [
                    "restaurant",
                    "workshop",
                    "museum",
                    "hotel",
                    "garret"
                  ],
                  "word": "ATELIER",
                  "correct": "workshop"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EVANESCENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "bright",
                    "sparkling",
                    "vanishing",
                    "eternal",
                    "simple"
                  ],
                  "word": "EVANESCENT",
                  "correct": "vanishing"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERTINACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "rude",
                    "graceful",
                    "important",
                    "obstinate",
                    "intelligent"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERT!NACIOUS",
                  "correct": "obstinate"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PILEOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "tiny",
                    "hairy",
                    "ugly",
                    "winged",
                    "flat-headed"
                  ],
                  "word": "PILEOUS",
                  "correct": "hairy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PUNCTILIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "careful",
                    "extravagant",
                    "ridiculous",
                    "pompous",
                    "stern"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUNCTILIOUS",
                  "correct": "careful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COMITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "hostility",
                    "pleasure",
                    "love",
                    "beauty",
                    "civility"
                  ],
                  "word": "COMITY",
                  "correct": "civility"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Can an adage be APPOSITE?",
                  "word": "APPOSITE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a CALLOW youth likely to be extremely self-confident?",
                  "word": "CALLOW",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a timid person likely to be CONTUMACIOUS?",
                  "word": "CONTUMACIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are COUNTERPANES generally soft?",
                  "word": "COUNTERPANE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is CUPIDITY a vice?",
                  "word": "CUPIDITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could an OFFICIOUS person be annoying?",
                  "word": "OFFICIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a PROLIX person use a great many words?",
                  "word": "PROLIX",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can the president of a company issue a UKASE?",
                  "word": "UKASE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an extravagant person feel an ANIMUS against spending money?",
                  "word": "ANIMUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would an ATELIER generally be tiny?",
                  "word": "ATELIER",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a cathedral EVANESCENT?",
                  "word": "EVANESCENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it easy to get rid of a PERTINACIOUS admirer?",
                  "word": "PERTINACIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are billiard balls PILEOUS?",
                  "word": "PILEOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a sloppy person likely to be PUNCTILIOUS?",
                  "word": "PUNCTILIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are belligerent nations interested in COMITY?",
                  "word": "COMITY",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "No one could gainsay the principal's APPOSITE remarks about the need for discipline.",
                  "word": "APPOSITE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The CALLOW young actress was afraid to ask the director for an audition.",
                  "word": "CALLOW",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The judge deplored their CONTUMACY and threatened to hold them in contempt of court.",
                  "word": "CONTUMACIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The baseball shattered the COUNTERPANE.",
                  "word": "COUNTERPANE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The accountant's CUPIDITY led him to steal thousands of dollars in company funds.",
                  "word": "CUPIDITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The OFFICIOUS results showed neither candidate gaining a majority.",
                  "word": "OFFICIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Because of space limitations, the editor told the writer to avoid PROLIXITY.",
                  "word": "PROLIX",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The workers resent these management UKASES; they want some say in how the company is run.",
                  "word": "UKASE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His ANIMUS toward foreigners is an unfortunate byproduct of his experiences during the war.",
                  "word": "ANIMUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The apprentices crowded into the ATELIER to see the famous sculptor at work.",
                  "word": "ATELIER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Her happiness proved to be EVANESCENT; in a few months tragedy struck.",
                  "word": "EVANESCENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It is PERTINACIOUS of you to suggest that I am bigoted.",
                  "word": "PERTINACIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The animal is smooth-skinned except for small PILEOUS areas on each paw.",
                  "word": "PILEOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He was PUNCTILIOUS about winning the contest; he simply said he deserved it.",
                  "word": "PUNCTILIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "These new trade restrictions will certainly not increase COMITY among the affected nations.",
                  "word": "COMITY",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "APPOSITE",
                  "answers": [
                    "pertinent",
                    "germane",
                    "ardent"
                  ],
                  "word": "APPOSITE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CALLOW",
                  "answers": [
                    "naive",
                    "carefree",
                    "inexperienced"
                  ],
                  "word": "CALLOW",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONTUMACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "defiant",
                    "vindictive",
                    "rebellious"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONTUMACIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COUNTERPANE",
                  "answers": [
                    "pillow",
                    "quilt",
                    "coverlet"
                  ],
                  "word": "COUNTERPANE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CUPIDITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "antagonism",
                    "avarice",
                    "rapacity"
                  ],
                  "word": "CUPIDITY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OFFICIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "obtrusive",
                    "irrelevant",
                    "impertinent"
                  ],
                  "word": "OFFICIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROLIX",
                  "answers": [
                    "voluble",
                    "steadfast",
                    "loquacious"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROLIX",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "UKASE",
                  "answers": [
                    "request",
                    "law",
                    "proclamation"
                  ],
                  "word": "UKASE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ANIMUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "antipathy",
                    "aversion",
                    "indifference"
                  ],
                  "word": "ANIMUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ATELIER",
                  "answers": [
                    "parlor",
                    "workshop",
                    "studio"
                  ],
                  "word": "ATELIER",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EVANESCENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "cerebral",
                    "transitory",
                    "ephemeral"
                  ],
                  "word": "EVANESCENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERTINACIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "rowdy",
                    "stubborn",
                    "dogged"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERTINACIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PILEOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "woolly",
                    "scaly",
                    "furry"
                  ],
                  "word": "PILEOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PUNCTILIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "meticulous",
                    "timeless",
                    "scrupulous"
                  ],
                  "word": "PUNCTILIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "COMITY",
                  "answers": [
                    "amicability",
                    "loyalty",
                    "courtesy"
                  ],
                  "word": "COMITY",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "8.9",
          "definitions": {
            "TURPITUDE": {
              "word": "TURPITUDE",
              "phonetic": "(ter'-p;-tUd",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "depravity, baseness \nTURPITUDE is baseness or vileness. It is often used in the phrase \"moral TURPITUDE.\" \n\"Hester Prynne was accused of moral TURPITUDE when the town discovered she was pregnant without being married.\" \n\"The governor said his opponent's TURPITUDE made him unfit to serve in office.\" \nTURPITUDE is also occasionally used about a base or vile act. \n\"The preacher said that such TURPITUDES would not go unpunished in the hereafter.\" \nTURPITUDE is thought to mean <em>righteousness</em> by a large proportion of the people taking the Pretest, due to confusion of TURPITUDE with <em>rectitude</em>."
            },
            "CAPTIOUS": {
              "word": "CAPTIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(kap'-sh;s)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "faultfinding, carping \nCAPTIOUS means <em>faultfinding</em>; someone who is CAPTIOUS is hard to please, likes to make petty criticisms. \n\"Pamela was annoyed by John's CAPTIOUS criticism of her every utterance.\" \n\"The man is so CAPTIOUS that his valets leave one after another, fed up with his constant nitpicking.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>entrancing</em>, probably due to a confusion of CAPTIOUS with <em>captivating</em>."
            },
            "DILATORY": {
              "word": "DILATORY",
              "phonetic": "(dil'-ÔøΩtor-E)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "slow, tardy, causing delay \nDILATORY is applied to people and their actions. A DILATORY person delays, out of laziness, indifference, or simply out of a desire to delay. \n\"Alan was so DILATORY in returning books that the library took away his card.\" \n\"Realizing his company was short of cash, the accountant was DILATORY about paying bills.\" \nDILATORY actions are characterized by delay or are intended to delay. \n\"The senator's DILATORY tactics prevented the bill from being considered before Congress adjourned.\""
            },
            "EPIGONE": {
              "word": "EPIGONE",
              "phonetic": "(ep'-ÔøΩgOn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an imitator, follower \nEPIGONE comes from the Greek <em>epigonoi</em>, which literally means \"born after.\" In Greek legend, the Epigonoi were the sons of the seven leaders who had been defeated at Thebes; they, like their fathers, attacked that city. An EPIGONE is an imitator, usually a second-rate one. \n\"The miserable EPIGONE spent his days copying Caravaggio's great works and dreaming of the day that he'd be famous.\" \n\"The professor considers himself a follower of Plato's, but he is merely an EPIGONE: where Plato was profound the professor is merely pompous.\""
            },
            "FEBRILE": {
              "word": "FEBRILE",
              "phonetic": "(feb'-rJI",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "feverish \nFEBRILE is a close synonym of <em>feverish</em>. Both come from the Latin word for <em>fever</em>. FEBRILE comes to us through the French, <em>feverish</em> through Old English. As is usually the case, the word that has been in the language longer is more commonly used and understood. \n\"The child was hot and FEBRILE after the long, exhausting day.\" \n\"The candidate's last FEBRILE burst of activity was not enough to stave off defeat.\" \n<em>Delicate</em> is a common choice on the Pretest, perhaps due to a vague similarity of FEBRILE to <em>fragile</em>. <em>Diseased</em> is also a common choice; it is probably chosen by people who have a vague idea of FEBRILE's meaning."
            },
            "FRIABLE": {
              "word": "FRIABLE",
              "phonetic": "(frl'-g-b;}I)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "crumbly, brittle \nFRIABLE means \"easily reduced to powder.\" The word is usually used about certain rocks or other materials that are brittle and crumble readily. \n\"The FRIABLE piece of sandstone crumbled into a thousand pieces when I dropped it on the sidewalk.\" \n\"The spade cut easily through the FRIABLE soil.\" \n\"The FRIABLE chalk disintegrated as soon as the teacher tried to write with it.\""
            },
            "LACUNA": {
              "word": "LACUNA",
              "phonetic": "(1ÔøΩ-kyU'-nÔøΩ)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a gap, hole, empty space \nA LACUNA is a missing part, a gap. The word is often used about gaps of knowledge or gaps in a manuscript or inscription. The plural of LACUNA is LACUNAE or LACUNAS. \n\"The professor is widely read, but she obviously has a LACUNA in the area of the physical sciences.\" \n\"Several LACUNAE in the tattered old letter made its subject difficult to decipher.\" \n\"There are many LACUNAS in our knowledge of how and when Shakespeare wrote his plays.\""
            },
            "BENIGHTED": {
              "word": "BENIGHTED",
              "phonetic": "(bi-nI'-tid)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "ignorant, unenlightened \nThe literal meaning of BENIGHTED is \"covered over by night.\" In this sense the word might be used about travelers caught by darkness. Usually, however, the word is used figuratively, about people enveloped by the darkness of intellectual or moral ignorance. \n\"The poor BENIGHTED peasants had never heard of these wonderful modern inventions.\" \n\"The missionary wished to proclaim his beliefs to the BENIGHTED savages.\" \n\"In those BENIGHTED times any woman who didn't marry was suspected of being a witch.\""
            },
            "MORIBUND": {
              "word": "MORIBUND",
              "phonetic": "lks",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "dormant, dying, obsolescent \nThe Latin root <em>mor</em> or <em>mort</em> means <em>death</em>, and is found in such words as <em>mortal</em>, <em>mortuary</em>, and MORIBUND. The basic meaning of MORIBUND is \"about to die.\" The word is more often used in a figurative sense about anything that is approaching an end. It is also used about things that are now lying dormant, but could come back to life in the future. \n\"When funds ran out, the project became MORIBUND.\" \n\"The oil shortage put new life into the MORIBUND coal industry, as people searched for alternative forms of energy.\" \n<em>Grotesque</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, possibly because MORIBUND is confused with <em>morbid</em>."
            },
            "GELID": {
              "word": "GELID",
              "phonetic": "(jel'-id)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "icy, very cold \nGELID comes from the Latin word for <em>cold</em>, and is a synonym for <em>freezing</em>, <em>icy</em>. It tends to emphasize the discomfort of such cold. \n\"The snowstorm brought such GELID weather that frostbite was epidemic.\" \n\"Bob knew that he couldn't survive long in the GELID water: already his feet and hands were numb.\" \nThe word is also used in a figurative sense. \n\"The teacher's GELID stare indicated he had not found the student's remark amusing.\" \n<em>Weak</em> is a common answer on the Pretest, perhaps be- cause GELID looks and sounds like <em>jellied</em>."
            },
            "DOYEN": {
              "word": "DOYEN",
              "phonetic": "(doy-en'",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "the senior member \nDOYEN is from the French and means \"the senior member of a group.\" The word generally suggests experience and wisdom as a result of this position. The feminine of DOYEN is DOYENNE. \n\"Because of his age and experience, the other members of the team regarded the designated hitter as the DOYEN of the team.\" \n\"The 98-year-old man was unquestionably the DOYEN of the senior citizens' club; no one else was over 80.\""
            },
            "NUGATORY": {
              "word": "NUGATORY",
              "phonetic": "(nU'-gÔøΩ-tor-E)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "worthless, trifling, futile, ineffectual \nSomething that is NUGATORY is without value or significance. \n\"Endless and mindless repetition of endearments can make them NUGATORY after a while.\" \nIn a slightly different sense, NUGATORY can also describe something that has no effect, that doesn't work. In this sense NUGATORY is often applied to laws. \n\"He had a deluded sense of self-importance, but his actual influence in politics was quite NUGATORY. After he left office few people remembered him.\" \n\"All too often the laws that ban littering are NUGATORY in practice because they aren't enforced.\""
            },
            "RECALCITRANT": {
              "word": "RECALCITRANT",
              "phonetic": "(ri-kal'-sg-trÔøΩmt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "rebellious, refractory, defiant \nA RECALCITRANT person is actively defiant of another's authority. The word is stronger than <em>intractable</em> or <em>refractory</em>, and suggests that it will be almost impossible to get the person to obey. \n\"The RECALCITRANT sailor refused to obey the captain, and incited the rest of the crew to defy him as well.\" \n\"In a dictatorship, even a small group of RECALCITRANT subjects is a threat.\" \nRECALCITRANT is occasionally used about things that are very difficult to control or treat. \n\"He simply could not get the RECALCITRANT stereo system to work properly.\" \"The doctor told us that the patients in the ward had a RECALCITRANT form of the disease.\" \n<em>Repentant</em> and <em>reluctant</em> are both commonly chosen wrong answers, perhaps because they look like RECALCITRANT. \nOther forms of the word: RECALCITRANCE, n. RECALCITRANCY, n."
            },
            "SACERDOTAL": {
              "word": "SACERDOTAL",
              "phonetic": "(sas-gr-dO'-tgl)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "priestly \nSACERDOTAL comes from the Latin word for <em>priest</em>; it is related to such English words as <em>sacred</em> and <em>sacrament</em>. SACERDOTAL means \"having to do with priests or the priesthood,\" <em>priestly</em>. \n\"After every religious service, the SACERDOTAL garments were hung in a special closet.\" \n\"The priest regretted that business matters intruded on his SACERDOTAL duties.\""
            },
            "SATURNINE": {
              "word": "SATURNINE",
              "phonetic": "(sat'-gr-nln)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "gloomy, dour, morose \nSATURNINE was originally a term in astrology, meaning \"born under, or affected by the influence of, the planet Saturn.\" Such a person is supposed to have a gloomy, cold, sluggish temperament. The word has come into general use to describe any person with these characteristics. \n\"Emily's SATURNINE disposition makes it difficult for anyone to know or like her.\" \n\"One look at his SATURNINE countenance told us he was in no mood for joking.\" \n\"The SATURNINE man sat silently in his room and brooded about the unhappiness of his life.\""
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "TURPITUDE",
                  "answers": [
                    "depravity",
                    "righteousness",
                    "ambiguity",
                    "necessity",
                    "strangeness"
                  ],
                  "word": "TURPITUDE",
                  "correct": "depravity"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CAPTIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "entrancing",
                    "faultfinding",
                    "constructive",
                    "crowning",
                    "incorrect"
                  ],
                  "word": "CAPTIOUS",
                  "correct": "faultfinding"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DILATORY",
                  "answers": [
                    "prompt",
                    "industrious",
                    "slow",
                    "uncertain",
                    "expansive"
                  ],
                  "word": "DILATORY",
                  "correct": "slow"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EPIGONE",
                  "answers": [
                    "writer",
                    "youth",
                    "gourmet",
                    "imitator",
                    "teacher"
                  ],
                  "word": "EPIGONE",
                  "correct": "imitator"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FEBRILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "soothing",
                    "delicate",
                    "enthusiastic",
                    "diseased",
                    "feverish"
                  ],
                  "word": "FEBRILE",
                  "correct": "feverish"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FRIABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "inflexible",
                    "edible",
                    "crumbly",
                    "soft",
                    "washable"
                  ],
                  "word": "FRIABLE",
                  "correct": "crumbly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LACUNA",
                  "answers": [
                    "addition",
                    "poison",
                    "gap",
                    "paradox",
                    "error"
                  ],
                  "word": "LACUNA",
                  "correct": "gap"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BENIGHTED",
                  "answers": [
                    "ignorant",
                    "blessed",
                    "stranded",
                    "inspired",
                    "impossible"
                  ],
                  "word": "BENIGHTED",
                  "correct": "ignorant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MORIBUND",
                  "answers": [
                    "dormant",
                    "grotesque",
                    "paralyzed",
                    "conquered",
                    "desperate"
                  ],
                  "word": "MORIBUND",
                  "correct": "dormant"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GELID",
                  "answers": [
                    "firm",
                    "weak",
                    "nervous",
                    "icy",
                    "brittle"
                  ],
                  "word": "GELID",
                  "correct": "icy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DOYEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "angry woman",
                    "senior member",
                    "favorite child",
                    "noisy girl",
                    "young actress"
                  ],
                  "word": "DOYEN",
                  "correct": "senior member"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NUGATORY",
                  "answers": [
                    "effective",
                    "obligatory",
                    "threatening",
                    "illegal",
                    "worthless"
                  ],
                  "word": "NUGATORY",
                  "correct": "worthless"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RECALCITRANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "repentant",
                    "rebellious",
                    "awkward",
                    "offensive",
                    "reluctant"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECALCITRANT",
                  "correct": "rebellious"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SACERDOTAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "blessed",
                    "ancient",
                    "pagan",
                    "official",
                    "priestly"
                  ],
                  "word": "SACERDOTAL",
                  "correct": "priestly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SATURNINE",
                  "answers": [
                    "cheerful",
                    "gloomy",
                    "kindly",
                    "wise",
                    "evil"
                  ],
                  "word": "SATURNINE",
                  "correct": "gloomy"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Is self-denial an example of TURPITUDE?",
                  "word": "TURPITUDE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would CAPTIOUS criticisms be helpful?",
                  "word": "CAPTIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a diligent person be DILATORY?",
                  "word": "DILATORY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Was Michelangelo an EPIGONE?",
                  "word": "EPIGONE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can the flu cause a person to feel FEBRILE?",
                  "word": "FEBRILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is granite FRIABLE?",
                  "word": "FRIABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do authors like to have their books contain LACUNAE?",
                  "word": "LACUNA",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a BENIGHTED person ignorant?",
                  "word": "BENIGHTED",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a person be MORIBUND?",
                  "word": "MORIBUND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can the weather be GELID?",
                  "word": "GELID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are DOYENS usually inexperienced?",
                  "word": "DOYEN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is the Bill of Rights NUGATORY?",
                  "word": "NUGATORY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a horse be RECALCITRANT?",
                  "word": "RECALCITRANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would giving a sermon be a SACERDOTAL duty?",
                  "word": "SACERDOTAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a SATURNINE person enjoy a comedy show?",
                  "word": "SATURNINE",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Everyone admires the absolute TURPITUDE of the fine young man.",
                  "word": "TURPITUDE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "After Rich's parents gave him a Cadillac for his birthday, it was CAPTIOUS of him to complain about the color.",
                  "word": "CAPTIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It is DILATORY that we avoid being caught tonight.",
                  "word": "DILATORY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He is just an EPIGONE, with no distinctive voice or ideas of his own.",
                  "word": "EPIGONE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The FEBRILE pace of Mary's life often makes her tired and irritable.",
                  "word": "FEBRILE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "This piece of steak has gone bad; it is no longer FRIABLE.",
                  "word": "FRIABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Erosion has caused several LACUNAS to appear in the ancient tomb inscription.",
                  "word": "LACUNA",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We are BENIGHTED that you could be with us today.",
                  "word": "BENIGHTED",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Several MORIBUND bills were given a new life when Congress returned from its recess.",
                  "word": "MORIBUND",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The committee's GELID response to our proposal convinced us it would never be accepted.",
                  "word": "GELID",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The DOYEN of American chefs sums up his knowledge of cuisine in this new book.",
                  "word": "DOYEN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The effect of the lawyer's closing argument was NUGATORY; the jury had already made up its mind.",
                  "word": "NUGATORY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The RECALCITRANT students absolutely refused to take the test.",
                  "word": "RECALCITRANT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Once he was admitted to the priesthood he learned the secret SACERDOTAL language.",
                  "word": "SACERDOTAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The SATURNINE man cheerfully gave his help to anyone who asked for it.",
                  "word": "SATURNINE",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "TURPITUDE",
                  "answers": [
                    "vileness",
                    "destitution",
                    "corruption"
                  ],
                  "word": "TURPITUDE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CAPTIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "insubordinate",
                    "faultfinding",
                    "complaining"
                  ],
                  "word": "CAPTIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DILATORY",
                  "answers": [
                    "thwarting",
                    "delaying",
                    "lagging"
                  ],
                  "word": "DILATORY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EPIGONE",
                  "answers": [
                    "follower",
                    "successor",
                    "imitator"
                  ],
                  "word": "EPIGONE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FEBRILE",
                  "answers": [
                    "weak",
                    "hot",
                    "hectic"
                  ],
                  "word": "FEBRILE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FRIABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "fragile",
                    "smooth",
                    "crisp"
                  ],
                  "word": "FRIABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LACUNA",
                  "answers": [
                    "interval",
                    "hiatus",
                    "torrent"
                  ],
                  "word": "LACUNA",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BENIGHTED",
                  "answers": [
                    "illicit",
                    "uninformed",
                    "illiterate"
                  ],
                  "word": "BENIGHTED",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MORIBUND",
                  "answers": [
                    "quiescent",
                    "dormant",
                    "restless"
                  ],
                  "word": "MORIBUND",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "GELID",
                  "answers": [
                    "cool",
                    "frigid",
                    "frosty"
                  ],
                  "word": "GELID",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DOYEN",
                  "answers": [
                    "elder",
                    "dictator",
                    "leader"
                  ],
                  "word": "DOYEN",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "NUGATORY",
                  "answers": [
                    "exceptional",
                    "ineffectual",
                    "invalid"
                  ],
                  "word": "NUGATORY",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RECALCITRANT",
                  "answers": [
                    "refractory",
                    "vindictive",
                    "resistant"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECALCITRANT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SACERDOTAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "priestly",
                    "secular",
                    "clerical"
                  ],
                  "word": "SACERDOTAL",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SATURNINE",
                  "answers": [
                    "morose",
                    "devilish",
                    "grim"
                  ],
                  "word": "SATURNINE",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ADJURE",
            "answer": "adjured"
          },
          {
            "word": "CALLOW",
            "answer": "callow or ingenuous"
          },
          {
            "word": "INGENUOUS",
            "answer": "ingenuous"
          },
          {
            "word": "OFFICIOUS",
            "answer": "officious"
          },
          {
            "word": "RECALCITRANT",
            "answer": "recalcitrant"
          },
          {
            "word": "ANIMUS",
            "answer": "animus"
          },
          {
            "word": "EPIGONE",
            "answer": "epigones"
          },
          {
            "word": "INSOUCIANT",
            "answer": "insouciant"
          },
          {
            "word": "PERTINACIOUS",
            "answer": "pertinacious"
          },
          {
            "word": "SOBRIQUET",
            "answer": "sobriquet"
          },
          {
            "word": "APPOSITE",
            "answer": "apposite"
          },
          {
            "word": "GAINSAY",
            "answer": "gainsay"
          },
          {
            "word": "MORIBUND",
            "answer": "moribund"
          },
          {
            "word": "PILEOUS",
            "answer": "pileous"
          },
          {
            "word": "SPATE",
            "answer": "spate"
          },
          {
            "word": "ATELIER",
            "answer": "atelier"
          },
          {
            "word": "GELID",
            "answer": "gelid"
          },
          {
            "word": "NUGATORY",
            "answer": "nugatory"
          },
          {
            "word": "PUNCTILIOUS",
            "answer": "punctilious"
          },
          {
            "word": "TRUCULENT",
            "answer": "truculent or recalcitrant"
          },
          {
            "word": "ASPERITY",
            "answer": "asperity"
          },
          {
            "word": "COUNTERPANE",
            "answer": "counterpane"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXTIRPATE",
            "answer": "extirpate"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROLIX",
            "answer": "prolix"
          },
          {
            "word": "SEDULOUS",
            "answer": "sedulous"
          },
          {
            "word": "BENIGHTED",
            "answer": "benighted"
          },
          {
            "word": "CUPIDITY",
            "answer": "cupidity"
          },
          {
            "word": "FEBRILE",
            "answer": "febrile"
          },
          {
            "word": "RATIOCINATION",
            "answer": "ratiocination"
          },
          {
            "word": "SENTIENT",
            "answer": "sentient"
          },
          {
            "word": "CAPTIOUS",
            "answer": "captious"
          },
          {
            "word": "DILATORY",
            "answer": "dilatory"
          },
          {
            "word": "FRIABLE",
            "answer": "friable"
          },
          {
            "word": "SACERDOTAL",
            "answer": "sacerdotal"
          },
          {
            "word": "TEMERITY",
            "answer": "temerity"
          },
          {
            "word": "COMITY",
            "answer": "comity"
          },
          {
            "word": "DOYEN",
            "answer": "doyen"
          },
          {
            "word": "LACUNA",
            "answer": "lacuna"
          },
          {
            "word": "SANGUINE",
            "answer": "sanguine"
          },
          {
            "word": "TURPITUDE",
            "answer": "turpitude"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONTUMACIOUS",
            "answer": "contumacious"
          },
          {
            "word": "EVANESCENT",
            "answer": "evanescent"
          },
          {
            "word": "NACREOUS",
            "answer": "nacreous"
          },
          {
            "word": "SATURNINE",
            "answer": "saturnine"
          },
          {
            "word": "UKASE",
            "answer": "ukase"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "The article was enhanced by the use of",
            "part2": "quotations to illustrate the author's points.",
            "correct": "apposite",
            "word": "APPOSITE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The members of the club solemnly",
            "part2": "Bill never to reveal their secret.",
            "correct": "adjured",
            "word": "ADJURE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The night air was so",
            "part2": "we could feel it even through five layers of clothing.",
            "correct": "gelid",
            "word": "GELID"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Even though Gwen tries to act",
            "part2": ", we know she cares very deeply about what other people think.",
            "correct": "insouciant",
            "word": "INSOUCIANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The artist worked all day long on the huge painting in his brightly lit",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "atelier",
            "word": "ATELIER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The drunk became quite",
            "part2": "when the police tried to arrest him, so they had to call for assistance.",
            "correct": "truculent or recalcitrant",
            "word": "TRUCULENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "young woman told him that she didn't know the first thing about typing, but wanted the job anyway.",
            "correct": "ingenuous",
            "word": "INGENUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Her",
            "part2": "toward doctors is so intense that she can't even speak to one at a party.",
            "correct": "animus",
            "word": "ANIMUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The amazing new treatment turned the scalp from bald to",
            "part2": "overnight.",
            "correct": "pileous",
            "word": "PILEOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The book's constant errors of fact make it",
            "part2": "as a source of information.",
            "correct": "nugatory",
            "word": "NUGATORY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The servant is more formal and correct in his behavior than his easygoing employer.",
            "correct": "punctilious",
            "word": "PUNCTILIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The great writer attracts many",
            "part2": "who strive, without success, to imitate his style.",
            "correct": "epigones",
            "word": "EPIGONE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "No one can",
            "part2": "the importance of Shakespeare in English literature.",
            "correct": "gainsay",
            "word": "GAINSAY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Nothing could make the",
            "part2": "workers return to the dangerous mine.",
            "correct": "recalcitrant",
            "word": "RECALCITRANT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "new manager meddles in everyone's work, trying to show he knows what he is doing.",
            "correct": "officious",
            "word": "OFFICIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The downtown district was",
            "part2": "until federal funds were obtained to revitalize it.",
            "correct": "moribund",
            "word": "MORIBUND"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The company received a(n)",
            "part2": "of orders when it started advertising its new product.",
            "correct": "spate",
            "word": "SPATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "youth was unprepared for the sophistication and glamour of big-city life.",
            "correct": "callow or ingenuous",
            "word": "CALLOW"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "salesman called a dozen times trying to convince Jim to buy life insurance.",
            "correct": "pertinacious",
            "word": "PERTINACIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Mark was from Texas, so it was natural that he would receive the",
            "part2": "\"Tex.\"",
            "correct": "sobriquet",
            "word": "SOBRIQUET"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Jim was",
            "part2": "about doing his homework every night, and finally his hard work paid off when he got straight A's.",
            "correct": "sedulous",
            "word": "SEDULOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "natives still live in the Stone Age and know nothing of the civilized world.",
            "correct": "benighted",
            "word": "BENIGHTED"
          },
          {
            "part1": "This plaster is too",
            "part2": "; it crumbles as soon as you put any pressure on it.",
            "correct": "friable",
            "word": "FRIABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The fellow's",
            "part2": "disposition makes him difficult to like; he is too cold and gloomy for most people.",
            "correct": "saturnine",
            "word": "SATURNINE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The aged",
            "part2": "of South American writers was finally rewarded with the Nobel Prize.",
            "correct": "doyen",
            "word": "DOYEN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The priest's",
            "part2": "duties include visiting the sick and burying the dead.",
            "correct": "sacerdotal",
            "word": "SACERDOTAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The editor made",
            "part2": "criticisms of insignificant details in the manuscript.",
            "correct": "captious",
            "word": "CAPTIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The philosopher said that all",
            "part2": "beings shared the same life force that enabled them to perceive their environment.",
            "correct": "sentient",
            "word": "SENTIENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "among these nations is based on mutual respect for each other's sovereignty.",
            "correct": "comity",
            "word": "COMITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "She admired the",
            "part2": "luster of the pearl necklace.",
            "correct": "nacreous",
            "word": "NACREOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Simpson remarked with some",
            "part2": "that if we didn't like it, we could get out.",
            "correct": "asperity",
            "word": "ASPERITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Fame is",
            "part2": "; everyone knows you today, and tomorrow you are forgotten.",
            "correct": "evanescent",
            "word": "EVANESCENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I wish I had the",
            "part2": "to tell my boss what I really think of him.",
            "correct": "temerity",
            "word": "TEMERITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Their refusal to accept the decision of the court was considered",
            "part2": "by many.",
            "correct": "contumacious",
            "word": "CONTUMACIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His ignorance of early German silent films was the one",
            "part2": "in his knowledge of the cinema.",
            "correct": "lacuna",
            "word": "LACUNA"
          },
          {
            "part1": "They bought a beautiful quilted",
            "part2": "for their bed.",
            "correct": "counterpane",
            "word": "COUNTERPANE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The dean expelled the student, citing her moral",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "turpitude",
            "word": "TURPITUDE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Anne is a rather",
            "part2": "correspondent; she uses any excuse to delay writing a letter.",
            "correct": "dilatory",
            "word": "DILATORY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The jewels aroused her",
            "part2": "; she decided she would do anything to possess them.",
            "correct": "cupidity",
            "word": "CUPIDITY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The coach was",
            "part2": "about our chances of winning; he said it was the easiest game on our schedule.",
            "correct": "sanguine",
            "word": "SANGUINE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The introduction is too",
            "part2": "; the author should have cut unnecessary details.",
            "correct": "prolix",
            "word": "PROLIX"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After considerable",
            "part2": "the mathematician was able to solve the problem.",
            "correct": "ratiocination",
            "word": "RATIOCINATION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "heat and redness of her face indicated that she was seriously ill.",
            "correct": "febrile",
            "word": "FEBRILE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The doctor said the proposed operation would",
            "part2": "the cancer.",
            "correct": "extirpate",
            "word": "EXTIRPATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "After the accident the dean issued a(n)",
            "part2": "banning motorcycles from the campus.",
            "correct": "ukase",
            "word": "UKASE"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    },
    {
      "wordsets": [
        {
          "title": "8.10",
          "definitions": {
            "ARCANE": {
              "word": "ARCANE",
              "phonetic": "(ahr-kAn')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "mysterious, esoteric \nARCANE comes from the Latin word for <em>chest</em>; it came to mean <em>secret</em>, <em>hidden</em>, like something hidden away in a chest. In English today it refers to something known only to a few people, and means <em>mysterious</em>. \n\"The wizard said a few words in an ARCANE language and his wand turned into a snake.\" \n\"We felt that there were ARCANE forces in the cave that were beyond our understanding.\" \n\"He spent a lifetime seeking the ARCANE knowledge of the sages of the East.\" \nOn the Pretest, people choose <em>ancient</em>, a wrong answer, more often than <em>mysterious</em>, the right one. This choice may be influenced by the word <em>archaic</em>. Something may be ARCANE because it is ancient, but the emphasis in ARCANE is on secret knowledge, not great age."
            },
            "ABROGATE": {
              "word": "ABROGATE",
              "phonetic": "(ab'-rO-gAt)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to repeal, annul, nullify \nTo ABROGATE is to set aside or do away with. The word is most often used with regard to the actions of a ruler or a court in abolishing a law, treaty, or the like. \n\"The new prime minister's first act was to ABROGATE all treaties with neighboring nations.\" \n\"The lawyer claimed the Supreme Court's recent decisions were, in effect, ABROGATING the Bill of Rights.\" \nABROGATE is also used in a more general way. \n\"Janet refused to ABROGATE her principles for a temporary benefit.\" \n<em>Suspend</em> is a more common choice on the Pretest than the correct answer, <em>repeal). ABROGATE is stronger than <em>suspend</em>; to ABROGATE something is to do away with it completely, not merely to stop it temporarily. \nOther forms of the word: ABROGATION, n."
            },
            "ADDUCE": {
              "word": "ADDUCE",
              "phonetic": "(g-dUs'",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to cite, bring forward for consideration \nSee <em>ad-</em> under Prefixes. The <em>duc</em> root in ADDUCE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>lead</em>; it is also found in such words as <em>induce</em>, <em>deduce</em>, and <em>reduce</em>. To ADDUCE something is to lead it to someone, to offer it or bring it forward. The word is used about facts, examples, or the like brought forward as evidence in a discussion. \n\"The student ADDUCED several reasons in his paper for the decline of the Roman Empire.\" \n\"She ADDUCED many examples as proof of the doctor's incompetence.\" \n\"Since no facts were ADDUCED in support of his argument I must conclude that none exist.\" \n<em>Solve</em> is chosen more frequently than the correct answer, <em>cite</em>, on the Pretest, probably due to the similarity of ADDUCE and <em>deduce</em>."
            },
            "ADUMBRATE": {
              "word": "ADUMBRATE",
              "phonetic": "(ad'-uhm-brAt",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to foreshadow, suggest, prefigure, outline broadly \nThe <em>umbra</em> part of ADUMBRATE means <em>shadow</em> in Latin; this root is also found in the word <em>umbrella</em>. See <em>ad-</em> under Prefixes and <em>-ate1</em> under Suffixes. To ADUMBRATE means to <em>foreshadow</em>, especially in a vague or sketchy way. \n\"These happy times ADUMBRATE the joy we will someday feel when we live here permanently.\" \nIn an extended sense, ADUMBRATE also means to <em>outline broadly</em> or to <em>disclose partially</em>. \n\"His brief synopsis could only ADUMBRATE the complexities of the novel.\" \n\"The project was ADUMBRATED at a meeting last week; the complete proposal runs some two hundred pages.\" \nOther forms of the word: ADUMBRATION, n."
            },
            "CONDIGN": {
              "word": "CONDIGN",
              "phonetic": "(kgn-dln')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "well-deserved, due, merited \nThe <em>dign</em> root in CONDIGN comes from a Latin word meaning <em>worthy</em> or <em>deserving</em>; it is also found in the word <em>dignity</em>. CONDIGN at one time was applied to people and meant <em>deserving</em>. Now its use is limited to punishment and it means <em>well-deserved</em>, <em>fitting</em>. \n\"The public felt that hanging was a CONDIGN punishment for the traitors.\" \n\"The principal tried to decide what would be a CONDIGN punishment for Jimmy's offense.\""
            },
            "CYNOSURE": {
              "word": "CYNOSURE",
              "phonetic": "(sJ'-ng-shUr",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "an attraction, center of attention \nCYNOSURE comes from Greek words meaning \"dog's tail.\" The reference is one to the names for the constellation Ursa Minor, or the Little Dipper. One of the stars in Ursa Minor is Polaris, which is useful in navigation because it is situated close to the north pole in the heavens. Originally a CYNOSURE was something that served as a guide. Now it is used about anything that attracts, a focal point of attention or interest. \n\"The brilliant young actress was the CYNOSURE of the film's opening night.\" \n\"The newly renovated museum became a CYNOSURE for visitors to the city.\" \n<em>Flaw</em> is chosen more frequently than the correct answer on the Pretest, <em>attraction</em>. This choice may be made by people who connect the <em>cyn</em> in CYNOSURE with <em>cynicism</em>, a tendency to seek for flaws."
            },
            "HIERATIC": {
              "word": "HIERATIC",
              "phonetic": "(hl-g-rat'-ik)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "priestly, sacerdotal \nHIERATIC comes from a Greek word meaning <em>sacred</em>, the source of the word <em>hierarchy</em>, which originally referred specifically to religious officials organized into ranks or grades. The Greek word is also the source of the word <em>hieroglyphics</em>, the ancient Egyptian form of writing used by the priestly class. HIERATIC refers to a simplified form of hieroglyphics also used by priests. In general use it means \"of or associated with priests or priestly duties.\" \n\"With a solemn, HIERATIC gesture he bade us depart from the temple.\" \n\"The HIERATIC vestments were folded and carefully put away for next year's ceremony.\" \n\"His HIERATIC duties leave him no time for personal enjoyment.\""
            },
            "INCHOATE": {
              "word": "INCHOATE",
              "phonetic": "(in-kO'-it)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "incipient, just beginning, incomplete \nNote the pronunciation. \nINCHOATE means \"in an early stage of existence; begun, but not fully formed.\" \n\"The theory was not worked out fully until several years later. At this point it was half-formed, INCHOATE.\" \n\"The INCHOATE affection they felt for each other never had a chance to ripen into true love.\" \n\"You should tell them your ideas while the project is still INCHOATE and before it's too late to change anything.\" \n<em>Mixed</em> is a common choice as the meaning of INCHOATE. INCHOATE usually contains the suggestion that, because something is in an early stage, it is disorganized and confused, and this may lead to the choice of <em>mixed</em>."
            },
            "INELUCTABLE": {
              "word": "INELUCTABLE",
              "phonetic": "(in-i-luhk'-tg-bÔøΩI)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "inevitable, inescapable \nThe <em>eluct</em> root in INELUCTABLE comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>struggle out</em>. The basic meaning of INELUCTABLE is \"not able to be struggled out of.\" See <em>in-2</em> under Prefixes and <em>-able</em> under Suffixes. INELUCTABLE is a close synonym of <em>inevitable</em>, although it usually also contains the implication that struggling is useless. \n\"He felt it was his INELUCTABLE destiny to be a loser.\" \n\"Down by forty points in the last quarter, the coach watched the INELUCTABLE approach of defeat with quiet dignity.\" \n\"The conclusion is INELUCTABLE: it was our fault and we will have to pay the damages.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>unreachable</em>, which is virtually an opposite of INELUCTABLE."
            },
            "INTERNECINE": {
              "word": "INTERNECINE",
              "phonetic": "{in-tgr-nes'-En",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "deadly, destructive, characterized by internal struggle \nThe basic meaning of INTERNECINE is \"characterized by great bloodshed.\" It is often applied to battles that are mutually destructive, that cause carnage on both sides. \n\"The encounter between the two hostile tribes led to an INTERNECINE slaughter.\" \nA more recent meaning of INTERNECINE, probably influenced by the word <em>internal</em>, is \"involving struggle within a group.\" This newer meaning contains less of a sense of destruction or bloodshed. \n\"The long INTERNECINE struggle within the party will surely hurt its chances in the general election.\""
            },
            "QUONDAM": {
              "word": "QUONDAM",
              "phonetic": "(kwon'-d;;lm",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "former, onetime \nQUONDAM comes directly from Latin and means \"having been at one time,\" <em>former</em>. It is a somewhat literary word, and would not generally be used in everyday conversation. \n\"Pat discovered that her QUONDAM boyfriend was now saying nasty things about her.\" \n\"This QUONDAM pacifist has now become an ardent supporter of the war.\" \n\"The QUONDAM cigarette smoker has taken up chewing gum instead.\""
            },
            "RECHERCHÉ": {
              "word": "RECHERCHÉ",
              "phonetic": "(r;}-ShÔøΩr-shA')",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "exquisite, rare, exotic, precious \nNote the pronunciation. RECHERCHÉ is from the French, and retains its French pronunciation. \nRECHERCHÉ is related to the English word <em>research</em>. Its literal meaning in French is \"sought after.\" It is usually used in English about something that is sought after because it is rare and, often, elegant. \n\"The jaded aristocrats were forever seeking new and RECHERCHÉ ways to spend their money.\" \n\"She dresses in a RECHERCHÉ style that is unusual but the height of good taste.\" \nRECHERCHÉ often has a negative connotation, suggesting overelegance or an inappropriate straining for a novel effect. \n\"His stories are too RECHERCHÉ for the average reader. They are filled with archaic words, obscure literary allusions, and deliberately inscrutable characters.\" \n<em>Out-of-date</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, due to confusion with the word <em>passé</em>."
            },
            "REDACTION": {
              "word": "REDACTION",
              "phonetic": "(r;;l-dak'-sh;;ln)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "revision, editing, adaptation \nREDACTION is the act of preparing something for publication. The word is generally not used about modern, everyday editorial work, but is a literary term used with reference to works of the past. It can imply either simple editing or a more elaborate revision or adaptation by someone other than the original author. \n\"There were probably many versions of the <em>Iliad</em> and the <em>Odyssey</em> before they underwent a REDACTION that produced the poems we know today.\" \n\"The REDACTION of this material must have presented many difficult decisions to the medieval monks.\" \nA REDACTION is also the work produced as a result of the editing. \n\"The eighteenth-century REDACTIONS of Shakespeare's play were infinitely inferior to the originals.\" \nOther forms of the word: REDACT, v. REDACTOR, n."
            },
            "RETICULATE": {
              "word": "RETICULATE",
              "phonetic": "(ri-tik'-y;;l-lit)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "net-like, forming a network \nRETICULATE and the similar adjectives <em>reticulated</em> and <em>reticular</em> all come from a Latin word meaning \"a little net,\" and all mean \"forming or resembling a network.\" \n\"Through the microscope you could see the RETICULATE pattern of fibers in the paper.\" \n\"The RETICULATE wing was crisscrossed with tiny veins.\""
            },
            "STERTOROUS": {
              "word": "STERTOROUS",
              "phonetic": "(ster'-t;}r-;;ls)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "snoring, characterized by snoring \nSTERTOR is a medical term for a heavy snoring sound made while breathing. STERTOROUS is the adjective from STERTOR. See <em>-ous</em> under Suffixes. STERTOROUS means \"characterized by a loud snoring sound.\" It is often used about breathing. \n\"No one could sleep listening to the STERTOROUS breathing of the asthmatic man.\" \n\"Jane finds the STERTOROUS sounds of her sleeping husband oddly reassuring.\" \nOther forms of the word: STERTOR, n."
            }
          },
          "id": 0,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ARCANE",
                  "answers": [
                    "mysterious",
                    "common",
                    "weird",
                    "complicated",
                    "ancient"
                  ],
                  "word": "ARCANE",
                  "correct": "mysterious"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ABROGATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "repeal",
                    "ratify",
                    "limit",
                    "suspend",
                    "censure"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABROGATE",
                  "correct": "repeal"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ADDUCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "refute",
                    "extend",
                    "solve",
                    "explain",
                    "cite"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADDUCE",
                  "correct": "cite"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to ADUMBRATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "complicate",
                    "recall",
                    "produce",
                    "offend",
                    "foreshadow"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADUMBRATE",
                  "correct": "foreshadow"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONDIGN",
                  "answers": [
                    "extreme",
                    "well-deserved",
                    "unfair",
                    "ritual",
                    "inevitable"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONDIGN",
                  "correct": "well-deserved"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CYNOSURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "attraction",
                    "easy job",
                    "flaw",
                    "proof",
                    "extravaganza"
                  ],
                  "word": "CYNOSURE",
                  "correct": "attraction"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HIERATIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "perverse",
                    "complex",
                    "priestly",
                    "magical",
                    "noble"
                  ],
                  "word": "HIERATIC",
                  "correct": "priestly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCHOATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "mixed",
                    "incompatible",
                    "degenerating",
                    "incipient",
                    "nonexistent"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCHOATE",
                  "correct": "incipient"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INELUCTABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "impossible",
                    "unreachable",
                    "unfortunate",
                    "unchanging",
                    "inevitable"
                  ],
                  "word": "INELUCTABLE",
                  "correct": "inevitable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTERNECINE",
                  "answers": [
                    "healing",
                    "endless",
                    "deadly",
                    "international",
                    "dangerous"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTERNECINE",
                  "correct": "deadly"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "QUONDAM",
                  "answers": [
                    "former",
                    "typical",
                    "temporary",
                    "future",
                    "dear"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUONDAM",
                  "correct": "former"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RECHERCHÉ",
                  "answers": [
                    "common",
                    "exquisite",
                    "out-of-date",
                    "puzzling",
                    "aristocratic"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECHERCHÉ",
                  "correct": "exquisite"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REDACTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "response",
                    "expansion",
                    "decline",
                    "revision",
                    "creation"
                  ],
                  "word": "REDACTION",
                  "correct": "revision"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RETICULATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "spotted",
                    "net-like",
                    "narrow",
                    "specific",
                    "checkered"
                  ],
                  "word": "RETICULATE",
                  "correct": "net-like"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STERTOROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "snoring",
                    "soothing",
                    "abrupt",
                    "hoarse",
                    "alarming"
                  ],
                  "word": "STERTOROUS",
                  "correct": "snoring"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Is arithmetic an ARCANE subject?",
                  "word": "ARCANE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a law be ABROGATED?",
                  "word": "ABROGATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you ADDUCE evidence?",
                  "word": "ADDUCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you ADUMBRATE a theory?",
                  "word": "ADUMBRATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a one-year jail sentence a CONDIGN punishment for littering?",
                  "word": "CONDIGN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it easy to ignore a CYNOSURE?",
                  "word": "CYNOSURE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a cassock a HIERATIC garment?",
                  "word": "HIERATIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is an INCHOATE plan completed?",
                  "word": "INCHOATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is death INELUCTABLE?",
                  "word": "INELUCTABLE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Was the Civil War an INTERNECINE struggle?",
                  "word": "INTERNECINE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is Jimmy Carter a QUONDAM president?",
                  "word": "QUONDAM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a RECHERCHÉ activity be commonplace?",
                  "word": "RECHERCHÉ",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Did Tolstoy write REDACTIONS?",
                  "word": "REDACTION",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are parallel lines RETICULATE?",
                  "word": "RETICULATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Are STERTOROUS sounds mellifluous?",
                  "word": "STERTOROUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "In ARCANE days people used to read books instead of watching television.",
                  "word": "ARCANE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The treaty was temporarily ABROGATED until a couple of provisos could be changed.",
                  "word": "ABROGATE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Ralph could ADDUCE no examples of the man's immorality.",
                  "word": "ADDUCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The thrilling conclusion to the symphony is ADUMBRATED by the initial simple presentation of the theme.",
                  "word": "ADUMBRATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Mary's parents felt her punishment was CONDIGN, even though she complained that it was excessive.",
                  "word": "CONDIGN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Samantha wants to be the CYNOSURE of every party she attends.",
                  "word": "CYNOSURE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The HIERATIC form of writing is indecipherable by lay people.",
                  "word": "HIERATIC",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "These INCHOATE longings for a different way of life eventually led her to change jobs.",
                  "word": "INCHOATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The goal is INELUCTABLE; we will never make it.",
                  "word": "INELUCTABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "An INTERNECINE commission was set up to study the causes of war.",
                  "word": "INTERNECINE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The QUONDAM actress now spends her time writing and directing.",
                  "word": "QUONDAM",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The meal consisted of oxtail soup, buffalo steaks, and other RECHERCHÉ foodstuffs.",
                  "word": "RECHERCHÉ",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The scholar's massive REDACTION of English folk ballads was incomplete at the time of his death.",
                  "word": "REDACTION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "He noticed the RETICULATE pattern of the city streets on the map.",
                  "word": "RETICULATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The patient's STERTOROUS breathing alerted the doctors that something was the matter.",
                  "word": "STERTOROUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "ARCANE",
                  "answers": [
                    "abstruse",
                    "archaic",
                    "occult"
                  ],
                  "word": "ARCANE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ABROGATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "invalidate",
                    "annul",
                    "defer"
                  ],
                  "word": "ABROGATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ADDUCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "allege",
                    "discover",
                    "advance"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADDUCE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ADUMBRATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "prefigure",
                    "muse",
                    "intimate"
                  ],
                  "word": "ADUMBRATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CONDIGN",
                  "answers": [
                    "exceptional",
                    "fitting",
                    "equitable"
                  ],
                  "word": "CONDIGN",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "CYNOSURE",
                  "answers": [
                    "follower",
                    "star",
                    "attraction"
                  ],
                  "word": "CYNOSURE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "HIERATIC",
                  "answers": [
                    "priestly",
                    "mercantile",
                    "ecclesiastical"
                  ],
                  "word": "HIERATIC",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INCHOATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "imperfect",
                    "imbecilic",
                    "immature"
                  ],
                  "word": "INCHOATE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INELUCTABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "inexorable",
                    "ineffable",
                    "inescapable"
                  ],
                  "word": "INELUCTABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "INTERNECINE",
                  "answers": [
                    "lengthy",
                    "internal",
                    "destructive"
                  ],
                  "word": "INTERNECINE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "QUONDAM",
                  "answers": [
                    "onetime",
                    "current",
                    "past"
                  ],
                  "word": "QUONDAM",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RECHERCHÉ",
                  "answers": [
                    "novel",
                    "banal",
                    "unusual"
                  ],
                  "word": "RECHERCHÉ",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REDACTION",
                  "answers": [
                    "creation",
                    "compilation",
                    "adaptation"
                  ],
                  "word": "REDACTION",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "RETICULATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "net-like",
                    "grid-like",
                    "box-like"
                  ],
                  "word": "RETICULATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STERTOROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "ferocious",
                    "loud",
                    "harsh"
                  ],
                  "word": "STERTOROUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "8.11",
          "definitions": {
            "SUBORN": {
              "word": "SUBORN",
              "phonetic": "(sg-born')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to bribe, instigate, induce to commit \nTo SUBORN a person is to induce him or her, by secret or illegal means, to commit a crime. SUBORN is particularly used with reference to perjury. \n\"The mobster SUBORNED the witness to change his testimony by buying him a new car.\" \n\"The spy SUBORNED the clerk to remove the secret documents from the file.\" \n\"Three of the jurors were SUBORNED by the unscrupulous defense attorney and agreed to vote 'Not Guilty' for a fee.\" \n<em>Replace</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest, possibly because of a vague resemblance be- tween SUBORN and <em>substitute</em>. \nOther forms of the word: SUBORNATION, n."
            },
            "TENDENTIOUS": {
              "word": "TENDENTIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(ten-den'-shgs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "biased, not impartial \nTENDENTIOUS is an adjective from the noun <em>tendency</em>. A person or thing that is TENDENTIOUS has a tendency to support a particular cause or point of view, is not objective. \n\"She wrote a TENDENTIOUS article praising the mayor's record and ridiculing his opponent.\" \n\"I thought the politician was rather TENDENTIOUS in his speech-mentioning all the good things about his party and ignoring its weaknesses.\" \n\"Advertisements on TV are at best TENDENTIOUS, at worst deliberately misleading.\" \n<em>Pompous</em> and <em>misleading</em> are the common mistakes. <em>Pompous</em> is probably chosen due to confusion with <em>pretentious</em>. Something that it TENDENTIOUS may also be misleading, because the truth is not as important as promoting a point of view. The emphasis, however, is on this lack of impartiality."
            },
            "TENEBROUS": {
              "word": "TENEBROUS",
              "phonetic": "(ten'-g-brgs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "gloomy, dark, murky \nTENEBROUS is a somewhat literary term meaning \"dark and gloomy.\" It can be used about actual physical darkness: \n\"There were living creatures even in the TENEBROUS depths of the cave.\" \nOr it can be used in a figurative sense: \n\"The TENEBROUS atmosphere created by the Gothic novel was both mysterious and frightening.\" \n<em>Flimsy</em> and <em>stubborn</em> are the most commonly chosen wrong answers. <em>Flimsy</em> is probably chosen because TENEBROUS looks vaguely like <em>tenuous</em>; <em>stubborn</em> because it looks like <em>tenacious</em>."
            },
            "STENTORIAN": {
              "word": "STENTORIAN",
              "phonetic": "(sten-tor'-E-gn)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "loud, earsplitting, resounding \nSTENTOR was a Greek warrior in the <em>Iliad</em> famous for his loud, powerful voice. STENTORIAN is the adjective from STENTOR. It is usually applied to voices and means <em>extremely loud</em>. \n\"In a STENTORIAN voice the sergeant shouted out his orders to the troops.\" \n\"The orator's STENTORIAN tones could be heard in every part of the huge hall.\" \n\"Cindy didn't know how to whisper; when she tried to speak softly her voice was still STENTORIAN.\""
            },
            "SALIENT": {
              "word": "SALIENT",
              "phonetic": "(sA'-IE-gnt)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "prominent, striking, conspicuous \nSALIENT comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>leap</em>. SALIENTIA is the scientific name for the group of animals that includes frogs and toads. In English SALIENT sometimes has the basic meaning of <em>leaping</em> or <em>jumping</em>, particularly with reference to animals. Commonly, however, the word is used in a figurative sense of things that \"leap out\" at you, that are prominent and significant. \n\"The most SALIENT characteristic of the company's salespeople is their aggressiveness.\" \n\"The one SALIENT fact is that someone is dead; nothing else is important.\" \n\"The critic said that the SALIENT feature of television news is its superficiality.\" \n<em>Crucial</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer. SALIENT usually implies that there is some importance and significance to the thing it describes, but the emphasis is on its prominence. \nOther forms of the word: SALIENCE, n."
            },
            "OPPROBRIOUS": {
              "word": "OPPROBRIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(::)-prO'-brE-::)s)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "shameful, disgraceful, scurrilous, abusive \nOPPROBRIUM is disgrace that results from shameful conduct. \n\"The public OPPROBRIUM was so great following the scandal that the president was forced to resign in disgrace.\" \nOPPROBRIOUS is the adjective from OPPROBRIUM. When used about language, it means \"expressing OPPROBRIUM.\" \n\"She made OPPROBRIOUS comments about businessmen who don't care about the safety of their products.\" \nIn general, OPPROBRIOUS means \"deserving OPPROBRIUM,\" <em>shameful</em>, <em>infamous</em>. \n\"Your OPPROBRIOUS conduct must be condemned by every right-thinking person.\" \nOther forms of the word: OPPROBRIUM, n."
            },
            "AVER": {
              "word": "AVER",
              "phonetic": "(J-ver')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to assert, affirm, declare \nThe <em>ver</em> part of AVER comes from a Latin word meaning <em>true</em>; it is also found in such words as <em>verify</em> and <em>verdict</em>. To AVER something is to declare confidently that it is true. \n\"The governor AVERRED that nothing could make him raise taxes.\" \n\"The coach AVERRED that his team would win the championship easily.\" \n\"Several witnesses heard him AVER that he would get even if it was the last thing he did.\" \nOn the Pretest, <em>deny</em>, an exact opposite, is chosen more frequently than the correct answer, <em>assert</em>. People who choose <em>deny</em> are familiar with AVER, but perhaps haven't seen it often enough to remember whether to AVER something is to say it is true or say it is false."
            },
            "LANGUISH": {
              "word": "LANGUISH",
              "phonetic": "(lang'-gwish)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to grow weak, droop, fade, pine \nLANGUISH, <em>languor</em>, and <em>languid</em> all come from a Latin word meaning to <em>feel faint</em>. The basic meaning of LANGUISH is to grow weak, to lose strength. \n\"Without water the plants quickly began to LANGUISH.\" \nLANGUISH also means \"to continue in a state of suffering or neglect.\" \n\"He LANGUISHED in prison for ten years before finally being released.\" \nParticularly in its participial form, LANGUISHING, the word is used about an affected attitude of weariness or wistfulness. \n\"With a LANGUISHING sigh she said that if only she could get to Moscow, everything would be all right.\""
            },
            "DESCRY": {
              "word": "DESCRY",
              "phonetic": "(di-skrl')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to notice, discern, espy \nTo DESCRY means to <em>catch sight of</em>. The word implies keen vision that allows one to see something despite great distance or other hindrance. \n\"The townspeople could just barely DESCRY the masts of the ships on the horizon.\" \n\"The lookout DESCRIED the Indians moving stealthily through the trees.\" \nDESCRY can also be used in a figurative sense about anything that is discovered by keen mental observation. \n\"She thought she DESCRIED a pattern in the murderer's behavior.\" \n<em>Fear</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer, perhaps because of the <em>cry</em> part of DESCRY."
            },
            "ENCOMIUM": {
              "word": "ENCOMIUM",
              "phonetic": "(en-kO'-mE-Jm)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "a eulogy, tribute, panegyric \nAn ENCOMIUM is a formal, usually public, expression of praise. The plural of ENCOMIUM is either ENCOMIA or ENCOMIUMS. \n\"The president's ENCOMIUM of basic American values stirred the hearts of his listeners.\" \n\"Despite all these ENCOMIA the returning hero remained humble.\" \n\"Moved by the ENCOMIUM to Martin Luther King, Jr., Jack resolved to learn more about the man.\" \n<em>Reward</em> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer. An ENCOMIUM can be thought of as a kind of reward, but it is specifically an expression of praise."
            },
            "BALEFUL": {
              "word": "BALEFUL",
              "phonetic": "(bAl'-fal)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "ominous, sinister, malign, dire \nBALE is a poetic or archaic word meaning <em>harm</em> or <em>disaster</em>. Something that it BALEFUL threatens evil or disaster, often because it is evil itself. \n\"The teacher's BALEFUL look convinced John that he should start behaving.\" \n\"The economists' BALEFUL predictions of a worldwide depression never came true.\" \n\"Mary's parents feared the BALEFUL influence the drifter had over her.\" \n<em>Unhappy</em> is by far the most common choice on the Pretest. Something that is BALEFUL can cause unhappiness, but it is not necessarily unhappy."
            },
            "LIMPID": {
              "word": "LIMPID",
              "phonetic": "(lim'-pid)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "clear, transparent, translucent \nLIMPID means \"having the transparent clearness of water.\" It is often used in an extended sense about writing that is clear and readily intelligible. It sometimes also suggests calmness and serenity. \n\"The LIMPID water of the lake allowed us to see all the way to the bottom.\" \n\"The LIMPID grace of his essays is unmatched in English prose.\" \n\"No one could fail to be impressed by the nun's LIMPID, serene holiness.\" \nMost people choose <em>soft</em> as the meaning of LIMPID, obviously misled by the <em>limp</em> part of the word. \nOther forms of the word: LIMPIDITY, n."
            },
            "TRADUCE": {
              "word": "TRADUCE",
              "phonetic": "(tr:}-dUs'",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to slander, defame, malign, libel \nThe common root <em>duce</em>, found in such words as <em>reduce</em>, <em>produce</em>, and <em>induce</em>, means to <em>lead</em>. See <em>tra-</em> under Prefixes. TRADUCE originally was used as a synonym of transport. It then came to mean \"leading across as a spectacle,\" and finally reached its current meaning, \"to speak evil of,\" to <em>slander</em>. \n\"The book TRADUCES a great man with its unsupported accusations and sly innuendoes.\" \n\"The politician was not above planting false stories in the newspaper that TRADUCED his rivals.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>deceive</em>, probably because of confusion with <em>seduce</em>. To TRADUCE a person is not to deceive him, but to speak evil of him. This might deceive others, but it would not deceive the person being TRADUCED. \nOther forms of the word: TRADUCEMENT, n."
            },
            "VENIAL": {
              "word": "VENIAL",
              "phonetic": "(vE'-nE-::)1",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "excusable, insignificant, pardonable, forgivable \nVENIAL comes from a Latin word for <em>forgiveness</em> and is related to Venus, the Roman goddess of love. VENIAL is used about faults or sins that are not serious enough to require punishment, that are easily pardonable. In Roman Catholic theology, VENIAL sins are contrasted with mortal sins. A VENIAL sin is a minor offense against divine law, while a mortal sin is a serious offense that merits eternal punishment. \n\"These VENIAL faults are not worth punishing; just explain to him what he did wrong.\" \n\"Sheila thought her offense was VENIAL, but the dean felt it merited expulsion.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is <em>immoral</em>, a word that might be used in the same situation as VENIAL. A VENIAL sin or offense might be immoral, but mainly it is excusable, insignificant."
            },
            "PRODIGAL": {
              "word": "PRODIGAL",
              "phonetic": "(prod'-i-g:)I)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "extravagant, wasteful; lavish, profuse \nPRODIGAL means \"given to extravagance.\" The word generally suggests waste and recklessness. \n\"Unless you check your PRODIGAL habits of spending you will soon be ruined.\" \nIt does not always have a totally negative connotation, however, and may mean <em>lavish</em>, <em>profuse</em>. \n\"The kind theater critic was PRODIGAL in his praise of the young performers.\" \n\"That spring the PRODIGAL earth brought forth flowers in incredible abundance.\" \nThree times as many people pick <em>wandering</em> as pick the correct answer, <em>extravagant</em>, on the Pretest. These people have been misled by the parable of the prodigal son. The PRODIGAL son wanders far from home and wastes his money. PRODIGAL refers to the wasting, not the wandering. \nOther forms of the word: PRODIGALITY, n."
            }
          },
          "id": 1,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "to SUBORN",
                  "answers": [
                    "jail",
                    "replace",
                    "bribe",
                    "swear",
                    "trick"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUBORN",
                  "correct": "bribe"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TENDENTIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "pompous",
                    "biased",
                    "fair",
                    "necessary",
                    "misleading"
                  ],
                  "word": "TENDENTIOUS",
                  "correct": "biased"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TENEBROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "glowing",
                    "flimsy",
                    "stubborn",
                    "gloomy",
                    "invisible"
                  ],
                  "word": "TENEBROUS",
                  "correct": "gloomy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STENTORIAN",
                  "answers": [
                    "solemn",
                    "strict",
                    "fierce",
                    "proud",
                    "loud"
                  ],
                  "word": "STENTORIAN",
                  "correct": "loud"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SALIENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "hidden",
                    "crucial",
                    "unexpected",
                    "serious",
                    "prominent"
                  ],
                  "word": "SALIENT",
                  "correct": "prominent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OPPROBRIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "shameful",
                    "fitting",
                    "solemn",
                    "cruel",
                    "mysterious"
                  ],
                  "word": "OPPROBRIOUS",
                  "correct": "shameful"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to AVER",
                  "answers": [
                    "deny",
                    "imply",
                    "assert",
                    "wish",
                    "demand"
                  ],
                  "word": "AVER",
                  "correct": "assert"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to LANGUISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "feel pain",
                    "lie down",
                    "grow weak",
                    "give in",
                    "worry"
                  ],
                  "word": "LANGUISH",
                  "correct": "grow weak"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to DESCRY",
                  "answers": [
                    "notice",
                    "expect",
                    "search for",
                    "fear",
                    "overlook"
                  ],
                  "word": "DESCRY",
                  "correct": "notice"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENCOMIUM",
                  "answers": [
                    "accusation",
                    "eulogy",
                    "reward",
                    "debate",
                    "burden"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENCOMIUM",
                  "correct": "eulogy"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BALEFUL",
                  "answers": [
                    "unhappy",
                    "sympathetic",
                    "grotesque",
                    "ominous",
                    "pompous"
                  ],
                  "word": "BALEFUL",
                  "correct": "ominous"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LIMPID",
                  "answers": [
                    "muddy",
                    "cold",
                    "soft",
                    "sweet",
                    "clear"
                  ],
                  "word": "LIMPID",
                  "correct": "clear"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to TRADUCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "slander",
                    "glorify",
                    "deceive",
                    "ruin",
                    "mock"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRADUCE",
                  "correct": "slander"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VENIAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "serious",
                    "bodily",
                    "excusable",
                    "humble",
                    "immoral"
                  ],
                  "word": "VENIAL",
                  "correct": "excusable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRODIGAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "ungrateful",
                    "wandering",
                    "sorry",
                    "exceptional",
                    "extravagant"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRODIGAL",
                  "correct": "extravagant"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a senator be SUBORNED?",
                  "word": "SUBORN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should a scientific article be TENDENTIOUS?",
                  "word": "TENDENTIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Should an office be TENEBROUS?",
                  "word": "TENEBROUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a diminutive person have a STENTORIAN voice?",
                  "word": "STENTORIAN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is humor a SALIENT feature of a Marx Brothers movie?",
                  "word": "SALIENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is immorality OPPROBRIOUS?",
                  "word": "OPPROBRIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a criminal AVER that he is innocent?",
                  "word": "AVER",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a conversation LANGUISH?",
                  "word": "LANGUISH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can you DESCRY something with a microscope?",
                  "word": "DESCRY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a person be likely to receive an ENCOMIUM for deplorable behavior?",
                  "word": "ENCOMIUM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would a BALEFUL look betray a dislike for someone?",
                  "word": "BALEFUL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a cloud LIMPID?",
                  "word": "LIMPID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is it shameful to TRADUCE someone?",
                  "word": "TRADUCE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is depravity a VENIAL fault?",
                  "word": "VENIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a spendthrift PRODIGAL?",
                  "word": "PRODIGAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "They accused the government of SUBORNING the witness with the promise of a job if he cooperated.",
                  "word": "SUBORN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We thought the travel agent was being TENDENTIOUS in describing nothing but the good points of the island.",
                  "word": "TENDENTIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Through the foggy, TENEBROUS London night Holmes and Watson pursued the criminal.",
                  "word": "TENEBROUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The workers covered their ears when the boss issued his STENTORIAN commands.",
                  "word": "STENTORIAN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Jim's most SALIENT trait is an inability to accept criticism.",
                  "word": "SALIENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The boss thought the workers' attitude was OPPROBRIOUS: they didn't care about doing a good job.",
                  "word": "OPPROBRIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The defendant AVERRED being with the deceased on the night of the murder.",
                  "word": "AVER",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "His story LANGUISHED for months on the editor's desk before it was finally read.",
                  "word": "LANGUISH",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Despite the camouflage we managed to DESCRY the enemy's tanks.",
                  "word": "DESCRY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The juvenile delinquent paid no attention to the judge's stern ENCOMIUMS.",
                  "word": "ENCOMIUM",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Their BALEFUL marriage finally ended in divorce.",
                  "word": "BALEFUL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The flag hung LIMPID in the dead air.",
                  "word": "LIMPID",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The con man TRADUCED the woman into giving him her life savings.",
                  "word": "TRADUCE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The preacher condemned the movie as VENIAL and depraved.",
                  "word": "VENIAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The PRODIGAL explorer never spent more than six months in the same place.",
                  "word": "PRODIGAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "SUBORN",
                  "answers": [
                    "infuse",
                    "incite",
                    "instigate"
                  ],
                  "word": "SUBORN",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TENDENTIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "partial",
                    "obstinate",
                    "predisposed"
                  ],
                  "word": "TENDENTIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TENEBROUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "murky",
                    "mysterious",
                    "mutinous"
                  ],
                  "word": "TENEBROUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "STENTORIAN",
                  "answers": [
                    "voluble",
                    "strident",
                    "raucous"
                  ],
                  "word": "STENTORIAN",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SALIENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "conspicuous",
                    "diligent",
                    "manifest"
                  ],
                  "word": "SALIENT",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OPPROBRIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "harsh",
                    "odious",
                    "ignominious"
                  ],
                  "word": "OPPROBRIOUS",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "AVER",
                  "answers": [
                    "avow",
                    "affirm",
                    "command"
                  ],
                  "word": "AVER",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LANGUISH",
                  "answers": [
                    "weaken",
                    "droop",
                    "dry"
                  ],
                  "word": "LANGUISH",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "DESCRY",
                  "answers": [
                    "discern",
                    "recall",
                    "behold"
                  ],
                  "word": "DESCRY",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "ENCOMIUM",
                  "answers": [
                    "eulogy",
                    "tribute",
                    "impetus"
                  ],
                  "word": "ENCOMIUM",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "BALEFUL",
                  "answers": [
                    "deplorable",
                    "foreboding",
                    "maleficent"
                  ],
                  "word": "BALEFUL",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "LIMPID",
                  "answers": [
                    "icy",
                    "transparent",
                    "clear"
                  ],
                  "word": "LIMPID",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "TRADUCE",
                  "answers": [
                    "violate",
                    "vilify",
                    "vituperate"
                  ],
                  "word": "TRADUCE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VENIAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "trivial",
                    "forgivable",
                    "casual"
                  ],
                  "word": "VENIAL",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PRODIGAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "benevolent",
                    "wasteful",
                    "overgenerous"
                  ],
                  "word": "PRODIGAL",
                  "correct": "0"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "title": "8.12",
          "definitions": {
            "EQUABLE": {
              "word": "EQUABLE",
              "phonetic": "(ek'-w;-b;}I",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "even-tempered, steady, unvarying \nEQUABLE comes from the Latin word for <em>equal</em>. EQUABLE's general meaning is <em>steady</em>, <em>uniform</em>. \n\"He wants an EQUABLE climate where he won't have to worry about extremes in temperature.\" \nIt is most often applied to a person's temperament or an expression of it; in this sense it means <em>even-tempered</em>, <em>tranquil</em>. \n\"We need someone with an EQUABLE disposition-someone who won't fly off the handle if something goes wrong.\" \n\"The teacher's EQUABLE manner in turn made her students relaxed and happy.\" \nFair-minded is a more common choice in the Pretest than the correct answer, <em>even-tempered</em>, due to confusion between EQUABLE and <em>equitable</em>."
            },
            "APOCRYPHAL": {
              "word": "APOCRYPHAL",
              "phonetic": "(;-pok'-r;-fal)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "spurious, counterfeit, of doubtful authenticity \nThe APOCRYPHA are early Christian writings of doubtful authenticity or authorship. The word has also come to be used about any writings of questionable authenticity. APOCRYPHAL is the adjective from APOCRYPHA. Although the emphasis of the word is on the trustworthiness of the source of something, it also often suggests that the thing itself is untrue. \n\"This story is probably APOCRYPHAL, although it has been attributed to Mark Twain.\" \n\"These APOCRYPHAL poems were once thought to have been written by Homer.\" \n\"He told an anecdote, possibly APOCRYPHAL, about George Washington's kindness to his mother.\" \n<em>Mysterious</em> is a more common choice than the correct synonym, <em>spurious</em>, perhaps because of the mysterious nature of the origins of the APOCRYPHA, and perhaps because of a confusion with the Apocalypse, the book of the Bible which describes the future in mysterious symbols. \nOther forms of the word: APOCRYPHA, n."
            },
            "REFULGENT": {
              "word": "REFULGENT",
              "phonetic": "(ri-fuhl",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "gleaming, radiant, brilliant \nThe <em>fulg</em> part of REFULGENT comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>shine</em>. This root is also found in the English word <em>effulgent</em>, which has much the same meaning as REFULGENT. REFULGENT means \"shining brightly, brilliantly resplendent.\" \n\"Her REFULGENT jewels glittered in the candle- light.\" \n\"The REFULGENT new cars gleamed as the salesman led us through the lot.\" \n<em>Swelling</em> is by far the most commonly chosen wrong answer, probably due to the similarity of the <em>fulge</em> sound to the word <em>bulge</em>. \nOther forms of the word: REFULGENCE, n. REFULGENCY, n."
            },
            "MERETRICIOUS": {
              "word": "MERETRICIOUS",
              "phonetic": "(mer-g-trish'-gs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "tawdry, gaudy; insincere, spurious \nMERETRICIOUS comes from the Latin word for <em>prostitute</em>, which in turn comes from a word meaning to <em>earn</em>, also the source of the word <em>merit</em>. The basic meaning of MERETRICIOUS is \"like a prostitute.\" In an extended sense, MERETRICIOUS refers to anything that is attractive in a cheap or deceitful way or that is based on insincerity. \n\"The critic decried the MERETRICIOUS appeal of the situation comedy, which was based on slapstick and vulgarity rather than on sophisticated humor.\" \n\"Her beauty was MERETRICIOUS, a product of heavy makeup and flattering camera angles.\" \n\"His arguments are MERETRICIOUS; they are superficially plausible, but in fact they are cynical attempts to manipulate our emotions.\" \n<em>Exemplary</em> is twice as popular as the correct answer, <em>tawdry</em>, on the Pretest, probably due to the influence of the words <em>merit</em> and <em>meritorious</em>."
            },
            "IMPRECATION": {
              "word": "IMPRECATION",
              "phonetic": "(im-prg-kA'-shgn)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "cursing; a curse \nTo IMPRECATE is to call down curses upon. IMPRECATION is the act of cursing or the curse itself. \n\"IMPRECATION is not a socially acceptable method of displaying anger.\" \n\"Muttering IMPRECATIONS under his breath, the driver sat and fumed in the heavy traffic.\" \nMore people choose <em>accusation</em> on the Pretest than the correct answer, <em>cursing</em>. This may be due to the similarity of the words IMPRECATION and <em>implication</em>, or <em>accusation</em> may be chosen because both accusations and cursing may be the result of anger. \nOther forms of the word: IMPRECATE, v."
            },
            "VITIATE": {
              "word": "VITIATE",
              "phonetic": "(vish'-E-At)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to spoil, contaminate, corrupt, debase, pervert \nBoth VITIATE and the more common word <em>vice</em> come ultimately from a Latin word meaning <em>defeat</em> or <em>fault</em>. To VITIATE something is to make it defective, faulty, or impure. The word is used about physical objects like the air and, more frequently, about abstractions like morality. \n\"His insane jealousy VITIATED their otherwise loving relationship.\" \n\"The novel is VITIATED by the author's obvious hatred of male characters.\" \n\"Their effectiveness as a team was VITIATED by their mutual dislike.\" \n<em>Cleanse</em> is more than twice as popular as the correct answer on the Pretest, <em>spoil</em>. This may be due to words like <em>obviate</em> and <em>alleviate</em>, which sound like VITIATE, but have almost the opposite meaning. \nOther forms of the word: VITIATION, n."
            },
            "PROTEAN": {
              "word": "PROTEAN",
              "phonetic": "(prO'-tE-:;m",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "changeable, variable, versatile \nIn Greek mythology, PROTEUS was a sea god who could assume different shapes at will. PROTEAN is the adjective from PROTEUS. It is used about both physical objects and abstract qualities that can readily take on different shapes or appearances. \n\"The artist loved the sea's PROTEAN quality: it was never the same color or shape twice.\" \n\"Her PROTEAN disposition makes her difficult to live with: you never know when she will be happy or sad or angry.\" \n\"The PROTEAN actor is capable of transforming himself instantly into any of a hundred different characters.\" \nMost people pick <em>powerful</em> as the meaning of PROTEAN. Perhaps they are thinking of <em>herculean</em>, another adjective derived from Greek mythology. Or perhaps there is some confusion with the noun <em>protein</em>."
            },
            "PERSPICUOUS": {
              "word": "PERSPICUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(per-spik'-yU-gs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "clear, lucid \nPERSPICUOUS is used about style or mode of expression and means \"easy to understand,\" <em>clear</em>. Like the similar word <em>conspicuous</em>, it comes originally from a Latin word meaning to <em>see</em>. \n\"His essays are noted for a PERSPICUOUS style that makes them easy to read and understand.\" \n\"The speaker was not at all PERSPICUOUS in his remarks; at times it seemed as if he was purposely trying to confuse us.\" \n<em>Hidden</em> is the most commonly chosen answer on the Pretest; perhaps people who are unfamiliar with PERSPICUOUS guess that it is an opposite of <em>conspicuous</em>. \nOther forms of the word: PERSPICUITY, n."
            },
            "OBVIATE": {
              "word": "OBVIATE",
              "phonetic": "(ob'-vE-At)",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to prevent, make unnecessary \nTo OBVIATE something is to anticipate it and make it unnecessary, for example by removing the conditions under which it may occur. \n\"Good nutrition now will OBVIATE the need for expensive medical treatments later on.\" \n\"Putting your valuables in the hotel safe OBVIATES the risk of theft.\" \n\"Careful planning and attention to detail will OBVIATE the confusion generally associated with large conventions.\" \nOBVIATE comes from the same Latin root as <em>obvious</em>. The similarity of the words probably explains why <em>reveal</em> is the most popular choice on the Pretest. Despite the similar derivations, however, OBVIATE has a very different meaning from <em>obvious</em>."
            },
            "FULSOME": {
              "word": "FULSOME",
              "phonetic": "(ful'sgm)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "sickening, repulsive, disgustingly excessive \nFULSOME comes from the word <em>full</em> and the suffix <em>-some</em>, which means \"tending to be.\" \nFULSOME originally meant <em>abundant</em>, but in modern usage it has come to mean <em>grossly excessive</em> and is used about something like praise that can be overdone to the point of being sickening. \n\"The young queen quickly tired of the FULSOME compliments of the courtiers.\" \n\"The critic's FULSOME praise of the trashy movie suggested that he had been bought off by its press agents.\" \n\"The introduction to the book was admiring but not FULSOME; it said the book was not without flaws, but deserved our attention.\" \nFULSOME is often seen without this negative connotation, with a meaning close to its original sense of <em>abundant</em>. This probably accounts for the popularity of <em>pleasant</em> as an answer on the Pretest. This use of FULSOME, however, is generally considered to be incorrect."
            },
            "SCURRILOUS": {
              "word": "SCURRILOUS",
              "phonetic": "(skuhr'-ÔøΩlÔøΩs",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "abusive, foul-mouthed, vituperative \nSCURRILOUS means \"given to or containing coarse, abusive language.\" \n\"Certain SCURRILOUS people scrawled obscenities all over the wall.\" \n\"The mayor said he wouldn't dignify his opponent's SCURRILOUS charges with a reply.\" \n\"The speaker attacked organized religion in such SCURRILOUS terms that we were deeply offended.\" \nMore people choose <em>sneaky</em> as the meaning of SCURRILOUS on the Pretest than choose the correct synonym, <em>abusive</em>, perhaps because of the unrelated verb to <em>scurry</em>. \nOther forms of the word: SCURRILITY, n."
            },
            "IMPUGN": {
              "word": "IMPUGN",
              "phonetic": "(im-pyUn')",
              "pos": "v.",
              "deftext": "to contradict, refute, call into question, malign \nThe <em>pugn</em> part of IMPUGN comes from a Latin word meaning <em>fight</em>; it is also found in the word <em>pugnacious</em>. IMPUGN has the pronunciation it does because it comes into English through French. IMPUGN originally meant to <em>attack physically</em>. Now it means \"to attack with words,\" to criticize as false or call into question. \n\"How dare you IMPUGN my honesty! I have never lied in my life.\" \n\"She IMPUGNED his motives, saying he was helping her in hopes of a reward.\" \n\"The boss IMPUGNED Bill's work on the project, calling it of questionable value.\" \n<em>Suspect</em> is the most frequently marked wrong answer. IMPUGN goes one step further than <em>suspect</em>; one who IMPUGNS not only suspects but actively calls into question."
            },
            "OBLOQUY": {
              "word": "OBLOQUY",
              "phonetic": "(ob'-1ÔøΩ-kwE)",
              "pos": "n.",
              "deftext": "abuse, vituperation, calumny; disgrace, dishonor, ignominy \nOBLOQUY comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>speak against</em>; the <em>loqu</em> root is also found in <em>loquacious</em>. OBLOQUY has two related meanings. The first is \"abusive and defamatory language,\" <em>calumny</em>. \n\"The hostile newspapers subjected the mayor to continuous OBLOQUY.\" \nOBLOQUY is also the disgrace and ill repute of a person who has been subjected to this abusive language. \n\"He was never able to live down the OBLOQUY of having been called a traitor.\" \n\"After her release from prison the confessed child-murderer lived in OBLOQUY the rest of her days.\""
            },
            "EXIGUOUS": {
              "word": "EXIGUOUS",
              "phonetic": "(eg-zig'-yU-ÔøΩs)",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "scanty, meager, skimpy \nEXIGUOUS means \"small in amount or size,\" <em>scanty</em>. It comes from a Latin word meaning to <em>weigh</em> or <em>measure</em>; the idea is of something that is measured and found lacking. \n\"His EXIGUOUS income is barely enough to support one person, let alone two.\" \n\"The prisoners were forced to live on an EXIGUOUS diet of bread and water.\" \n\"Their rather EXIGUOUS ranks were depleted still further when three students decided to leave the team.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXIGUITY, n."
            },
            "OTIOSE": {
              "word": "OTIOSE",
              "phonetic": "(O'-shE-Os",
              "pos": "adj.",
              "deftext": "idle, indolent; ineffective, futile, useless \nOTIOSE has two related meanings. The first is <em>idle</em>, <em>at leisure</em>. \n\"He condemned these OTIOSE young men who had never done a good day's work in their lives.\" \nFrom this OTIOSE has come to mean \"lacking in effectiveness,\" <em>futile</em> or <em>functionless</em>. \n\"The announcer felt that words were OTIOSE at a moment of such high drama, so he said nothing.\" \n\"The consultant said the whole department was OTIOSE and should be terminated.\" \nOther forms of the word: OTIOSITY, n."
            }
          },
          "id": 2,
          "exercises": [
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "EQUABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "irascible",
                    "fair-minded",
                    "pliable",
                    "even-tempered",
                    "rational"
                  ],
                  "word": "EQUABLE",
                  "correct": "even-tempered"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "APOCRYPHAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "mysterious",
                    "ancient",
                    "spurious",
                    "inspired",
                    "deceitful"
                  ],
                  "word": "APOCRYPHAL",
                  "correct": "spurious"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REFULGENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "disgusting",
                    "gleaming",
                    "swelling",
                    "echoing",
                    "exciting"
                  ],
                  "word": "REFULGENT",
                  "correct": "gleaming"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MERETRICIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "exemplary",
                    "elegant",
                    "tawdry",
                    "auspicious",
                    "fiendish"
                  ],
                  "word": "MERETRICIOUS",
                  "correct": "tawdry"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPRECATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "praise",
                    "involvement",
                    "cursing",
                    "accusation",
                    "shouting"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPRECATION",
                  "correct": "cursing"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to VITIATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "spoil",
                    "cleanse",
                    "soften",
                    "remove",
                    "transform"
                  ],
                  "word": "VITIATE",
                  "correct": "spoil"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROTEAN",
                  "answers": [
                    "powerful",
                    "invisible",
                    "nautical",
                    "growing",
                    "changeable"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROTEAN",
                  "correct": "changeable"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERSPICUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "hidden",
                    "difficult",
                    "uncommon",
                    "famous",
                    "clear"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERSPICUOUS",
                  "correct": "clear"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to OBVIATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "conceal",
                    "reveal",
                    "change",
                    "prevent",
                    "reduce"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBVIATE",
                  "correct": "prevent"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FULSOME",
                  "answers": [
                    "pleasant",
                    "sickening",
                    "flowery",
                    "important",
                    "deceitful"
                  ],
                  "word": "FULSOME",
                  "correct": "sickening"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SCURRILOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "whining",
                    "sneaky",
                    "pompous",
                    "cowardly",
                    "abusive"
                  ],
                  "word": "SCURRILOUS",
                  "correct": "abusive"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "to IMPUGN",
                  "answers": [
                    "suggest",
                    "protect",
                    "contradict",
                    "despise",
                    "suspect"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPUGN",
                  "correct": "contradict"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBLOQUY",
                  "answers": [
                    "abuse",
                    "commendation",
                    "conference",
                    "dispute",
                    "stupidity"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBLOQUY",
                  "correct": "abuse"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXIGUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "abundant",
                    "far away",
                    "unnecessary",
                    "scanty",
                    "lost"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXIGUOUS",
                  "correct": "scanty"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OTIOSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "useful",
                    "idle",
                    "forceful",
                    "uncertain",
                    "ignorant"
                  ],
                  "word": "OTIOSE",
                  "correct": "idle"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-one",
              "id": "pretest"
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a rebellious person have an EQUABLE temperament?",
                  "word": "EQUABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is the Declaration of Independence APOCRYPHAL?",
                  "word": "APOCRYPHAL",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could a chandelier be REFULGENT?",
                  "word": "REFULGENT",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is fake jewelry MERETRICIOUS?",
                  "word": "MERETRICIOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do most people find IMPRECATIONS shameful?",
                  "word": "IMPRECATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would extravagant spending VITIATE an attempt to economize?",
                  "word": "VITIATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Can a personality be PROTEAN?",
                  "word": "PROTEAN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Does a PERSPICUOUS writing style tend to be overly wordy?",
                  "word": "PERSPICUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do sterilized needles OBVIATE the danger of infection?",
                  "word": "OBVIATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could too much flattery be FULSOME?",
                  "word": "FULSOME",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would SCURRILOUS language be acceptable in a classroom?",
                  "word": "SCURRILOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Would you IMPUGN someone's work by calling it worthless?",
                  "word": "IMPUGN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Do pardonable offenses deserve OBLOQUY?",
                  "word": "OBLOQUY",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Could excessive praise be considered EXIGUOUS?",
                  "word": "EXIGUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Is a diligent student OTIOSE?",
                  "word": "OTIOSE",
                  "correct": "false"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 1
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "One of the heirs complained that the division of the inheritance wasn't EQUABLE.",
                  "word": "EQUABLE",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The book was full of APOCRYPHAL tales that sounded true but had no reliable source.",
                  "word": "APOCRYPHAL",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The man's REFULGENT belly made him look a bit like Santa Claus.",
                  "word": "REFULGENT",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The principal gave Jane an award for MERETRICIOUS conduct.",
                  "word": "MERETRICIOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The rowdy people shouted IMPRECATIONS at the police as they departed.",
                  "word": "IMPRECATION",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The poor officiating VITIATED what should have been an exciting game.",
                  "word": "VITIATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The teenager lifts weights and works out so that he will be PROTEAN.",
                  "word": "PROTEAN",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "She is an excellent debater; her arguments are always PERSPICUOUS and to the point.",
                  "word": "PERSPICUOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "A trained counselor can OBVIATE some of the problems associated with release from prison.",
                  "word": "OBVIATE",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The employer's FULSOME letter of recommendation made the worker sound like a candidate for sainthood.",
                  "word": "FULSOME",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The comedian's SCURRILOUS jokes did not appeal to the more refined members of the audience.",
                  "word": "SCURRILOUS",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "Feeling his honor had been IMPUGNED, the officer challenged the man to a duel.",
                  "word": "IMPUGN",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "We do not deserve such OBLOQUY; we have done nothing to be ashamed of.",
                  "word": "OBLOQUY",
                  "correct": "true"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "It is my EXIGUOUS duty to inform you of your arrest.",
                  "word": "EXIGUOUS",
                  "correct": "false"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "The minister began to feel his sermons were OTIOSE; the people in his congregation would never change.",
                  "word": "OTIOSE",
                  "correct": "true"
                }
              ],
              "type": "tf",
              "id": 2
            },
            {
              "questions": [
                {
                  "prompt": "EQUABLE",
                  "answers": [
                    "halcyon",
                    "impartial",
                    "steady"
                  ],
                  "word": "EQUABLE",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "APOCRYPHAL",
                  "answers": [
                    "fictitious",
                    "bizarre",
                    "untrustworthy"
                  ],
                  "word": "APOCRYPHAL",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "REFULGENT",
                  "answers": [
                    "illustrious",
                    "luminous",
                    "lustrous"
                  ],
                  "word": "REFULGENT",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "MERETRICIOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "garish",
                    "vanishing",
                    "deceptive"
                  ],
                  "word": "MERETRICIOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPRECATION",
                  "answers": [
                    "inference",
                    "execration",
                    "curse"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPRECATION",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "VITIATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "adulterate",
                    "taint",
                    "revise"
                  ],
                  "word": "VITIATE",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PROTEAN",
                  "answers": [
                    "chameleonic",
                    "slow",
                    "mutable"
                  ],
                  "word": "PROTEAN",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "PERSPICUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "plain",
                    "lucid",
                    "persistent"
                  ],
                  "word": "PERSPICUOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBVIATE",
                  "answers": [
                    "attain",
                    "avert",
                    "preclude"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBVIATE",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "FULSOME",
                  "answers": [
                    "remorseful",
                    "repulsive",
                    "revolting"
                  ],
                  "word": "FULSOME",
                  "correct": "0"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "SCURRILOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "insulting",
                    "instantaneous",
                    "vituperative"
                  ],
                  "word": "SCURRILOUS",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "IMPUGN",
                  "answers": [
                    "refute",
                    "cite",
                    "malign"
                  ],
                  "word": "IMPUGN",
                  "correct": "1"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OBLOQUY",
                  "answers": [
                    "odium",
                    "invective",
                    "bantering"
                  ],
                  "word": "OBLOQUY",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "EXIGUOUS",
                  "answers": [
                    "attenuated",
                    "emaciated",
                    "reticent"
                  ],
                  "word": "EXIGUOUS",
                  "correct": "2"
                },
                {
                  "prompt": "OTIOSE",
                  "answers": [
                    "lethargic",
                    "legible",
                    "listless"
                  ],
                  "word": "OTIOSE",
                  "correct": "1"
                }
              ],
              "type": "mc-all",
              "id": 3
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "reviewTest": {
        "wordList": [
          {
            "word": "ADUMBRATE",
            "answer": "adumbrated"
          },
          {
            "word": "HIERATIC",
            "answer": "hieratic"
          },
          {
            "word": "OBLOQUY",
            "answer": "obloquy"
          },
          {
            "word": "QUONDAM",
            "answer": "quondam"
          },
          {
            "word": "SUBORN",
            "answer": "suborn"
          },
          {
            "word": "CYNOSURE",
            "answer": "cynosure"
          },
          {
            "word": "INCHOATE",
            "answer": "inchoate"
          },
          {
            "word": "OPPROBRIOUS",
            "answer": "opprobrious"
          },
          {
            "word": "REFULGENT",
            "answer": "refulgent"
          },
          {
            "word": "TENDENTIOUS",
            "answer": "tendentious or fulsome"
          },
          {
            "word": "ENCOMIUM",
            "answer": "encomium"
          },
          {
            "word": "INELUCTABLE",
            "answer": "ineluctable"
          },
          {
            "word": "PRODIGAL",
            "answer": "prodigal"
          },
          {
            "word": "SALIENT",
            "answer": "salient"
          },
          {
            "word": "TRADUCE",
            "answer": "traduce"
          },
          {
            "word": "EXIGUOUS",
            "answer": "exiguous"
          },
          {
            "word": "LANGUISH",
            "answer": "languish"
          },
          {
            "word": "PROTEAN",
            "answer": "protean"
          },
          {
            "word": "STENTORIAN",
            "answer": "stentorian"
          },
          {
            "word": "VENIAL",
            "answer": "venial"
          },
          {
            "word": "FULSOME",
            "answer": "fulsome"
          },
          {
            "word": "MERETRICIOUS",
            "answer": "meretricious"
          },
          {
            "word": "ABROGATE",
            "answer": "abrogated"
          },
          {
            "word": "BALEFUL",
            "answer": "baleful"
          },
          {
            "word": "IMPUGN",
            "answer": "impugn"
          },
          {
            "word": "PERSPICUOUS",
            "answer": "perspicuous"
          },
          {
            "word": "SCURRILOUS",
            "answer": "scurrilous"
          },
          {
            "word": "ADDUCE",
            "answer": "adduce"
          },
          {
            "word": "CONDIGN",
            "answer": "condign"
          },
          {
            "word": "INTERNECINE",
            "answer": "internecine"
          },
          {
            "word": "RECHERCHÉ",
            "answer": "recherché"
          },
          {
            "word": "STERTOROUS",
            "answer": "stertorous"
          },
          {
            "word": "APOCRYPHAL",
            "answer": "apocryphal"
          },
          {
            "word": "DESCRY",
            "answer": "descry"
          },
          {
            "word": "LIMPID",
            "answer": "limpid"
          },
          {
            "word": "REDACTION",
            "answer": "redaction"
          },
          {
            "word": "TENEBROUS",
            "answer": "tenebrous"
          },
          {
            "word": "ARCANE",
            "answer": "arcane"
          },
          {
            "word": "EQUABLE",
            "answer": "equable"
          },
          {
            "word": "OBVIATE",
            "answer": "obviate"
          },
          {
            "word": "RETICULATE",
            "answer": "reticulate"
          },
          {
            "word": "VITIATE",
            "answer": "vitiated"
          },
          {
            "word": "AVER",
            "answer": "averred"
          },
          {
            "word": "IMPRECATION",
            "answer": "imprecations"
          },
          {
            "word": "OTIOSE",
            "answer": "otiose"
          }
        ],
        "questions": [
          {
            "part1": "The defendant tried to",
            "part2": "the witness with the promise of a Swiss bank account.",
            "correct": "suborn",
            "word": "SUBORN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The college's most",
            "part2": "feature is the diversity of its student body.",
            "correct": "salient",
            "word": "SALIENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The press called the enemy's mistreatment of their prisoners of war",
            "part2": "and said they ought to be ashamed of themselves.",
            "correct": "opprobrious",
            "word": "OPPROBRIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Their",
            "part2": "expenditures on parties prevented the business from making a profit.",
            "correct": "prodigal",
            "word": "PRODIGAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Bayreuth is a(n)",
            "part2": "for Wagner-lovers; they all travel there to hear his music played.",
            "correct": "cynosure",
            "word": "CYNOSURE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The politician has a(n)",
            "part2": "nature; it changes to fit the mood of the times.",
            "correct": "protean",
            "word": "PROTEAN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The fundraiser's praise of the rich widow was so",
            "part2": "that we were embarrassed.",
            "correct": "fulsome",
            "word": "FULSOME"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The priest raised his hands over our heads in a(n)",
            "part2": "gesture of blessing.",
            "correct": "hieratic",
            "word": "HIERATIC"
          },
          {
            "part1": "His faults are",
            "part2": "and hardly worth mentioning when compared with his virtues.",
            "correct": "venial",
            "word": "VENIAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Their",
            "part2": "supply of food would not last more than two days, and then they would starve.",
            "correct": "exiguous",
            "word": "EXIGUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The idea was",
            "part2": "in the fall of 1980, but it was only the next spring that all the details were clear.",
            "correct": "adumbrated",
            "word": "ADUMBRATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "brochure made the congressman sound like another Abraham Lincoln.",
            "correct": "tendentious or fulsome",
            "word": "TENDENTIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "We found the music",
            "part2": "; its effect was based on cheap tricks rather than on real substance.",
            "correct": "meretricious",
            "word": "MERETRICIOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "swords gleamed brilliantly in the bright sun.",
            "correct": "refulgent",
            "word": "REFULGENT"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The general was subject to considerable public",
            "part2": "over what people felt was his cowardice in battle.",
            "correct": "obloquy",
            "word": "OBLOQUY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The top student received a glowing",
            "part2": "from the principal at graduation.",
            "correct": "encomium",
            "word": "ENCOMIUM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "antagonism between the two nations finally culminated in full-scale war.",
            "correct": "inchoate",
            "word": "INCHOATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "athlete now gets hardly any exercise at all.",
            "correct": "quondam",
            "word": "QUONDAM"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Joe viewed the",
            "part2": "approach of the final exam with trepidation, but there was nothing he could do to avoid it.",
            "correct": "ineluctable",
            "word": "INELUCTABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "In a(n)",
            "part2": "voice he boomed out the instructions for the test.",
            "correct": "stentorian",
            "word": "STENTORIAN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Interest in the team began to",
            "part2": "when they started losing to weaker opponents.",
            "correct": "languish",
            "word": "LANGUISH"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The notorious gossip likes to",
            "part2": "important people with half-truths and unfounded rumors.",
            "correct": "traduce",
            "word": "TRADUCE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The pleasantness of the holiday weekend was",
            "part2": "by the numerous holiday fatalities.",
            "correct": "vitiated",
            "word": "VITIATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "remarks about the man caused his family a great deal of pain and embarrassment.",
            "correct": "scurrilous",
            "word": "SCURRILOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The witch's",
            "part2": "prophecy of doom and destruction proved to be all too true.",
            "correct": "baleful",
            "word": "BALEFUL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The new government",
            "part2": "all laws regarding the ownership of the land and started redistributing it to the peasants.",
            "correct": "abrogated",
            "word": "ABROGATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "symbols on the manuscript were understood only by a few philosophers.",
            "correct": "arcane",
            "word": "ARCANE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I do not wish to",
            "part2": "your motives, but I think your actions have been rather questionable.",
            "correct": "impugn",
            "word": "IMPUGN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "leaf contains many crisscrossing veins.",
            "correct": "reticulate",
            "word": "RETICULATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The",
            "part2": "struggle within the committee led to the resignation of three members.",
            "correct": "internecine",
            "word": "INTERNECINE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "All our preparations could not",
            "part2": "the necessity for a hundred last-minute decisions.",
            "correct": "obviate",
            "word": "OBVIATE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The judge felt that ten years in prison would be",
            "part2": "punishment for the criminal.",
            "correct": "condign",
            "word": "CONDIGN"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The book is cogent and",
            "part2": "; it is a pleasure to read something that is free from obscurity.",
            "correct": "perspicuous",
            "word": "PERSPICUOUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Any further work on the project would be",
            "part2": "; it's as good as we can make it.",
            "correct": "otiose",
            "word": "OTIOSE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The scientist",
            "part2": "that nothing could possibly go wrong with the experiment.",
            "correct": "averred",
            "word": "AVER"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Deep in the",
            "part2": "forest, it was difficult to see even your hand in front of your face.",
            "correct": "tenebrous",
            "word": "TENEBROUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Her",
            "part2": "temperament allows her to confront the most bizarre situations in the same steady manner.",
            "correct": "equable",
            "word": "EQUABLE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The water in the",
            "part2": "mountain stream is utterly pure.",
            "correct": "limpid",
            "word": "LIMPID"
          },
          {
            "part1": "In the distance we could",
            "part2": "a tiny figure making its way toward us.",
            "correct": "descry",
            "word": "DESCRY"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The homeowner hurled angry",
            "part2": "at the children who had broken his window.",
            "correct": "imprecations",
            "word": "IMPRECATION"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The play, for many years considered",
            "part2": ", has definitely been shown to be the work of Christopher Marlowe.",
            "correct": "apocryphal",
            "word": "APOCRYPHAL"
          },
          {
            "part1": "I would like to",
            "part2": "several additional arguments in support of my position.",
            "correct": "adduce",
            "word": "ADDUCE"
          },
          {
            "part1": "Bill's",
            "part2": "breathing when he is asleep is so loud you wonder why it doesn't wake him.",
            "correct": "stertorous",
            "word": "STERTOROUS"
          },
          {
            "part1": "He considers his hobby of collecting eighteenth-century bills of lading rather mundane, but we consider it rather",
            "part2": ".",
            "correct": "recherché",
            "word": "RECHERCHÉ"
          },
          {
            "part1": "The medieval",
            "part2": "of the Latin love poems omitted many of the more erotic passages.",
            "correct": "redaction",
            "word": "REDACTION"
          }
        ],
        "type": "fitb"
      }
    }
  ]
}